<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/feed.xml</link> 
            <description>The Raymii.org RSS feed, all about GNU/Linux</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Let's Encrypt with DirectAdmin, now built in!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin_Now_Built_In.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin_Now_Built_In.html</guid>
                <description>Let's Encrypt is a new certificate authority, recognized by all major browsers. They make it a breeze to set up TLS certificates for your web server. And for free! Let's Encrypt is supported by major players like Mozilla, Akamai, Cisco, the EFF, the Internet Security Research Group and others. Let's Encrypt provides free, automatic and secure certificates so that every website can be secured with an SSL certificate. This article shows you how to setup Let's Encrypt with the DirectAdmin web control panel. DirectAdmin now supports Lets Encrypt natively since 1.50, so no more ssh fiddling, just via the control panel, for all the users on the server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 04, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_04_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_04_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 04 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 03, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_03_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_03_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 03 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible playbook for GoAccess Log Analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible_role_for_GoAccess_Log_Analyzer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible_role_for_GoAccess_Log_Analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small Ansible playbook to deploy the GoAccess log analyzer on Debian based systems. Next to Piwik, I use goaccess myself to get better insights in who and what visits my servers. This role is ment to be included in your webserver playbooks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 02, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 02 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Deborphan cleanup until no more orphaned packages left</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html</guid>
                <description>Deborphan removes packages it thinks your system doesn't need anymore. It is a great tool for package cleanup and maintenance. Sometimes, after cleaning up the packages, it will find new packages that are orphaned (because you just cleaned up). This is a small script that cleans up with deborphan until there is nothing more to cleanup.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 01, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_01_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_01_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 01 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Microsoft Office 2013 and 2010 on Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Office_2013_and_2010_on_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Office_2013_and_2010_on_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to run Microsoft Office 2013 and 2010 on Linux using CrossOver. It guides you through the installation and gives a review on what parts of the Office suite work with Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 53, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_53_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_53_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 53 of 2015, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recursively find all [installed] package dependencies</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Recursively_find_all_installed_package_dependencies.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Recursively_find_all_installed_package_dependencies.html</guid>
                <description>This small script shows you all packages [installed] that are a dependency from a package, and the dependencies of those packages. I installed the build-essential package, but apt-get remove-ing that package doens't remove the development tools. So I was wondering what packages were installed, including those dependencies, to remove the ones I didn't want. This small script shows you all packages that are dependencies of a package, and repeats that for those packages.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 52, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_52_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_52_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 52, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Ubuntu 15.10 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.10.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.10.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server on Ubuntu 15.04 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC protocol stack because of vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Ubuntu 15.04 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server on Ubuntu 15.04 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC protocol stack because of vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 51, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 51, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Forward or save outgoing email with Exim</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Forward_or_save_all_outgoing_email_with_exim.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Forward_or_save_all_outgoing_email_with_exim.html</guid>
                <description>I have a specific server where requirements state that all outgoing email should be saved for archival and auditing purposes. The server uses the Exim mail transfer agent, which makes this easy to configure. The outgoing email is also forwarded to an off-site mailbox, both for backup and easy consulting. This captures all outgoing email, sent by PHP scripts or cronjobs, or user accounts that send via exim. This tutorial also shows how to forward or save all outgoing email for a specific domain.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 50, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_50_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_50_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 50 of 2015, covering open source and sysadmin related stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Generate hashes of files with rhash for archival storage</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Generate_hashes_of_files_with_rhash_for_archival_storage.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Generate_hashes_of_files_with_rhash_for_archival_storage.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to archive a large amount of files to archival storage. To save space and reduce the amount of files I decided to create archives with tar. The files will be stored to tapes and DVD's, and will be restored in full, so random access times are not an issue, therefore the tar.gz choice. I do want to make sure that when the files need to be restored they still are correct. I first dabbled with some long shell commands to create checksums and verify them, but then I found the `rhash` tool in the repositories. It allows you to create checksums of files and folders, recursively, with all sorts of checksums, like CRC, MD5, SHA1 and many more. It also makes bulk validation very simple. This small article shows you how to create an archive file with the checksums included and shows you how to validate these checksums later on.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Let's Encrypt with DirectAdmin or other Web Control Panels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin.html</guid>
                <description>Let's Encrypt is a new certificate authority, recognized by all major browsers. They make it a breeze to set up TLS certificates for your web server. And for free! Let's Encrypt is supported by major players like Mozilla, Akamai, Cisco, the EFF, the Internet Security Research Group and others. Let's Encrypt provides free, automatic and secure certificates so that every website can be secured with an SSL certificate. This article shows you how to setup Let's Encrypt with the DirectAdmin web control panel. The guide is generic, so it works for other controlpanels as well. For now it works with the beta, and required some linux knowledge and root access to the hosting server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Linux Containers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Linux_Containers.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Linux_Containers.html</guid>
                <description>This article goes over Linux Containers. It touches both bare linux cgroups and namespaces and goes over LXC (linux conrainers).</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypt and decrypt files to public keys via the OpenSSL Command Line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypt_and_decrypt_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypt_and_decrypt_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial will show you how to use the openssl command line to encrypt and decrypt a file using a public key. We will first generate a random key, encrypt that random key against the public key of the other person and use that random key to encrypt the actual file with using symmetric encryption.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Sign and verify text/files to public keys via the OpenSSL Command Line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Sign_and_verify_text_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Sign_and_verify_text_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</guid>
                <description>This small guide will shows you how to use the OpenSSL Command Line to sign a file, and how to verify the signing of this file. You can do this to prove ownership of a key, or to prove that a file hasn't been modified since you signed it. This works both with small text files as well as huge photo's, documents or PDF files.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Make OpenELEC/Kodi work with the Sitecom CN-524/ Cambridge Silicon Radio (CSR) 8510 A10 Bluetooth USB adapter on the Raspberry Pi.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Make_Openelec_Kodi_work_with_the_Sitecom_CN-524_Cambridge_Silicon_Radio_CSR_8510_A10_Bluetooth_USB_adapter_on_the_Raspberry_Pi.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Make_Openelec_Kodi_work_with_the_Sitecom_CN-524_Cambridge_Silicon_Radio_CSR_8510_A10_Bluetooth_USB_adapter_on_the_Raspberry_Pi.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I set up a Kodi (XMBC) media center on a Raspberry Pi.  The setup is mounted on a flatscreen TV and uses a small Wifi dongle for network access and a small Bluetooth dongle for a Rapoo E6700 wireless bluetooth keyboard/touchpad. This is a nice bluetooth keyboard/mouse combo for a media center, it charges via micro USB. That saves a lot of battery hassle. The bluetooth adapter is a Sitecom CN-524, which was the only one my local electronic store had available. It however does not work with linux/Kodi by default. This is because the device boots in a wrong mode. This guide shows you how this can be fixed and the necessary software changes for OpenELEC.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do action if on specific distribution (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS or RHEL) or distribution version (ubuntu precise, ubuntu trusty)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if you are on a certain distribution. You might have a mixed environment with CentOS and Debian and when using Ansible to execute actions on nodes you don't need to run Yum on Debian, or Apt on CentOS. Some package names are different and such, so this helps you with an only if statement to select a specific distribution. As a bonus, you also get an only_if for specific distribution versions, like Ubuntu precise (12.04 LTS) or Ubuntu trusty (14.04 LTS).</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios 4 + Nagiosgraph (latest) installation on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_Core_4_Installation_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_Core_4_Installation_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the latest Nagios Core (4.1.1) on Ubuntu 12.04 and 14.04. Nagios is an open source computer system monitoring, network monitoring and infrastructure monitoring software application. Nagios offers monitoring and alerting services for servers, switches, applications, and services. It alerts the users when things go wrong and alerts them a second time when the problem has been resolved. The version in the Ubuntu 12.04 repositories is quite old, it is still the in the 3 branch. This guide helps to fix that by using the latest Nagios version. We also install Nagiosgraph, a plugin for Nagios which gives you graps of the metrics.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install Ubuntu Linux on the LG Chromebase</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/LG_Chromebase_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/LG_Chromebase_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>I recently acquired the LG Chromebase 22CV241-W. It is an All in One type machine with Chrome OS. The hardware, excluding the screen and lack of battery, is largely the same as the Acer C720. Of course I removed Chrome OS and installed a real Linux on it, of which you'll find instructions below. In my case it is Ubuntu Mate. Arch Linux also works fine, but this was for someone else, so a more beginner friendly distro seemed to be a better choise. This article will cover the removal of Chrome OS and the installation of Ubuntu Mate on the LG Chromebase.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Running TSS/8 on the DEC PiDP-8/i and SIMH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_TSS_8_on_the_DEC_PiDP-8_i_and_SIMH.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_TSS_8_on_the_DEC_PiDP-8_i_and_SIMH.html</guid>
                <description>In this guide I'll show you how run the TSS/8 operating system on the PiDP replica by Oscar Vermeulen, and on SIMH on any other computer. I'll also cover a few basic commands like the editor, user management and system information. TSS-8 was a little time-sharing operating system  released in 1968 and requires a minimum of 12K words of memory and a swapping device; on a 24K word machine, it supports up to 17 users. Each user gets a virtual 4K PDP-8; many of the utilities users ran on these virtual machines were only slightly modified versions of utilities from the Disk Monitor System or paper-tape environments. Internally, TSS-8 consists of RMON, the resident monitor, DMON, the disk monitor (file system), and KMON, the keyboard monitor (command shell). BASIC was well supported, while restricted (4K) versions of FORTRAN D and Algol were available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Running Adventure on the DEC PDP-8 with SIMH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_ADVENT-on-the-PDP-8-with-SIMH.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_ADVENT-on-the-PDP-8-with-SIMH.html</guid>
                <description>In this guide I'll show you how run the classic Colossal Cave Adventure game on a PDP-8, emulated by the SIMH emulator. The PDP-8 was an 12 bit minicomputer made in 1964 by DEC, the Digital Equipment Corporation. We will install and set up SIMH, the emulator with a RK05 diskimage running OS/8. We will use FORTRAN on OS/8 to load ADVENTURE, then we use our brain to play the game. As a bonus, I also show you how to edit files using EDIT, and show you a bit of the OS/8 system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Find all services using libssl to restart after an OpenSSL update</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html</guid>
                <description>When you update OpenSSL, the software that currently has the ssl libraries loaded in memory do not automatically load the updated libraries. A full system reboot resolves that problem, but sometimes that is not possible. This command shows you all the software that has loaded the libraries, allowing you to restart only those services. If you don't restart or reload after an update, the software might still be vulnerable to issues that the update fixed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Stong SSL Security on lighttpd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_lighttpd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_lighttpd.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up strong SSL security on the lighttpd webserver. We do this by updating OpenSSL to the latest version to mitigate attacks like Heartbleed, disabling SSL Compression and EXPORT ciphers to mitigate attacks like FREAK, CRIME and LogJAM, disabling SSLv3 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will set up a strong ciphersuite that enables Forward Secrecy when possible. We also enable HSTS and HPKP. This way we have a strong and future proof ssl configuration and we get an A+ on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Strong SSL Security on nginx</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_nginx.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_nginx.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up strong SSL security on the nginx webserver. We do this by updating OpenSSL to the latest version to mitigate attacks like Heartbleed, disabling SSL Compression and EXPORT ciphers to mitigate attacks like FREAK, CRIME and LogJAM, disabling SSLv3 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will set up a strong ciphersuite that enables Forward Secrecy when possible. We also enable HSTS and HPKP. This way we have a strong and future proof ssl configuration and we get an A+ on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Strong SSL Security on Apache2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_Apache2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_Apache2.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up strong SSL security on the Apache2 webserver. We do this by updating OpenSSL to the latest version to mitigate attacks like Heartbleed, disabling SSL Compression and EXPORT ciphers to mitigate attacks like FREAK, CRIME and LogJAM, disabling SSLv3 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will set up a strong ciphersuite that enables Forward Secrecy when possible. We also enable HSTS and HPKP. This way we have a strong and future proof ssl configuration and we get an A+ on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack - (Manually) migrating (KVM) Nova compute virtual machines</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_-_(Manually)_migrating_(KVM)_Nova_Compute_Virtual_Machines.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_-_(Manually)_migrating_(KVM)_Nova_Compute_Virtual_Machines.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to migrate KVM virtual machines with the  Openstack Nova compute service, either manually or with the Openstack tooling. Openstack provides a few different ways to migrate virtual machines from one compute node to another. Each option has different requirements and restrictions, for example, you can't live-migrate without shared storage. You can't live-migrate if you have a configdrive enabled. You can't select the target host if you use the nova migrate (non-live) command etc. This article describes the most common migration scenario's including live and manual migration using native linux tools.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>The awesomely epic guide to KDE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/The_awesomely_epic_guide_to_KDE.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/The_awesomely_epic_guide_to_KDE.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows gives an overview of the major KDE features like font management, visual effects, file management, eye candy, the panels, the task switcer and more great KDE stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Filing Effective Bug Reports</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Filing_Effective_Bug_Reports.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Filing_Effective_Bug_Reports.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to report bugs properly and help open source projects by doing so. It explains the things that help create a good bug report, one on which the developers can actually work on. It also explains the process of bug reporting, what happens after you've did the initial report?</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi Arcade Machine</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_Arcade_Machine.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_Arcade_Machine.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to build your own full size arcade machine using a Raspberry Pi. It involves a real, full size arcade cabinet, a converter device called a J-Pac and the MAME emulator software.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL command line Root and Intermediate CA including OCSP, CRL and revocation</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL and_revocation.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL and_revocation.html</guid>
                <description>These are quick and dirty notes on generating a certificate authority (CA), intermediate certificate authorities and end certificates using the OpenSSL command line tools. It includes OCSP, CRL and CA Issuer information and specific issue and expiry dates. We'll set up our own root CA. We'll use the root CA to generate an example intermediate CA. We'll use the intermediate CA to sign end user certificates.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>systemd: Don't fear change</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/systemd_dont_fear_change.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/systemd_dont_fear_change.html</guid>
                <description>This article talks about systemd in Red Hat Enterprise Linux / CentOS 7. It gives some usage examples and talks about the differences between systemd, upstart and sysvinit.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Keep messages secure with GPG</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Keeping_messages_secure_with_GPG.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Keeping_messages_secure_with_GPG.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to get started with GPG and Mailvelope. It discusses public/private key crypto and shows you how to use the Mailvelope software to encrypt and decrypt GPG messages on any webmail provider.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Manually verify a certificate against a CRL</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_manually_verify_a_certificate_against_a_CRL.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_manually_verify_a_certificate_against_a_CRL.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to manually verfify a certificate against a CRL. CRL stands for Certificate Revocation List and is one way to validate a certificate status. It is an alternative to the OCSP, Online Certificate Status Protocol.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>How I got a valid SSL certificate for my ISP's main domain, xs4all.nl</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/How_I_got_a_valid_SSL_certificate_for_my_ISPs_main_website.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/How_I_got_a_valid_SSL_certificate_for_my_ISPs_main_website.html</guid>
                <description>I got a valid SSL certificate for a domain that is not mine by creating an email alias. In this article I'll explain what happened, why that was possible and how we all can prevent this.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 mainline 4.0.0 kernel, u-boot and debian rootfs image building tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_A20_Lime2_Kernel_3.19_uBoot_Debian_7_image_building.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_A20_Lime2_Kernel_3.19_uBoot_Debian_7_image_building.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 45, and has 160 GPIO pins. This is a guide to build a linux image with Debian and the mainline 4.0.0 kernel for the Olimex A20-Lime2 board, from scratch. By default it comes with an 3.4 kernel with binary blobs and patches from Allwinner. Recently the mainline kernel has gained support for these boards, you can now run and use the mainline kernel without these awfull non-free binary blobs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Automating Openstack with cloud init run a script on VM's first boot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to create a VM in Openstack and execute a script at the first boot using cloud-init's user-data feature. This way you can eliminate some more manual labor and keep a small base image, instead of requiring all kinds of specific images for specific tasks. This tutorial will also give you a few example scripts to use with cloud-init and to create Openstack virtual machines from the command line. </description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a Flexible and Powerful System with Arch Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Build_a_Flexible_and_Powerful_System_with_Arch_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Build_a_Flexible_and_Powerful_System_with_Arch_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers the basic installation and configuration of Arch Linux, the distro that adheres to the Keep It Simple, Stupid principle. Arch Linux is a rolling release, that means that you always have the latest and greatest software. With Arch, you're on your own. In a world where where technology is taking your personal responsibility and giving it to the cloud, or to an internet search filter or the device manufacturers, getting your hands dirty with an operating system can be a revelation. Not only will you learn a great deal about how Linux works and what holds the whole thing together, you'll get a system you understand from the inside-out, and one that can be instantly upgraded to all the latest packages. You may also learn something about yourself in the process. And despite its reputation, it's not that difficult.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ada Lovelace and The Analytical Engine</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ada_Lovelace_and_The_Analytical_Engine.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ada_Lovelace_and_The_Analytical_Engine.html</guid>
                <description>This article discusses an important piece of computing history, the Analytical Engine. It was designed by Charles Babbage. The history of Ada Lovelace is also covered, she also worked on and programmed the Analytical Engine. This article explains how the Analytical Engine works and gives us a few example programs. It also covers the calculation of the Bernoulli numbers with the Analytical Engine.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python: build dynamic web pages</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Python_build_dynamic_web_pages.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Python_build_dynamic_web_pages.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you various ways of creating a dynamic webpage. It covers iframes, widgets and a few Python modules including Tornado, feedparser and JSON. We'll build a page which has RSS feeds, the weather and the current exchange rates.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Solve word puzzles with bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Solve_word_puzzles_with_bash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Solve_word_puzzles_with_bash.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to solve word puzzles with Bash. It covers the grep tool including regular expressions to solve different kinds of word puzzles.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Euclid's algorithm: recursion and python</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Euclids_algorithm_recursion_and_python.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Euclids_algorithm_recursion_and_python.html</guid>
                <description>This article talks about Euclids Algorithm. The problem that Euclid's algorithm solves is easy enough to understand: what is the largest common divisor of two integers? Take the numbers 100 and 80, for example: what's the largest number that divides into both? It walks us through Python example code explaining the function.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Glance Image Download, download Openstack images</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack_Glance_Image_Download.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack_Glance_Image_Download.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how download Openstack Images to your local machine using the command line Glance client. You can use this, for example, to download a copy of an image created from a VM, or to download the images your Openstack provider provides and adapt those.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing Virtual Machines with virt-install, plus copy pastable distro install one-liners</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</guid>
                <description>virt-install is a command line tool for creating new KVM , Xen or Linux container guests using the libvirt hypervisor management library. It allows you to create a VM and start an installation from the command line. This article has a few copy pastable getting started examples for different distro's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove Installatron from a (Directadmin) server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Remove_Installatron_from_a_(Directadmin)_server.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Remove_Installatron_from_a_(Directadmin)_server.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short guide which shows you how to remove Installatron from a server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi FM radio transmitter with Buttons</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_FM_Radio_With_Buttons.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_FM_Radio_With_Buttons.html</guid>
                <description>The PiFM project allows you to use a Raspberry Pi to send out a WAV file on the FM band. This is awesome because every normal radio then can receive your music/podcast without expensive (sonos) equipment. I've used a lasercutter to craft a new top plate for my Pi which has room for three buttons. These are hooked up to a python script which allows me to start and stop the transmission, and skip or go back songs. It also allows me to shut down the Pi instead of just pulling the power cable.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 Minimal Debian 7 Image</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A20-OLinuXino-LIME2_minimal_debian_7_image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A20-OLinuXino-LIME2_minimal_debian_7_image.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 45, and has 160 GPIO pins. The default Debian image from OlimeX is quite huge and bloated, over 2,5 GB, with X and all. I do not want a huge image, so I stripped it down to a 200 MB image with only dhcp and ssh and a few basic tools. It uses about 15 MB of RAM. This image allows you to start with almost nothing and build up only what you need.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - pre-backup all container dump script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</guid>
                <description>This simple script creates a vzdump of all the OpenVZ containers on a machine. It can be used before an actual backup, in my case the actual backup excludes the container path /var/lib/vz/private. This because a dump is easier to backup because it has much less files in it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Filtering IMAP mail with imapfilter</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Filtering_IMAP_mail_with_imapfilter.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Filtering_IMAP_mail_with_imapfilter.html</guid>
                <description>I have several email accounts at different providers. Most of them don't offer filtering capabilites like Sieve, or only their own non exportable rule system (Google Apps). My mail client of choice, Thunderbird, has filtering capabilities but my phone has not and I don't want to leave my machine running Thunderbird all the time since it gets quite slow with huge mailboxes. Imapfilter is a mail filtering utility written in Lua which connects to one or more IMAP accounts and filters on the server using IMAP queries. It is a lightweight command line utility, the configuration can be versioned and is simple text and it is very fast.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Broken Corrupted Raspberry Pi SD Card</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Broken_Corrupted_Raspberry_Pi_SD_Card.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Broken_Corrupted_Raspberry_Pi_SD_Card.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's would not boot up after a reboot. The SD card was corrupted, sadly beyond repair. This article walks you through the steps I took to try to fix the SD card, including fsck, badblocks and other filesystem utilities. It also has tips to reduce the writing on the Raspberry Pi, this to save SD cards from some amount of wear and thus possible corruption.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Shared Git repository over ssh for multiple users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to set up a shared git repo with multiple accounts over ssh. Only ssh, not gitolite or any other software. This is usefull if you have a small team of people that don't often need access to the repo and don't want something like github or bitbucket. With this you can use existing infrastructure.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get all IP ranges from an AS number</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_IP_ranges_from_an_AS_number.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_IP_ranges_from_an_AS_number.html</guid>
                <description>One of my clients wanted to block a few social networking websites. Since they have no IPv6 (yet) I figured the simplest way was to block access to the entire IP range. This won't work for all the CDN networks they use, but it does get you started. To find all the ranges beloning to an AS number you can query the whois.radb.net server with the AS number.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>pfSense allow web interface access on WAN from specific IP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/pfSense_allow_web_interface_access_on_WAN_from_specific_IP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/pfSense_allow_web_interface_access_on_WAN_from_specific_IP.html</guid>
                <description>pfSense is a fast and simple FreeBSD based firewall appliance with a nice web managent interface and the power of the pf firewall underneath. Normally the web interface is only accessible from the management LAN (or LAN by default) interface. If you for whatever reason locked yourself out or need access from a different IP via the WAN interface you can use the easyrule command line to temporarly add a rule that allows your remote IP in. This simple snippet shows you how.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Centos 7 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_CentOS_7.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_CentOS_7.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server with CentOS 7 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSECP protocol stack because of recent vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>HTTP Public Key Pinning Extension HPKP for Apache, NGINX and Lighttpd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/HTTP_Public_Key_Pinning_Extension_HPKP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/HTTP_Public_Key_Pinning_Extension_HPKP.html</guid>
                <description>Public Key Pinning means that a certificate chain must include a whitelisted public key. It ensures only whitelisted Certificate Authorities (CA) can sign certificates for `*.example.com`, and not any CA in your browser store. This article has background theory and configuration examples for Apache, Lighttpd and NGINX.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>HTTP Strict Transport Security for Apache, NGINX and Lighttpd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security_for_Apache_NGINX_and_Lighttpd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security_for_Apache_NGINX_and_Lighttpd.html</guid>
                <description>HTTP Strict Transport Security (often abbreviated as HSTS) is a security feature that lets a web site tell browsers that it should only be communicated with using HTTPS, instead of using HTTP. This tutorial will show you how to set up HSTS in Apache2, NGINX and Lighttpd.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Arch Linux AUR PKGBUILD generate new checksums</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch_Linux_AUR_PKGBUILD_generate_new_checksums.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch_Linux_AUR_PKGBUILD_generate_new_checksums.html</guid>
                <description>The AUR is a nice feature from Arch Linux, it allows anyone to create and upload a simple package build script, PKGBUILD, for a piece of software which is not in the repositories. Sometimes however, the PKGBUILD is outdated. You then need to manually fix it, by changing the download link or version. With a new version you get new checksums, and the makepkg command has a neat feature which generates the checksums for you.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if a file exists or does not exist</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_a_file_exists_or_does_not_exist.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_a_file_exists_or_does_not_exist.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if a file exists or does not exist. If you for example have a command you need to run to generate a certificate (or Diffie Hellman parameters for nginx) you only want to do that once. The command itself is not convergent so it will run with every ansible run. However, the command creates a file and Ansible is able to check if that file exists. If the file exists, it will not execute the action. The same goes for checking if a file does exist and only executing the action if it exists. (The action you want to do will remove that file).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Fix inconsistent Openstack volumes and instances from Cinder and Nova via the database</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Fix_inconsistent_Openstack_volumes_and_instances_from_Cinder_and_Nova_via_the_database.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Fix_inconsistent_Openstack_volumes_and_instances_from_Cinder_and_Nova_via_the_database.html</guid>
                <description>When running Openstack, sometimes the state of a volume  or an instance can be inconsistent on the cluster. Nova might find a volume attached while Cinder says the volume is detached or otherwise. Sometimes a volume deletion hangs, or a detach does not work. If you've found and fixed the underlying issue (lvm, iscsi, ceph, nfs etc...) you need to bring the database up to date with the new consistent state. Most of the time a reset-state works, sometimes you need to manually edit the database to correct the state. These snippets show you how.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clear Uncluttered SSH client config with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>Openssh allows you to configure parameters like username, port, proxycommand, key and more in the ~/.ssh/config file. If you have many servers this file can become cluttered and maintaining it can become a not so nice task. This simple guide shows you how you can use a conf.d directory with seperate smaller files which gets converted to the big config file by Ansible</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino a10 Lime uBoot, Kernel and root image guide</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino _10 Lime_uBoot_Kernel.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino _10 Lime_uBoot_Kernel.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A10 LIME is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 30, and has 160 GPIO. This guide is a cleaned up version of theirs with instructions to build your own kernel and u-boot image on Ubuntu 14.04.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ingsoc</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ingsoc.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ingsoc.html</guid>
                <description>ingsoc is a static site generator written in Python with the purpose of generating raymii.org. It differs from other static site generators because it does not create a blog-like site, but it is focused on pages and structure. It also does not use a template engine. It generates categories, pages, tags, an XML sitemap and a RSS feed. It takes markdown files with a yaml config header as input, and outputs html.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 12.04 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on CentOS 6 / Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 / Scientific Linux 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_CentOS_-_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_or_Scientific_-_Linux_6.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_CentOS_-_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_or_Scientific_-_Linux_6.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 13.04 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Ubuntu 13.04 using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Arch Linux on a Raspberry Pi with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_a_Raspberry_Pi_with_Arch_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_a_Raspberry_Pi_with_Arch_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Arch Linux on a Raspberry Pi using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 14.04 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_14.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_14.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Ubuntu 14.04 using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC/L2TP protocol stack because of recent vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all major operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 13.10 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.10.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.10.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Ubuntu 13.10 using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 12.10 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.10.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.10.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Affinity Groups, make sure instances are on the same or different compute hypervisor hosts</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_Affinity_Groups-make-sure-instances-are-on-the-same-or-a-different-hypervisor-host.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_Affinity_Groups-make-sure-instances-are-on-the-same-or-a-different-hypervisor-host.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to use Openstack Affinity groups. Affinity or Anti-Affinity groups allow you to make sure instances (VM/VPS) are on the same hypervisor host or on a different one. There are cases when you want two instances on different compute nodes, for example, when they are clustered servers like a load balancer or a database master-master setup. All VMs in each Affinity group are hosted in the same hypervisor, while no two VMs of a same Anti-Affinity group are hosted in the same hypervisor.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if host is also in other hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet helps you execute actions only when a host is in another hostgroup in Ansible. For example, you might deploy munin-node via ansible, but you only want your apache and NGINX plugins deployed on your webservers, not on your database servers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.1-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.1-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL Decoder Script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenSSL_Decoder.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenSSL_Decoder.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple PHP script which decodes a certificate, csr or connection and displays the information it finds.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL Command Generator</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenSSL_Command_Generator.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenSSL_Command_Generator.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple page with a form which you can use to generate OpenSSL commands to, for example, create a key, certificate and a CSR.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino a10 Lime Minimal Debian 7 Image</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A10-OLinuXino-LIME_minimal_debian_7_image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A10-OLinuXino-LIME_minimal_debian_7_image.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A10 LIME is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 30, and has 160 GPIO. The default Debian image from OlimeX is quite huge and bloated, over 2 GB, with X and all. I do not want a huge image, so I stripped it down to a 200 MB image with only dhcp and ssh and a few basic tools. It uses about 20 MB of RAM. This image allows you to start with almost nothing and build up only what you need.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Keepalived notify script, execute action on failover</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived_notify_script_execute_action_on_failover.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived_notify_script_execute_action_on_failover.html</guid>
                <description>Keepalived supports running scripts on VRRP state change. This can come in handy when you need to execute an action when a failover occurs. In my case, I have a VPN running on a Virtual IP and want to make sure the VPN only runs on the node with the Virtual IP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check and Fix SSL servers for SSLv3 connections or the Poodle CVE-2014-3566 bug</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html</guid>
                <description>The POODLE CVE-2014-3566 bug is a new bug discovered by Google in the SSLv3 protocol. The fix is easy, disable support for SSLv3. See https://cipherli.st for a good list of SSL ciphers. You can use this check from the shell to check your servers. This command can easily be automated with other shell scripts. It also allows you to check your services without exposing them to an external checking website.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Configserver Firewall and Security (CSF and LFD)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Configserver_Firewall_and_Security_CSF_LFD.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Configserver_Firewall_and_Security_CSF_LFD.html</guid>
                <description>his page covers my notes about csf and lfd. csf is an easy SPI iptables firewall suite. lfd is the login failure daemon, which scans log files for failed authentication and blocks the IP's doing that. This page covers installation, populair command line options and popular config file options.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Firefox History stats with Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small script to gather some statistics from your Firefox history. First we use sqlite3 to parse the Firefox history database and get the last three months, then we remove all the IP addresses and port numbers and finally we sort and count it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Patch Shellshock)with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple ansible playbook to patch Debian, CentOS, Ubuntu and derivatives for the Shellshock vulnerability (CVE-2014-6271).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Boot to Vim, Vim as Pid 1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Vim_as_PID_1_Boot_to_Vim.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Vim_as_PID_1_Boot_to_Vim.html</guid>
                <description>This is a response on a great article from Pascal Bourguignon, namely how to run Emacs as PID 1. As we all know, nobody uses emacs. No, all joking aside, I found it to be a good article and wanted to see how I could do that with Vim. Not in User Mode Linux, but by creating an actual ISO. Boot to Vim, as you might want to call it. This is actually fairly simple. Compile vim statically, set it as init= at boot and you're done. We are going to use small 9MB distro named Tiny Core, Core edition and customize that to boot right into our static build of Vim.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Statically (cross) compiled vim for x86, x86-64 and mipsel</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html</guid>
                <description>Sometimes I need to manage a few systems with either low resources or a very restricted set of packages. On those systems no compilers or development libraries are available, however it is allowed to bring binaries.A few of those systems are 32 bit x68 systems, some are MIPS systems, even worse. They serve a secure purpose, I cannot go in to much detail about them, except for they require a high level of security, they process certificates. I really like vim as my editor, the only editor available by default on those systems is ed. I have an ed cheatsheet for this purpose. The solution for this problem is to create a statically (cross) compiled version of vim. This article shows you how to create a statically compiled vim that runs everywhere.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Owncloud, DirectAdmin, Apache 2.4 and Error AH01797: client denied by server configuration</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Owncloud_DirectAdmin,_Apache_2.4_and_Error_AH01797_client_denied_by_server_configuration.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Owncloud_DirectAdmin,_Apache_2.4_and_Error_AH01797_client_denied_by_server_configuration.html</guid>
                <description>I keep a few servers around for shared webhosting for friends, family and some other domains. Most of them run Directadmin, because it is easier to work with for the target audience. I'm very good with the command line, they've never heard of it. One of my friends runs Owncloud, a wonderfull piece of software to get cloud services under your control. He does not use the file part but rather the calendar and contacts a lot. A recent update of Apache to 2.4.10 broke that functionality on a Directadmin machine with the error AH01797: client denied by server configuration. After a bit of searching and debugging, here's how I fixed it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set your IP as wallpaper</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set-your-ip-as-wallpaper.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set-your-ip-as-wallpaper.html</guid>
                <description>This  tutorial shows you how to set your IP address as wallpaper using Imagemagick</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>foaas.sh - Command Line Fuck Off as a Service client</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/foaas.sh_-_Command_Line_FOAAS_Client.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/foaas.sh_-_Command_Line_FOAAS_Client.html</guid>
                <description>foaas.sh is a command line [Fuck Off as a Service client](http://foaas.com/). It is written is bash and supports multiple forms of API interaction. It also supports `xclip`, when available, the result of an interaction is copied to the clipboard for later use.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get the current or all Firefox tab urls in Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This snippets gets the current firefox tab url or all the firefox tab url's. It uses the sessionstore.js file in your profile folder.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a $35 Time Capsule - Raspberry Pi Time Machine Backup Server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple guide on building a $35 Time Capsule with a Raspberry Pi. A Time Capsule is a network attached storage device from Apple for use with their Time Machine. Time Machine gives users a very easy and userfriendly way to automatically create and restore (encrypted) backups. A Time Capsule is basically an expensive NAS that only talks the AFP/netatalk protocol. The 2 TB version costs $299 at this time, a Raspberry Pi only $35. </description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Building HA Clusters with Ansible and Openstack</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</guid>
                <description>This is an extensive guide on building high available clusters with Ansible and Openstack. We'll build a Highly available cluster consisting out of two load balancers, two database servers and two application servers running a simple wordpress site. This is all done with Ansible, the cluster nodes are all on Openstack. Ansible is a super awesome orchestration tool and Openstack is a big buzzword filled software suite for datacenter virtualization.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - Container to Template</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to convert an OpenVZ (Proxmox) container to a template. You can then use this template on any other OpenVZ (or proxmox) host. This can be used either to migrate containers or to create a kind of master image to deploy new hosts from.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Proxmox VE - One Public IP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to set up Proxmox with only one public IP. We will configure an extra interface bridge and make sure VM traffic is NATed. I have a few dedicated servers, some run Proxmox. Most of them however have only a few IP's. Therefore the VM's in proxmox cannot all have a public IP. For most of them that is not a problem. If needed I run a proxy or set up iptables to forward ports to the VM's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>CentOS 5 CA Certificate Bundle Update</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_5_CA_Certificate_Bundle_Update.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_5_CA_Certificate_Bundle_Update.html</guid>
                <description>This simple snippet shows you how to update the root ca certificate bundle on CentOS 5. Some websites have certificates signed by authorities not in the default bundle and those websites will not work with tools like git, curl, wget or anything else that uses https.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Traceroute to Smokeping Target config</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Traceroute_to_Smokeping_Target_Config.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Traceroute_to_Smokeping_Target_Config.html</guid>
                <description>This little one-liner converts the output of traceroute to Smokeping Target output. This way you can build your smokeping config faster.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Simple keepalived failover setup on Ubuntu 14.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived-Simple-IP-failover-on-Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived-Simple-IP-failover-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to set up very simple keepalived IP failover on Ubuntu 14.04. Keepalived is a piece of software which can be used to achieve high availability by assigning two or more nodes a virtual IP and monitoring those nodes, failing over when one goes down.  Keepalived can do more, like load balancing and monitoring, but this tutorial focusses on a very simple setup, just IP failover.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OSSEC 2.8 Server, Client, Web UI and Analogi Dashboard Installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_2.8.0_Server_Client_and_Analogi_Dashboard_on_Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_2.8.0_Server_Client_and_Analogi_Dashboard_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>OSSEC is an Open Source Host-based Intrusion Detection System that performs log analysis, file integrity checking, policy monitoring, rootkit detection, real-time alerting and active response. It runs on most operating systems, including Linux, MacOS, Solaris, HP-UX, AIX and Windows. It also includes agentless monitoring for use with for example Cisco or Juniper hardware. This tutorial covers the installation of the OSSEC 2.8 server, the standard OSSEC Web UI and the Analogi dashboard on Ubuntu 14.04. It also covers OSSEC setup with MySQL support. Last but not least it shows you how to install the OSSEC agent on a *NIX system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.0-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.0-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance. This tutorial is more a collection of notes than what you are used of me, it has less explanation and such, just right on steps to get started.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Horizon installation with SSL on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the Openstack Horizon (icehouse) dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04 or 14.04, including SSL setup. It features nice screenshots and even an Ansible playbook to automate it all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Swift Objectstore Access via FTP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on accessing the Openstack Swift Object Storage system using an FTP client. Openstack Swift has a beautiful API which you can program to. However, sometimes it is handy to quickly be able to access your Swift/Objectstore data without programming around it. We will use ftp-cloudfs to do this. There is also Softlayers swftp, but that does not support Keystone Authentication (2.0). ftp-cloudfs does support this. The OS X Cyberduck FTP client also has Openstack Swift support, however that is a native implementation, not using FTP. With ftp-cloudfs we can use any ftp client, from Filezilla to midnight commander.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPv6 at Home</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/IPv6_at_Home.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/IPv6_at_Home.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's was running a test setup of the Citadel groupware service. The test was sucessfull, so I set up a real world setup. The Raspberry Pi would serve another purpose, namely, a Linux Torrent seedbox. As in, to seed Linux torrents from linuxtracker.org. I choose Transmission for this, because it is simple, fast and stable. Transmission has a good webinterface, plus it allows access from remote clients with the transmission-remote gui packages. This article shows you how to set it up on a Raspberry Pi running Arch Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Transmission Web on a Raspberry Pi with Arch Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's was running a test setup of the Citadel groupware service. The test was sucessfull, so I set up a real world setup. The Raspberry Pi would serve another purpose, namely, a Linux Torrent seedbox. As in, to seed Linux torrents from linuxtracker.org. I choose Transmission for this, because it is simple, fast and stable. Transmission has a good webinterface, plus it allows access from remote clients with the transmission-remote gui packages. This article shows you how to set it up on a Raspberry Pi running Arch Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FreeBSD 10, Converting from RELEASE to STABLE </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_10_Converting_from_RELEASE_to_STABLE.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_10_Converting_from_RELEASE_to_STABLE.html</guid>
                <description>Because of a [bug in  mpd][1] which is fixed in 10-STABLE I wanted to move one of my FreeBSD machines from 10.0-RELEASE to 10.0-STABLE. The process to do so is fairly simple. Basically, you check out the new source code, build the world, build the kernel, install the kernel, install the world, merge some stuff and reboot. Read on to see the entire process</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Linux software raid, rebuilding broken raid 1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html</guid>
                <description>Last week Nagios alerted me about a broken disk in one of my clients testing servers. There is a best effort SLA on the thing, and there were spare drives of the same type and size in the datacenter. Lucky me. This particular data center is on biking distance, so I enjoyed a sunny ride there. Simply put, I needed to replace the disk and rebuild the raid 1 array. This server is a simple Ubuntu 12.04 LTS server with two disks running in raid 1, no spare. Client has a tight budget, and with a best effort SLA not in production, fine with me. Consultant tip, make sure you have those things signed. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FreeBSD Ports: remove config options</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_Ports_remove_config_options.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_Ports_remove_config_options.html</guid>
                <description>Today I wanted to upgrade a few packages on one of my FreeBSD servers. The vim port kept complaining: You must select one and only one option from the UI single. Read on to find out how I fixed this error.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Manually verify a certificate against an OCSP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_Manually_Verify_a_certificate_against_an_OCSP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_Manually_Verify_a_certificate_against_an_OCSP.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to manually verfify a certificate against an OCSP server. OCSP stands for the Online Certificate Status Protocol and is one way to validate a certificate status. It is an alternative to the CRL, certificate revocation list. This article shows you how to manually validate a certificate against an OCSP server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: overwrite templates in wrapper-cookbooks</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chef_-_overwrite_templates_in_wrapper_cookbooks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chef_-_overwrite_templates_in_wrapper_cookbooks.html</guid>
                <description>This article describes how to use a template in a wrapper-cookbook in Chef. The Chef Cookbook Wrapper Pattern is based upon a design convention where you customize an existing library cookbook by using a separate wrapper cookbook, which wraps the original cookbook with any related configuration changes. a library cookbook is an existing cookbook, typically an open-source contribution from a user in the Chef community, designed for server configuration purposes. A wrapper cookbook is a cookbook that wraps the original library cookbook with custom modifications or additions such as overriding a Chef attribute, changing a Chef template, converting a Chef attribute to a user-definable input, etc. To override a template by just defining it again would result in it being written two times every Chef run, which is not what we want. Using this method, you can override the template from the default cookbook with a template in your wrapper-cookbook. It has an example for the graphite cookbook, where the wrapper ads LDAP login to the Apache server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: chef_gem vs gem_package and ORDER</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chef_-_chef_gem_vs_gem_package_and_ORDER.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chef_-_chef_gem_vs_gem_package_and_ORDER.html</guid>
                <description>This article describes a situation I had at one of my clients with Chef and the steps took to resolve this problem. They have a cookbook which builds a postgresql database node and it installs the pg ruby gem. However, it uses the chef_gem resource to do that, and it keeps failing.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Remove all Apple Remote Dekstop settings</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Remove_all_Apple_Remote_Desktop_settings.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Remove_all_Apple_Remote_Desktop_settings.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to remove all Apple Remote Desktop settings. My ARD installation recently stopped working correctly, having problems discovering new machines and connecting to already set up machines. These commands wipe all settings and the ARD installation is clean again. This solved my problem.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>3D modeling a real world object in OpenSCAD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/3D_modelling_a_real_world_object_in_OpenSCAD.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/3D_modelling_a_real_world_object_in_OpenSCAD.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how I built a real world object in OpenSCAD and how I got it 3D printed. OpenSCAD is a Solid 3D modeling based on the Computational Geometry Algorithms Library. It is not like Blender, AutoCAD or Maya, who allow you to visually create and manipulate something. OpenSCAD allows you to program the entire thing. Want a cube? Type cube([10,10,10]) and you have a cube. I have no previous experience in 3D modeling or OpenSCAD, however, in about three hours I had my key ready made.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>KVM add disk image or swap image to virtual machine with virsh</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_add_disk_image_or_swap_image_to_virtual_machine_with_virsh.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_add_disk_image_or_swap_image_to_virtual_machine_with_virsh.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to create and add a disk image to a KVM vm using virsh. This is useful when you for example want to expand the disk space of your virtual machine when it is using LVM, or if you want to add a swap disk to a virtual machine.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>KVM convert qcow2 disk images to raw disk images for performance</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_convert_qcow2_disk_images_to_raw_disk_images_for_performance.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_convert_qcow2_disk_images_to_raw_disk_images_for_performance.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to convert KVM qcow2 disk images to raw disk images. The qcow2 disk format has some decent features like encryption, compression and copy to write support. However, the compression and the copy processes make it quite a bit slower than raw disk images. Sometimes you want to convert the disk images so that the VM will perform better. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>KVM host with bonding and VLAN tagged Virtual Machines setup on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_with_bonding_and_VLAN_tagging_setup_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_with_bonding_and_VLAN_tagging_setup_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to setup Ubuntu 12.04 as a KVM host with multiple virtual machines. The kvm host will have VM's in multiple VLAN's and will handle the VLAN tagging over a bonded interface. It also covers creation of an example virtual machine with the ubuntu vmbuilder tool and shows you how to add a serial console to an ubuntu 12.04 virtual machine for troubleshooting.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bonding NIC Teaming on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NIC_Bonding_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NIC_Bonding_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to setup NIC bonding / NIC teaming on Ubuntu 12.04. Bonding, also called port trunking or link aggregation means combining several network interfaces (NICs) to a single link, providing either high-availability, load-balancing, maximum throughput, or a combination of these.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install extra software in the VMWare vCenter Appliance (VCSA)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare_vCenter_Appliance_Install_Extra_Software.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare_vCenter_Appliance_Install_Extra_Software.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to install extra software in the VMWare vCenter appliance (VCSA). VMWare provides a vCenter appliance, which is a SUSE Linux Enterprise Server appliance with the VMWare vCenter server software installed. Because this is SUSE, we can add repositories and install software from there. By default it comes without repositories enabled. I needed to do this because I want to use NRPE on the vCenter appliance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Get all certificates from a website in plain text</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to get all certificates of a website in plain text. With a few OpenSSL commands one can get the website certificate plus intermediate certificates, however, if you feed that output to OpenSSL it only works on the first certificate. Using a bit of sed and bash magic we can feed all certificates one by one to OpenSSL.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OCSP Stapling on Apache</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_Apache2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_Apache2.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up OCSP stapling on Apache. OCSP stapling is an enhancement to the standard OCSP protocol that delivers OCSP responses from the server with the certificate, eliminating the need for relying parties (web users) to check OCSP responses with the issuing CA. This has the effect of reducing bandwidth, improving perceived site performance, and increasing security for everyone involved in establishing the secure session.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OCSP Stapling on nginx</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_nginx.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_nginx.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up OCSP stapling on nginx. OCSP stapling is an enhancement to the standard OCSP protocol that delivers OCSP responses from the server with the certificate, eliminating the need for relying parties (web users) to check OCSP responses with the issuing CA. This has the effect of reducing bandwidth, improving perceived site performance, and increasing security for everyone involved in establishing the secure session.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: intercept all cookies and set secure attribute</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_intercept_all_cookies_and_set_secure_attribute.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_intercept_all_cookies_and_set_secure_attribute.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to use haproxy to set the secure attribute on cookies. You might have a backend application which is not able to set the secure attribute on cookies or for which haproxy does the ssl offloading. This simple frontend rspirep sets the secure attribute for all cookies.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check if passwordless sudo can be used in a bash script or nagios check</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple trick to see if you can use passwordless sudo in a script. This for example can be usefull in a Nagios plugin which requires sudo. Instead of putting the sudo line in your README and otherwise having a NRPE Unable to parse result error, you could just give a nice warning message plus the right sudo configuration rule.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused CentOS/Red Hat kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This small article will show you how to remove unused kernels in Red Hat or CentOS. This is sometimes necessary because the /boot partition can fill up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>rc.local support on Arch Linux with systemd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/rc.local_support_on_Arch_Linux_and_systemd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/rc.local_support_on_Arch_Linux_and_systemd.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple tutorial on how to get /etc/rc.local support back in Arch Linux or any distro with systemd. Arch Linux uses systemd. Therefore, init functions like rc.local are not supported anymore. This systemd service allows you to have support for `/etc/rc.local`.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible Inventory from VMWare</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible__Dynamic_Inventory_From_VMware_vCenter.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible__Dynamic_Inventory_From_VMware_vCenter.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple script which lets you use VMWare vCenter as a dynamic inventory for Ansible.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Simple command line arguments</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add command line arguments to your script. It is very simple, non-positional and does not use getopts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Playbook Testing</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible article shows you how to run a basic test on your playbooks to check if their syntax is correct. It shows methods for both Ansible 1.3 and 1.4. When you get more complicated Ansible playbooks you sometimes have syntax (YAML) errors in them. It sometimes can take a while before those errors show up because they are lower in a playbook. By running the syntax check you make sure this won't happen.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Local W3C HTML5 Validator Server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Local_W3C_HTML5_Validator_Server.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Local_W3C_HTML5_Validator_Server.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a local instance of the w3c html validator, including HTML5 validation support via a local instance of the Validator.nu HTML5 validator. The online w3 validator has strict limits and will ban you for some time if you validate to often. So if you for example have a local unit test to check a website you will get banned a lot. Which is understandable of course, it is a free service. They provide all source code plus it is in the debian repositories, it is dead simple to set up one yourself.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do something if another action changed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how execute actions only if another action has changed. For example, a playbook which downloads a remote key for package signing but only executes the apt-add command if the key has changed. Or a playbook which clones a git repository and only restarts a service if the git repository has changed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Sudo sometimes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how run some actions via sudo and some not. It also shows you how to run an entire role via sudo or not.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: client side ssl certificates</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_client_side_ssl_certificates.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_client_side_ssl_certificates.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to configure haproxy and client side ssl certificates. It features a few comprehensive examples.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Apache access/error log to syslog</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Apache_access_and_error_log_to_syslog.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Apache_access_and_error_log_to_syslog.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to redirect the Apache access log to syslog using the Customlog statement, and the Error log to syslog via the ErrorLog statement.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Back Up Thunderbird Message Filters</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Thunderbird_Back_Up_Mail__Message_Filters.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Thunderbird_Back_Up_Mail__Message_Filters.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to backup and restore the message filters in Thunderbird on multiple platforms.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install nmap 6.40 on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_nmap_6_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_nmap_6_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to install nmap 6.40 on Ubuntu 12.04. Ubuntu 12.04 has nmap 5.21 in the repositories. nmap 6 features a lot of improvements like full IPv6 support and better and faster scanning.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: set specific ssl ciphers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_set_specific_ssl_ciphers.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_set_specific_ssl_ciphers.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to set specific ciphers for haproxy when using an ssl frontend.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: add strict transport security or any other http header</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_add_strict_transport_security_or_any_other_http_header.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_add_strict_transport_security_or_any_other_http_header.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to add a header to a haproxy response, for example, the HSTS header (http strict transport security).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: ssl backends</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_ssl_backends.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_ssl_backends.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to configure an ssl backend on haproxy 1.5 or higher.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: redirect to ssl or other website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_redirect_to_ssl_or_any_other_website.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_redirect_to_ssl_or_any_other_website.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to use haproxy to redirect http traffic to https or any other website</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: restrict specific URLs to specific IP addresses</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_restrict_specific_urls_to_specific_ip_addresses.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_restrict_specific_urls_to_specific_ip_addresses.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to use haproxy to restrict certain URLs to certain IP addresses. For example, to make sure your admin interface can only be accessed from your company IP address.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ntop-ng 1.1 installation on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ntop-ng-installation-on-Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ntop-ng-installation-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the latest ntop-ng (1.1) on Ubuntu 12.04. ntopng is the next generation version of the original ntop, a network traffic probe that shows the network usage, similar to what the popular top Unix command does. ntop is based on libpcap and it has been written in a portable way in order to virtually run on every Unix platform, MacOSX and on Win32 as well. ntopng users can use a a web browser to navigate through ntop (that acts as a web server) traffic information and get a dump of the network status. In the latter case, ntop can be seen as a simple RMON-like agent with an embedded web interface. This tutorial will walk you through the compilation and installation of ntopng from source.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Corosync Pacemaker - Execute script on failover</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Corosync_Pacemaker_-_Execute_a_script_on_failover.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Corosync_Pacemaker_-_Execute_a_script_on_failover.html</guid>
                <description>With Corosync/Pacemaker there is no easy way to simply run a script on failover. There are good reasons for this, but sometimes you want to do something simple. This tutorial describes how to change the Dummy OCF resource to execute a script on failover.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>DigitalOcean Sucks. Use DigitalOcean!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Digital_Ocean_Sucks._Use_Digital_Ocean.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Digital_Ocean_Sucks._Use_Digital_Ocean.html</guid>
                <description>DigitalOcean Sucks. Use DigitalOcean. Why? Read this article to find out.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP Email Backup.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a bowsable HTML archive and a Maildir folder. Not one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view and no proprietary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password. This release has a few major new features, namely support to backup all available folders in one go and a conversion from HTML Kickstart to Bootstrap.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Self Hosted CryptoCat - Secure self hosted multiuser webchat</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Self_Hosted_CryptoCat_-_Secure_Self_Hosted_Multiuser_Webchat.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Self_Hosted_CryptoCat_-_Secure_Self_Hosted_Multiuser_Webchat.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up a self hosted secure multiuser webchat service with CryptoCat. It covers the set up of ejabberd, nginx and the web interface for CryptoCat. It supports secure encrypted group chat, secure encrypted private chat and file and photo sharing.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Corosync Notes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Corosync_Notes.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Corosync_Notes.html</guid>
                <description>These are my notes and command snippets for usage with Corosync.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused Ubuntu kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This one liner will help you remove unused Ubuntu kernels. Ubuntu does not remove kernels when they install a new one, however the default /boot partition is relatively small, about 100MB. So after 10 kernels, you can get No Space Left On Device errors with apt-get upgrading. Then you can eitehr remove them manually, or use this one liner to automatically remove them all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install the latest ZNC from source on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_the_Lastest_ZNC_from_Source_in_Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_the_Lastest_ZNC_from_Source_in_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install the latest (1.0) version of ZNC (an advanced IRC bouncer) on Ubuntu from source. Why from source? The package in the repositories is quite old and missing features like multiple IRC networks. It also includes an upstart script, and an example config for ZNC. ZNC is an advanced IRC bouncer that is left connected so an IRC client can disconnect/reconnect without losing the chat session.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up your own truly secure, encrypted and shared file synchronization, aka Dropbox clone</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html</guid>
                <description>This article describes my truly secure, encrypted file synchronization service. It used EncFS and dvcs-autosync which lets me share only the encrypted data and mount that locally to get the plaintext. It works on OS X, Linux and ARM linux. This article has setup instructions for all those platforms.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL One liner to create self signed certificate</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_One_line_to_create_self_signed_certificate.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_One_line_to_create_self_signed_certificate.html</guid>
                <description>This is a one-liner for OpenSSL to generate a self signed certificate and private key.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: search in recipe based on roles or recipes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_search_in_recipe_on_roles_or_recipes.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_search_in_recipe_on_roles_or_recipes.html</guid>
                <description>Chef supports a very powerfull search syntax which allows you for example to search all nodes with the graphite-server role and get their IP addresses. This tutorial shows you how to search based on a role a node has or a recipe a node has, plus an example config file with erb syntax. It has an example cookbook which sets up collectd as client and graphite as server. It shows you how to use the search function of Chef to get the IP addresses of the graphite servers and place those in the collectd config files. This technique is applicable to all kinds of services that use a client-server model, for example, munin, haproxy, zabbix and many more.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: include_recipe only_if or not_if</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_include_recipe_only_if_not_if.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_include_recipe_only_if_not_if.html</guid>
                <description>Chef supports including other recipes in cookbooks, for example, I can include the MySQL recipe from a PHP recipe. However, this is not a normal resource but a normal method. Therefore it ignores anything passed to it, including only_if or not_if. This tutorial shows you how to include or not include a recipe based on a variable, comparable with not_if or only_if.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Uninstall and Remove OSSEC</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial shows you how to remove an OSSEC installation. OSSEC is installed from source (via a script), so you have to remove all the things manually instead of with your package manager.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Check if item is in array</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how find out if an array has an item.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Add colour output to your script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to add coloured output to your scripts</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Debug Logging</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add debug logging to a bash script.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Trap Control C (SIGTERM)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to capture a Control C signal in a bash script, for example, to clean up any temp or pid files when your script is killed or closed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OSSEC Server, Client, Web UI and Analogi Dashboard Installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_and_webui_and_analogi_dashboard_installation_on_Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_and_webui_and_analogi_dashboard_installation_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>OSSEC is an Open Source Host-based Intrusion Detection System that performs log analysis, file integrity checking, policy monitoring, rootkit detection, real-time alerting and active response. It runs on most operating systems, including Linux, MacOS, Solaris, HP-UX, AIX and Windows. It also includes agentless monitoring for use with for example Cisco or Juniper hardware. This tutorial covers the installation of the OSSEC server, the standard OSSEC Web UI and the Analogi dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04. It also covers OSSEC setup with MySQL support, including a Makefile bugfix. Last but not least it shows you how to install the OSSEC agent on a *NIX system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Enable access for assistive devices via the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Enable-Access-for-assistive-devices-via-command-line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Enable-Access-for-assistive-devices-via-command-line.html</guid>
                <description>This command enables access for assistive devices on Apple OS X machines via the command line. This is needed for software like SpectacleApp or SizeUp. This article has methods for OS X Mavericks 10.9 as for 10.8 and 10.7</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Applescript to lock date and time preference panel to fix local sudo exploit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS-X-Applescript-To-Lock-Date-Time-Settings-Panel-for-Sudo-Exploit.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS-X-Applescript-To-Lock-Date-Time-Settings-Panel-for-Sudo-Exploit.html</guid>
                <description>This applescript locks the OS X Date and Time Preference Panel. It can be run via Apple Remote Desktop. This is related to CVE-2013-1775, a local sudo root exploit on OS X. If the date and time preference panel is locked, setting the date and time also requires a sudo password</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPv4 Address Conversion Tricks</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/IPv4_Address_Conversion_Tricks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/IPv4_Address_Conversion_Tricks.html</guid>
                <description>Did you know that http://3515693643/ is a valid link? Why? Because this is the decimal form of the binary IP address. Normally we represent IP addresses as 10.0.0.1, 4 blocks of numbers. Those numbers are actually binary octets represented in decimal, therefore they can never be more than 255. If we take the whole binary number of all blocks, and convert that to base 10, we get a result like above, which in turn is a working network address. I've written a little javascript based converter so you can try it out yourself.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ dnsmasq set capabilities failed fix</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</guid>
                <description>When running dnsmasq under OpenVZ I sometimes get an error when restarting: set capabilities failed. This is because dnsmasq starts as root, then does privileged stuff and then drops to the configured run user. In OpenVZ these permissions are not passed to the VPS, sadly. These three commands fix the problem.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bind DNS Query Graph Charts with GNUPlot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bind-GNUPlot-DNS-Bar-Graph.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bind-GNUPlot-DNS-Bar-Graph.html</guid>
                <description>This is a very simple script which uses GNUplot to create graphs of Bind Query logs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Microsoft Exchange / Active Directory Powershell script to notify users of expiring Passwords</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Microsoft_Exchange_Powershell_Script_User_Password_Expiry.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Microsoft_Exchange_Powershell_Script_User_Password_Expiry.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small PowerShell script which emails your users that their password is going to expire in X days. This is needed when you have an Active Directory and Exchange Environment, but your users do not log in to a Windows machine bound to the Active Directory, but for example a Mac OS X or Linux machine with Full Disk Encryption enabled. Then they are not notified that their password is about to expire. This script can run as a scheduled task and scan and email your users that their password is about to expire.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios - Hide all hosts in hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_-_Hide-entire-hostgroup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_-_Hide-entire-hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to hide all hosts from a hostgroup in Nagios, including the webinterface and email/sms notifications. It does however monitors and checks all the hosts in the hostgroup, so when there are problems you can view the hosts in Nagios. This is usefull for example when you have a staging, preproduction and production environment monitored by the same Nagios host, or by a Nagios cluster, and want to hide all of staging, but do want to quickly view the status when developers complain about a node.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Diffie Hellman Key Exchange Dutch Notes and Example</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Diffie-Hellman-Key-Exchange-Dutch-Notes.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Diffie-Hellman-Key-Exchange-Dutch-Notes.html</guid>
                <description>This is a Dutch article on a Diffie Hellman Key Exchange, including an example. I wrote this to better understand the Diffie Hellman Key Exchange.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL - Generate Psuedo Random Passwords</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Password_Generator.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Password_Generator.html</guid>
                <description>This a snippet to generate a psuedo random password fast via the command line with OpenSSL. It generates a number of random bytes, which can either be output raw, as Base64 or as HEX. The Base64 output is a good password most of the time.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My Todo.txt Workflow, including Unison, Todour and Android</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/My_Todo.txt_Workflow.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/My_Todo.txt_Workflow.html</guid>
                <description>Todo.txt is a way to manage your tasks/todo items in a plaintext format. It has a few simple rules, there are a lot of applications to work with it, but in its core it is a plaintext file, so a text editor is sufficient to use it. Recently I started using todo.txt, including syncing on all my devices via my own servers. This article shows you my workflow, and how to set up a similar environment, including ssh, unison, todour for OS X, DayTasks for Ubuntu and Simpletasks Cloudless for Android.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Stong SSL Security on Lighttpd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Lighttpd_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Lighttpd_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up strong SSL security on the lighttpd webserver. We do this by disabling SSL Compression to mitigate the CRIME attack, disable SSLv3 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will set up a strong ciphersuite that enables Forward Secrecy when possible. This way we have a strong and future proof ssl configuration and we get an A on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Pass the SSL Labs Test on NGINX (Mitigate the CRIME and BEAST attack, Disable SSLv2 and Enable Perfect Forward Secrecy).</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_NGINX_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_NGINX_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to get an A on the SSL Labs test using the NGINX webserver. We do this by disabling CBC based ciphers to mitigate the BEAST attack, disabling SSL Compression to mitigate the CRIME attack, disable SSLv2 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will enable Perfect Forward Secrecy when possible. This way we have a future proof ssl configuration and we get an A on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Pass the SSL Labs Test on Apache2 (Mitigate the CRIME and BEAST attack, Disable SSLv2 and Enable Perfect Forward Secrecy).</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Apache2_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Apache2_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to get an A on the SSL Labs test using the Apache2 webserver. We do this by disabling CBC based ciphers to mitigate the BEAST attack, disabling SSL Compression to mitigate the CRIME attack, disable SSLv2 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will enable Perfect Forward Secrecy when possible. This way we have a future proof ssl configuration and we get an A on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Sparkling Network</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Sparkling_Network.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Sparkling_Network.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of all the servers in the Sparkling Network, mostly as an overview for myself, but it might be interesting for others. It also has a status overview of the nodes...</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Disable Notification Center</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Disable_Notification_Centre.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Disable_Notification_Centre.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to disable the OS X Notification Center completely, the menu item and the sidebar. It also gives you the command to enable it again.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>bdsh - Whitelist Restricted Shell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</guid>
                <description>A shell where you whitelist commands and only those commands can be executed. Either via ssh, as an interactive shell or launched with commands. Logs everything and escapes dangerous characters. bdsh stands for Boa Diminish SHell. You can probably guess why. It might have to to with snakes and restricting users, no pun intended.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Strip all non-ascii characters from a file</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Strip_all_non-ascii_characters_from_a_file.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Strip_all_non-ascii_characters_from_a_file.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet strips all non-ascii characters from a file. It backs up the original file. This is handy if you have input for programs that bork on non-ascii input like older mainframes and such.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Samba Shares with Active Directory Login on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SAMBA_Share_with_Active_Directory_Login_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SAMBA_Share_with_Active_Directory_Login_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a SAMBA server which authenticates all users to an Active Directory, including group based permissions. It uses Samba, Winbind, Kerberos and nsswitch. This allows you to have a Linux machine serving files via SMB, where your authentication and autorization for the files and folders is done via Active Directory.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Incremental History Search / Autocomplete </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet for your .bashrc or your .inputrc changes the Up/Down arrow behavior to autocomplete what is already typed instead of just go back in history.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Dogtag / Red Hat Certificate System reset admin pkiconsole password</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dogtag_Red_Hat_Certificate_System_Reset_Admin_pkiconsole_Password.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dogtag_Red_Hat_Certificate_System_Reset_Admin_pkiconsole_Password.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to reset the password for the PKI Console within the Red Hat Certificate System (Dogtag).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ejabberd SSL Certificate</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_SSL_Certificate.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_SSL_Certificate.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up an SSL Certificate for use with Ejabberd. It covers both the creation of the Certificate Signing Request, the preparing of the certificate for use with Ejabberd and the installation of the certificate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ejabberd Active Directory LDAP Login</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_Active_Directory_LDAP_Login.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_Active_Directory_LDAP_Login.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up ejabberd to authenticate to an Active Directory LDAP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a federated XMPP Chat Network with ejabberd, your own Google Talk Hangouts alternative</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_federated_XMPP_Chat_Network_with_ejabberd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_federated_XMPP_Chat_Network_with_ejabberd.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up your own federated chat network using ejabberd. It covers a basic single node ejabberd server and also the setup of an ejabberd cluster, including errors and DNS SRV record examples. Last but not least federation is also covered.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Turn Bonjour off or on via the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet switches off Bonjour on OS X via the command line or Apple Remote Desktop. This is useful when you want to disable iChat or Messages chatting on the local network. Bonjour is Apple's implementation of Zero configuration networking (Zeroconf), a group of technologies that includes service discovery, address assignment, and hostname resolution. Bonjour locates devices such as printers, other computers, and the services that those devices offer on a local network using multicast Domain Name System (mDNS) service records.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Turn off sleep from the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_off_sleep_from_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_off_sleep_from_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet turns off Sleep on an OS X machine, either iMac or Macbook. Normally when a Mac is not used it goes in sleep mode, this turns that off.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Create Hardware report SPX and save it to a AFP share</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS_X_Create_Hardware_report_spx_and_save_it_to_a_AFP_share.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS_X_Create_Hardware_report_spx_and_save_it_to_a_AFP_share.html</guid>
                <description>This script creates a OS X hardware report (an SPX file) and saves it to a AFP share. This is usefull when you are rolling out new machines. Run this script via Apple Remote Desktop and you have all your administration in your AFP share, which you can later put in your CMDB. The report has all the hardware data, from firmware, serial number, model, MAC addresses, disk and memory information, in short everything you need for your CMDB and support contracts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Gitlab Active Directory LDAP Authentication</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Gitlab_and_Active_Directory_LDAP_Authentication.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Gitlab_and_Active_Directory_LDAP_Authentication.html</guid>
                <description>Gitlab is a self hosted git based source control application similar to Github, written in Ruby on Rails. It is used by many organisations and is a wonderfull piece of software. It supports LDAP Authentication (via the OmniAuth Gem), but it is tricky to set up with Active Directory and Windows Server 2003/2008/2012. This tutorials shows you how to set up Gitlab to authenticate against Active Directory LDAP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Turn firewall on or off from the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_-_Turn_firewall_on_or_off_from_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_-_Turn_firewall_on_or_off_from_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This command lets you turn the build in OS X firewall on and off, on both for specific services or essential services. It works with OS X 10.5, 10.6, 10.7 and 10.8.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2007 and 2010 Autodiscovery DNS SRV record for BIND</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</guid>
                <description>This is a BIND configuration example to set up Exchange Autodiscovery. Autodiscovery is the ability for Outlook to automatically configure itself to an Exchange 2007/2010 server. The main benefit is for remote users to use Outlook on the Internet as if it was connected on the LAN, this is called Outlook Anywhere or Outlook RPC over HTTP. This is very easily accomplished by having a specific DNS record available for the domain. However, the only examples Microsoft gives you are for their own software. This is the BIND version of the record.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Hide or determine BIND version number</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Get_DNS_server_version_and_hide_it_in_BIND.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Get_DNS_server_version_and_hide_it_in_BIND.html</guid>
                <description>The BIND nameserver (and many others) return their version number when queried a special DNS query. This tutorial shows you how to query the BIND version and how to stop your own BIND server sending its version out.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check an OCSP server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_OCSP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_OCSP.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin to check an OCSP server. You can give it a hard coded certificate or your own one. This is sent to the OCSP server and the response is then parsed to give the correct nagios result. It is targeted at administrators who have their own OCSP and need to know when it is not working.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check Safenet HSM</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_Plugin_to_check_a_Safenet_HSM.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_Plugin_to_check_a_Safenet_HSM.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin which checks a Safenet Protectserver External HSM via the Safenet tools.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check CRL expiry in minutes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_CRL_expiry.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_CRL_expiry.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin which you can use to check if a CRL (Certificate Revocation List, public list with revoked certificates) is still valid.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Join Mac OS X to an Active Directory / OpenDLAP directory from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet joins an Mac OS X computer to a Windows Active Directory or OpenLDAP Directory domain from the Command Line or via Apple Remote Desktop.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>HP ILO - Quickly gather ILO version and firmware information via CURL</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/HP-ILO-Quickly-gather-firmware-and-version-information-with-CUR.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/HP-ILO-Quickly-gather-firmware-and-version-information-with-CUR.html</guid>
                <description>Have a lot of HP servers with ILO cards, and want to gather information from them quicly? By default you can get some information in XML format, for ILO, ILO2, ILO3 and ILO4, with curl.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin plugin to show Logstash/Kibana messages per hour</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Munin_plugin_Logstash_Kibana_messages_per_hour.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Munin_plugin_Logstash_Kibana_messages_per_hour.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple munin plugin which shows you the amount of log messages your logstash/kibana server receives per hour.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd client</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd client for use with a collectd server. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;).</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd server with web frontend</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd server. It also shows you how to set up the collectd-web frontend, an interactive gui for collectd, and has it all firewalled. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;). A collectd server is able to receive data from collectd clients.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NGINX: Proxy folders to different root</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NGINX_proxy_folder_to_different_root.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NGINX_proxy_folder_to_different_root.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to have NGINX use different folders as different upstream proxy's, without the proxy also having the folder. For example, if you proxy www.example.com/wiki to server wiki.example.com, by default it will go to wiki.example.com/wiki. This tutorial has a rewrite rule to fix that.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Silent unatended apt-get upgrade</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Silent-automatic-apt-get-upgrade.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Silent-automatic-apt-get-upgrade.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to setup completely silent apt-get upgrade via cron. It also defaults to not overwriting config files if a package has a newer version.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - sudoers safety and sanity checking in playbook</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</guid>
                <description>Using Ansible to manage the /etc/sudoers file is fine, except when you have a syntax error in your template. This method helps you to only deploy a correct sudoers file.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NGINX: Catch all error codes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Catch_all_error_codes.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Catch_all_error_codes.html</guid>
                <description>This little nginx config snippet shows you how to catch all error codes and show a single unified error page.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NGINX: Hide / Block .git and .svn folders</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Block_access_to_.git_or_.svn_project_folders.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Block_access_to_.git_or_.svn_project_folders.html</guid>
                <description>This little nginx config snippets helps you prohibit access to .git or .svn folders in nginx</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Hosted Piwik</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Hosted_Piwik.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Hosted_Piwik.html</guid>
                <description>Piwik is an open source alternative to Google Analytics. I provide a free hosted version for your website at hosted-oswa.org</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - pure ssh based configuration management and deployment</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will get you started with Ansible. Ansible is a radically simple model-driven configuration management, deployment, and command execution framework. Other tools in this space have been too complicated for too long, require too much bootstrapping, and have too much learning curve. By comparison, Ansible is dead simple and painless to extend. Puppet and Chef have about 60k lines of code. Ansibles core is a little over 2000 lines.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Screenfetch installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install screenfetch, a bash information tool. It displays handy system information at login, including distro name, kernel, uptime, cpu, ram and nice distro-based artwork. The tutorial includes support for bash and zsh, for every supported linux OS (ubuntu, centos, arch, redhat, solusOS, linux mint and more.)</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Better Cron env and shell control with the SHELL variable</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html</guid>
                <description>Have better control over env variables and shell settings in cron via the SHELL variable and a few scripts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Word occurrence counter and analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Word_occurrence_counter_and_analyzer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Word_occurrence_counter_and_analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>With these commands you can analyze a text file. It will count all the occurrences of all words and put out the stats. It is usefull for song lyrics, books, notes and everything.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Create a VMWare ESXi 5  5.1 5.5 USB install disk</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare-ESXi-5-USB-installer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare-ESXi-5-USB-installer.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how you can convert a VMWare ESXi 5, 5.1 and 5.5 iso image to a USB install disk. You will learn how to create a USB drive from which you can install VMWare ESXi 5.1. This also works for the special HP version of ESXi with all the drivers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Basic website and database backups with Duplicity</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will help you backup your website and database with Duplicity. You can safely backup your MySQL, MongoDB, website and other data to an off-site location.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Systemd rosetta / cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</guid>
                <description>A reference for systemd, for sysadmins who love plain old init.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL Generate CSR non-interactive</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_generate_CSR_non-interactivemd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_generate_CSR_non-interactivemd.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short command to generate a CSR (certificate signing request) with openssl without being prompted for the values which go in the certificate's Subject field.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL match certificate and private key</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_match_certificate_with_private_key.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_match_certificate_with_private_key.html</guid>
                <description>This check lets you know if a certificate matches a private key. Today I had to set up something but I kept getting ssl errors. Turns out, the certificate did not match the private key, because the private key file was damaged. This is how I found out.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Fix MySQL plugin on Ubuntu 12.04 and Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Debian 6 and Ubuntu 12.04 the Munin MySQL plugin does not work by default because of a missing package. Here is a little trick on fixing it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Set up the NGINX status plugin on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This little tutorial will show you how to set up the Munin plugin to monitor NGINX (nginx_request and nginx_status) and graph it. You need to change some URLs in the config because by default this is wrong.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exploring /proc/ - tips and tricks for the procfs</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Procfs_tips_and_tricks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Procfs_tips_and_tricks.html</guid>
                <description>This article has a lot of nice tips and trics on using the procfs linux virtual file system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL one liner to get expiry date from SSL Certificate of any website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Get_Certificate_Expiry_Date_and_Other_Info.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Get_Certificate_Expiry_Date_and_Other_Info.html</guid>
                <description>This little openssl one liner gets the expiry date from a website's ssl certificate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Fix CentOS IPTables rule saving (iptables: Saving firewall rules to /etc/sysconfig/iptables: /etc/init.d/iptables: line 274: restorecon: command not found)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_Save_iptables_restorecon_error.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_Save_iptables_restorecon_error.html</guid>
                <description>On a default CentOS installation, when trying to execute the iptables save command you can get an error like iptables: Saving firewall rules to /etc/sysconfig/iptables: /etc/init.d/iptables: line 274: restorecon: command not found. Read this article to find out how to fix it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Restrict SSH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html</guid>
                <description>restrict_ssh.sh is a bash script which restricts ssh for a user to a set of commands via .ssh/authorized_keys, and log it verbosely.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>RT (Request Tracker) - find and delete big attachments</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/RT_find__and_delete_big_attachments.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/RT_find__and_delete_big_attachments.html</guid>
                <description>RT (Request Tracker) can save attachments. It saves these in the database (mysql). I had an issue where my mysqldump used in backupping RT would fail due to an `mysqldump: Error 2020: Got packet bigger than 'max_allowed_packet' bytes when dumping table Attachments at row: xxxxx error. Adding the --max_allowed_packet=500M parameter to the mysqldump command didn't work, so here is how to search and find big attachments in RT using mysql.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install python 2.7 or 3 under Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_Python_2.7_or_3_on_debian_6.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_Python_2.7_or_3_on_debian_6.html</guid>
                <description>Debian 6 by default ships with python 2.6.6. If for some reason need a newer version of python you can either mess with repo's, compile from source or use pythonbrew. This tutorial will show you how to install python 2.7 or 3 under debian 6 using pythonbrew.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ruby script to upload or convert a Maildir Inbox to an IMAP server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ruby_script_to_upload_or_convert_a_Maildir_Inbox_to_an_IMAP_Server.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ruby_script_to_upload_or_convert_a_Maildir_Inbox_to_an_IMAP_Server.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of all the servers in the Sparkling Network, mostly as an overview for myself, but it might be interesting for others. It also has a status overview of the nodes...</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python script to monitor a file for changes and then mail the report with the file attached.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script which checks a file's md5 hash, compares it to a previous (or given) hash and mails a report with the option of attaching the file with the email. I wrote it because I use AIDE on some systems, and I let it auto update the database. This script runs via cron before and after the AIDE run, so I have an archive of databases. But it can be used for all kind of files, not just for the AIDE database.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2010 - OWA - Lock user after x amount of failed logins</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to set up automatic user lockout in Exchange 2010 - Outlook Web Acces (OWA). When a user does 5 wrong login attempts, he/she is locked out from the webinterface. After for example 5 minutes he or she is unlocked again automatically. This helps you mitigate brute force attacks, since an attacker can only try 1 password/minute, but the user will not be blocked for to long. Exchange 2010 has some special register settings to make IIS stop caching, otherwise it would not work. As a bonus you get an LDAP saved search query to view locked out users</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Restore iptables rules after a reboot on debian</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Restore-iptables-rules-after-a-reboot-on-debian.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Restore-iptables-rules-after-a-reboot-on-debian.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial will help you set up iptables to survive a reboot.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Resize OS X Mountain Lion installer to fit on a single layer 4.7 GB DVD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OS-X-Mountain_Lion_iso_resize_to_fit_on_a_single_layer_dvd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OS-X-Mountain_Lion_iso_resize_to_fit_on_a_single_layer_dvd.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you resize the OS X Mountain Lion InstallESD.dmg file to fit on a single layer DVD. The normal .dmg file will give an error that it is to big for a single layer DVD. The install works fine afterwards, the .dmg file just has a defined size of 4.75 GB. Resizing it via the Disk Utility will not work because it is a read only dmg image.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>CIDR Cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/CIDR-Cheatsheet.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/CIDR-Cheatsheet.html</guid>
                <description>This is a handy CIDR cheatsheet.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin optimization guide for Debian (rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice and nice)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to help you tune the performance of Munin using rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice, nice and a few other tricks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set OS X hostname from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Change-Hostname.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Change-Hostname.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet helps you change the hostname of a computer running OS X. OS X defines the hostname/computer name in three places and you need to change all of them.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ClamAV installation and daily scan + report on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ClamAV.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ClamAV.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Limit access to openssh features with the Match option</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Limit_access_to_openssh_features_with_the_Match_keyword.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Limit_access_to_openssh_features_with_the_Match_keyword.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Git-clean</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Git-clean.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Git-clean.html</guid>
                <description>git-clean - bash script to find big (binary) files in a git repo and history, and clean them</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up your own distributed, redundant, and encrypted storage grid with Tahoe-LAFS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tahoe_LAFS_Storage_Grid.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tahoe_LAFS_Storage_Grid.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers the installation and configuration of Tahoe/LAFS, a distributed, encrypted and redundant storage clustering grid.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Small low cost linux pc's, an overview from 11-2012</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_PCs.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_PCs.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of small linux computers, mostly ARM based.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ray-Mon - PHP and Bash server status monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</guid>
                <description>Ray-Mon is a linux server monitoring script written in PHP and Bash, utilizing JSON as data storage. It requires only bash and a webserver on the client side, and only php on the server side. The client currently supports monitoring processes, uptime, updates, amount of users logged in, disk usage, RAM usage and network traffic.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Codename Geld</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Codename_Geld.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Codename_Geld.html</guid>
                <description>Codename Geld is a finance manager written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the values and the visual side is created with the excellent HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke. It is not as fancy as mint.com or gnucash, so if you need advanced features (multiple accounts for example) you might want to use another piece of software. Also, the code is quite messy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ed cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ed_cheatsheet.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ed_cheatsheet.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Persistent reverse (NAT bypassing) SSH tunnel access with autossh</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Autossh_persistent_tunnels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Autossh_persistent_tunnels.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check certificates on local file system</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_check_local_certificate_files.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_check_local_certificate_files.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin to check local ssl certifcates for expiry.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NutsManager</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/NutsManager.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/NutsManager.html</guid>
                <description>NutsManager is a power/gas/water usage tracker written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the values and the visual side is created with the excellent HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke. The graphs are made with the flot framework. It helps me to keep track of my power usage, and shows me on which days I use a lot, and on which days I do not. That way, I know that a LAN party costs me a lot. Also, the code is quite messy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>PHP Task/Todo list</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/PHP-task-list-v2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/PHP-task-list-v2.html</guid>
                <description>This is a task/todo list written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the tasks, and the visual side is created with the HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Complete word count analysis of Security Now, episode 1 trough 370.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Security_Now_Word_Analyzer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Security_Now_Word_Analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>Bash-based analysis of which words are used in the security now podcast by Steve Gibson and Leo Laporte</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Correctly grep and display the uptime, load average and amount of users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Packages</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Software_packages.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Software_packages.html</guid>
                <description>Some software I encounter does not have a debian .deb package available. Via the ./configure, make, sudo checkinstall I compile them into a package and put it up here for download.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Tiny Tiny RSS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS.html</guid>
                <description>Tiny Tiny RSS is an open source web-based news feed (RSS/Atom) reader and aggregator, designed to allow you to read news from any location, while feeling as close to a real desktop application as possible. I will go over the features of TIny Tiny RSS, compare it to Google Reader and write some things I like about it, and things I miss about it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Wallbase.cc commandline bash wget downloader</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Wallbase.cc_Command_line_script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Wallbase.cc_Command_line_script.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script to download wallpapers from wallbase.cc with bash and wget.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Small Operating Systems / Linux Distributions</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_Distros.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_Distros.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of small operating systems and Linux distributions, most of them work well on older hardware (pre-dual core era). It provides screenshots, package information, size and specs and project information on the distro.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Postfix snippets - not finished</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Set_up_an_IMAPS_and_SMTPS_mail_server_with_Postfix_and_Dovecot.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Set_up_an_IMAPS_and_SMTPS_mail_server_with_Postfix_and_Dovecot.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ProxBash - a bash script to manage Proxmox VE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</guid>
                <description>ProxMox VE is a very nice piece of software to setup a VM host very fast, which also is easy manageable via a webinterface. It supports both OpenVZ and KVM. I use it to manage a few VM's to test stuff on and it works really great. However, I'm a command line lover, and I thought it would be nice to be able to 'Manage' Proxmox VE from a bash shell. And I've written a script to do just that. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ubuntu/Debian update mailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</guid>
                <description>This is a bash script for Ubuntu and Debian, to be run by cron on a set interval. It checks if there are apt-updates, and if so, mails an overview of the packages which can be updated, whith their local version, the version available and an URL to the Ubuntu package site where you can see the changelog. I wrote this as an addition for my Nagios monitoring, that only shows how many updates there are, this is a lot more verbose. It also runs on Debian since 1 Nov 2012. Only the links don't work then, because the packages are different.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Terrible Start</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Terrible-start.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Terrible-start.html</guid>
                <description>This is a python based Linux start/welcome screen written for Terrible Linux</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash - do something in every subdirectory</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html</guid>
                <description>Snippet which has a copy paste bash for loop to do something in a directory.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash script to list all changed files in certain period</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/List-all-changed-files-in-a-certain-period.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/List-all-changed-files-in-a-certain-period.html</guid>
                <description>This is a little script I wrote and use to get a daily report of all the files that have changed on my servers. What it does is list all the files that are modified within a certain time period from a given directory. It can also be run from a desktop machine, or any machine which runs bash, find and ls. Usage is simple, save the script, chmod +x it, then run (./report.sh). If you want a specific directory to be scanned run it like ./report.sh /var/www/my/dir</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a local Ubuntu (apt) repository with apt-mirror</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_local_Ubuntu_debian_apt_mirror.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_local_Ubuntu_debian_apt_mirror.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to setup your own debian/ubuntu package repository with apt-mirror.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NurseCalc o2 - Bash script and online app for Oxygen Calculations</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-o2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-o2.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you with nursing-related oxygen calculations. Available as bash script and as online HTML5 application.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NurseCalc Infuus - Bash script and Online app for infusion and drip (speed) Calculations </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-Infuus.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-Infuus.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you with nursing-related infusion and drip speed calculations. Available as bash script and as online HTML5 application.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Some Bash and Arch Tweaks </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>MagicProg: Magic the Gathering (RPG/TGC) Life Program </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Magicprog.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Magicprog.html</guid>
                <description>I'm a fervent [Magic the Gathering][7] player. If you do not know what magic is, scroll down for an explanation. I play it a lot in my free time, and I participate in bootserdrafts and casual tournaments here locally. I've developed a program to keep the life in a 2 player game. It's called MagicProg. It will also work for TGC's like pokemon, yu-gi-oh, WoW TCG or any other TGC. And it has a note area.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chrome Extensions for Privacy, Adblocking and anti-tracking</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chrome-extensions-for-privacy.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chrome-extensions-for-privacy.html</guid>
                <description>This is a list with extensions for google chrome which help you block tracking and ads, and help you protect your privacy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Stopping fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication error and other errors in fail2ban on ubuntu 9.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to stop fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication errors on Ubuntu 9.04.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Introduction to DokuWiki</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dokuwiki_Overview.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dokuwiki_Overview.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Introduction to Markdown</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Markdown_Introduction_Tutorial_Overview.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Markdown_Introduction_Tutorial_Overview.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Tether your Sonim XP3 phone with Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tether-your-sonim-xp3-phone-with-linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tether-your-sonim-xp3-phone-with-linux.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how tot tether your sonim xp3 phone with (arch) linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>What to do if you cannot execute CHMOD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/What-to-do-if-you-cannot-execute-chmod.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/What-to-do-if-you-cannot-execute-chmod.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to execute chmod when you have screwed up the permissions of chmod.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP email backup to HTML archive.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a HTML archive, nicely browsable, instead of weird folders (Maildir), one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view (thunderbird) and no propritary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Customize your Clonezilla Live CD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Customize-your-clonezilla-live-CD.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Customize-your-clonezilla-live-CD.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Debian packages clean up commands</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Debian-apt-get-dpkg-packages-cleanup-commands.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Debian-apt-get-dpkg-packages-cleanup-commands.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>EasyConverter</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Easyconverter.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Easyconverter.html</guid>
                <description>Zenity wrapper around ffmpeg to convert media files</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSHdialog</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html</guid>
                <description>SSHdialog - Small command line SSH helper</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clonezilla Backup Script v0.2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Clonezilla-custom-backup-script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Clonezilla-custom-backup-script.html</guid>
                <description>Clonezilla is wonderfull software. At work we use it daily to image laptops. We have a windows PC with a big hard drive, which is shared via samba. Because we image an average of 10 laptops every morning, I decided to customize the script. So together with a colleague we made a script which automatically grabs our latest image from the share and restores it. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Postfix: log message from, to and subject</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Postfix_Log_message_from_to_and_subject_headers.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Postfix_Log_message_from_to_and_subject_headers.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up postfix to log email subject and other headers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSH: Key and user restrictions</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH-Key-Restrictions.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH-Key-Restrictions.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will help you set restrictions for specific ssh keys and users. For example, how to allow only tunneling and how to restrict port forwards.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash script for massive rename to numbers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html</guid>
                <description>Older snippet which was used for dynamic wallpaper switching.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Javascript tricks</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Javascript-tricks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Javascript-tricks.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Convert FLV's to MP3</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html</guid>
                <description>Bash snippet to convert all .flv files to .mp3.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Setting up Motion with FTP and Email! support</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Setting-up-motion-with-ftp-and-email-support.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Setting-up-motion-with-ftp-and-email-support.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash ja/nee keuze</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html</guid>
                <description>Dutch snippet on adding a yes/no choice in a bash script</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Imagemagick thumbnailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html</guid>
                <description>Create some nice thumbnails with Imagemagick</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Vim Cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Vim_Cheatsheet.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Vim_Cheatsheet.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>About</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/static/About.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/static/About.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    