<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s</link> 
            <description>The raymii.org RSS feed, all about GNU/Linux</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC/L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 13.10 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.10.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.10.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Ubuntu 13.10 using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC/L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 13.04 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Ubuntu 13.04 using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Corosync Notes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Corosync_Notes.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Corosync_Notes.html</guid>
                <description>These are my notes and command snippets for usage with Corosync.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Free Raspberry Pi - October 2013</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Free_Raspberry_Pi_October_2013_Winners.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Free_Raspberry_Pi_October_2013_Winners.html</guid>
                <description>The winners of the first Free Raspberry Pi Giveaway are known. I am giving away two Raspberry Pi computers each month to anybody with a good idea. If you write down your idea or code and post it to Github and the voting page, you might win. The two ideas with the most votes at the end of the month get a free Raspberry Pi, Model B, including an SD card, USB cable and free shipping anywhere in the world. The first month was a great success, with almost a hundred ideas posted, over 5000 votes cast and about 2000 people voting on ideas. Read on to find out who won the first two Raspberry Pis'.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused Ubuntu kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This one liner will help you remove unused Ubuntu kernels. Ubuntu does not remove kernels when they install a new one, however the default /boot partition is relatively small, about 100MB. So after 10 kernels, you can get No Space Left On Device errors with apt-get upgrading. Then you can eitehr remove them manually, or use this one liner to automatically remove them all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install the latest ZNC from source on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_the_Lastest_ZNC_from_Source_in_Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_the_Lastest_ZNC_from_Source_in_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install the latest (1.0) version of ZNC (an advanced IRC bouncer) on Ubuntu from source. Why from source? The package in the repositories is quite old and missing features like multiple IRC networks. It also includes an upstart script, and an example config for ZNC. ZNC is an advanced IRC bouncer that is left connected so an IRC client can disconnect/reconnect without losing the chat session.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up your own truly secure, encrypted and shared file synchronization, aka Dropbox clone</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html</guid>
                <description>This article describes my truly secure, encrypted file synchronization service. It used EncFS and dvcs-autosync which lets me share only the encrypted data and mount that locally to get the plaintext. It works on OS X, Linux and ARM linux. This article has setup instructions for all those platforms.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Free Raspberry Pi</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/static/Free_Raspberry_Pi.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/static/Free_Raspberry_Pi.html</guid>
                <description>Do you have a good idea, open source software project, itch to scratch or are you just interested in the Raspberry Pi? .I'm giving away two Raspberry Pi's per month, for free, to anybody which has a good use for it. It includes a case and a USB cable. Shipping included to anywhere in the world. However, there are a few conditions, which are listed in on the page.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL One liner to create self signed certificate</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_One_line_to_create_self_signed_certificate.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_One_line_to_create_self_signed_certificate.html</guid>
                <description>This is a one-liner for OpenSSL to generate a self signed certificate and private key.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: search in recipe based on roles or recipes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_search_in_recipe_on_roles_or_recipes.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_search_in_recipe_on_roles_or_recipes.html</guid>
                <description>Chef supports a very powerfull search syntax which allows you for example to search all nodes with the graphite-server role and get their IP addresses. This tutorial shows you how to search based on a role a node has or a recipe a node has, plus an example config file with erb syntax. It has an example cookbook which sets up collectd as client and graphite as server. It shows you how to use the search function of Chef to get the IP addresses of the graphite servers and place those in the collectd config files. This technique is applicable to all kinds of services that use a client-server model, for example, munin, haproxy, zabbix and many more.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: include_recipe only_if or not_if</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_include_recipe_only_if_not_if.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_include_recipe_only_if_not_if.html</guid>
                <description>Chef supports including other recipes in cookbooks, for example, I can include the MySQL recipe from a PHP recipe. However, this is not a normal resource but a normal method. Therefore it ignores anything passed to it, including only_if or not_if. This tutorial shows you how to include or not include a recipe based on a variable, comparable with not_if or only_if.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Uninstall/Remove OSSEC</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial shows you how to remove an OSSEC installation. OSSEC is installed from source (via a script), so you have to remove all the things manually instead of with your package manager.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Check if item is in array</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how find out if an array has an item.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Add colour output to your script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to add coloured output to your scripts</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Debug Logging</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add debug logging to a bash script.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Trap Control C (SIGTERM)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to capture a Control C signal in a bash script, for example, to clean up any temp or pid files when your script is killed or closed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OSSEC Server, Client, Web UI and Analogi Dashboard Installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_and_webui_and_analogi_dashboard_installation_on_Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_and_webui_and_analogi_dashboard_installation_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>OSSEC is an Open Source Host-based Intrusion Detection System that performs log analysis, file integrity checking, policy monitoring, rootkit detection, real-time alerting and active response. It runs on most operating systems, including Linux, MacOS, Solaris, HP-UX, AIX and Windows. It also includes agentless monitoring for use with for example Cisco or Juniper hardware. This tutorial covers the installation of the OSSEC server, the standard OSSEC Web UI and the Analogi dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04. It also covers OSSEC setup with MySQL support, including a Makefile bugfix. Last but not least it shows you how to install the OSSEC agent on a *NIX system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Enable access for assitive devices via the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Enable-Access-for-assistive-devices-via-command-line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Enable-Access-for-assistive-devices-via-command-line.html</guid>
                <description>This command enables access for assistive devices on Apple OS X machines via the command line. This is needed for software like SpectacleApp or SizeUp.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Applescript to lock date and time preference panel to fix local sudo exploit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Applescript-To-Lock-Date-Time-Settings-Panel-for-Sudo-Exploit.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Applescript-To-Lock-Date-Time-Settings-Panel-for-Sudo-Exploit.html</guid>
                <description>This applescript locks the OS X Date and Time Preference Panel. It can be run via Apple Remote Desktop. This is related to CVE-2013-1775, a local sudo root exploit on OS X. If the date and time preference panel is locked, setting the date and time also requires a sudo password</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPv4 Address Conversion Tricks</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/IPv4_Address_Conversion_Tricks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/IPv4_Address_Conversion_Tricks.html</guid>
                <description>Did you know that http://3515693643/ is a valid link? Why? Because this is the decimal form of the binary IP address. Normally we represent IP addresses as 10.0.0.1, 4 blocks of numbers. Those numbers are actually binary octets represented in decimal, therefore they can never be more than 255. If we take the whole binary number of all blocks, and convert that to base 10, we get a result like above, which in turn is a working network address. I've written a little javascript based converter so you can try it out yourself.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ dnsmasq set capabilities failed fix</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</guid>
                <description>When running dnsmasq under OpenVZ I sometimes get an error when restarting: set capabilities failed. This is because dnsmasq starts as root, then does privileged stuff and then drops to the configured run user. In OpenVZ these permissions are not passed to the VPS, sadly. These three commands fix the problem.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bind DNS Query Graph Charts with GNUPlot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bind-GNUPlot-DNS-Bar-Graph.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bind-GNUPlot-DNS-Bar-Graph.html</guid>
                <description>This is a very simple script which uses GNUplot to create graphs of Bind Query logs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Microsoft Exchange / Active Directory Powershell script to notify users of expiring Passwords</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Microsoft_Exchange_Powershell_Script_User_Password_Expiry.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Microsoft_Exchange_Powershell_Script_User_Password_Expiry.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small PowerShell script which emails your users that their password is going to expire in X days. This is needed when you have an Active Directory and Exchange Environment, but your users do not log in to a Windows machine bound to the Active Directory, but for example a Mac OS X or Linux machine with Full Disk Encryption enabled. Then they are not notified that their password is about to expire. This script can run as a scheduled task and scan and email your users that their password is about to expire.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios - Hide all hosts in hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_-_Hide-entire-hostgroup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_-_Hide-entire-hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to hide all hosts from a hostgroup in Nagios, including the webinterface and email/sms notifications. It does however monitors and checks all the hosts in the hostgroup, so when there are problems you can view the hosts in Nagios. This is usefull for example when you have a staging, preproduction and production environment monitored by the same Nagios host, or by a Nagios cluster, and want to hide all of staging, but do want to quickly view the status when developers complain about a node.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Diffie Hellman Key Exchange Dutch Notes and Example</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Diffie-Hellman-Key-Exchange-Dutch-Notes.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Diffie-Hellman-Key-Exchange-Dutch-Notes.html</guid>
                <description>This is a Dutch article on a Diffie Hellman Key Exchange, including an example. I wrote this to better understand the Diffie Hellman Key Exchange.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL - Generate Psuedo Random Passwords</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Password_Generator.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Password_Generator.html</guid>
                <description>This a snippet to generate a psuedo random password fast via the command line with OpenSSL. It generates a number of random bytes, which can either be output raw, as Base64 or as HEX. The Base64 output is a good password most of the time.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My Todo.txt Workflow, including Unison, Todour and Android</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/My_Todo.txt_Workflow.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/My_Todo.txt_Workflow.html</guid>
                <description>Todo.txt is a way to manage your tasks/todo items in a plaintext format. It has a few simple rules, there are a lot of applications to work with it, but in its core it is a plaintext file, so a text editor is sufficient to use it. Recently I started using todo.txt, including syncing on all my devices via my own servers. This article shows you my workflow, and how to set up a similar environment, including ssh, unison, todour for OS X, DayTasks for Ubuntu and Simpletasks Cloudless for Android.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Pass the SSL Labs Test on Lighttpd (Mitigate the CRIME and BEAST attack, Disable SSLv2 and Enable Perfect Forward Secrecy).</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Lighttpd_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Lighttpd_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to get an A on the SSL Labs test using the lighttpd webserver. We do this by disabling CBC based ciphers to mitigate the BEAST attack, disabling SSL Compression to mitigate the CRIME attack, disable SSLv2 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will enable Perfect Forward Secrecy when possible. This way we have a future proof ssl configuration and we get an A on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Pass the SSL Labs Test on NGINX (Mitigate the CRIME and BEAST attack, Disable SSLv2 and Enable Perfect Forward Secrecy).</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_NGINX_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_NGINX_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to get an A on the SSL Labs test using the NGINX webserver. We do this by disabling CBC based ciphers to mitigate the BEAST attack, disabling SSL Compression to mitigate the CRIME attack, disable SSLv2 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will enable Perfect Forward Secrecy when possible. This way we have a future proof ssl configuration and we get an A on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Pass the SSL Labs Test on Apache2 (Mitigate the CRIME and BEAST attack, Disable SSLv2 and Enable Perfect Forward Secrecy).</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Apache2_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Apache2_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to get an A on the SSL Labs test using the Apache2 webserver. We do this by disabling CBC based ciphers to mitigate the BEAST attack, disabling SSL Compression to mitigate the CRIME attack, disable SSLv2 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will enable Perfect Forward Secrecy when possible. This way we have a future proof ssl configuration and we get an A on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Sparkling Network</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/static/Sparkling_Network.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/static/Sparkling_Network.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of all the servers in the Sparkling Network, mostly as an overview for myself, but it might be interesting for others. It also has a status overview of the nodes...</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Disable Notification Center</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Disable_Notification_Centre.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Disable_Notification_Centre.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to disable the OS X Notofication Center completely, the menu item and the sidebar. It also gives you the command to enable it again.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>bdsh - Whitelist Restricted Shell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</guid>
                <description>A shell where you whitelist commands and only those commands can be executed. Either via ssh, as an interactive shell or launched with commands. Logs everything and escapes dangerous characters. bdsh stands for Boa Diminish SHell. You can probably guess why. It might have to to with snakes and restricting users, no pun intended.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Strip all non-ascii characters from a file</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Strip_all_non-ascii_characters_from_a_file.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Strip_all_non-ascii_characters_from_a_file.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet strips all non-ascii characters from a file. It backs up the original file. This is handy if you have input for programs that bork on non-ascii input like older mainframes and such.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Samba Shares with Active Directory Login on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SAMBA_Share_with_Active_Directory_Login_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SAMBA_Share_with_Active_Directory_Login_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a SAMBA server which authenticates all users to an Active Directory, including group based permissions. It uses Samba, Winbind, Kerberos and nsswitch. This allows you to have a Linux machine serving files via SMB, where your authentication and autorization for the files and folders is done via Active Directory.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Incremental History Search / Autocomplete </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet for your .bashrc or your .inputrc changes the Up/Down arrow behaviour to autocomplete what is already typed instead of just go back in history.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Dogtag / Red Hat Certificate System reset admin pkiconsole password</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dogtag_Red_Hat_Certificate_System_Reset_Admin_pkiconsole_Password.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dogtag_Red_Hat_Certificate_System_Reset_Admin_pkiconsole_Password.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to reset the password for the PKI Console within the Red Hat Certificate System (Dogtag).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ejabberd SSL Certificate</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_SSL_Certificate.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_SSL_Certificate.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up an SSL Certificate for use with Ejabberd. It covers both the creation of the Certificate Signing Request, the preparing of the certificate for use with Ejabberd and the installation of the certificate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ejabberd Active Directory LDAP Login</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_Active_Directory_LDAP_Login.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_Active_Directory_LDAP_Login.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up ejabberd to authenticate to an Active Directory LDAP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a federated XMPP Chat Network with ejabberd, your own Google Talk/Hangouts alternative</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_federated_XMPP_Chat_Network_with_ejabberd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_federated_XMPP_Chat_Network_with_ejabberd.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up your own federated chat network using ejabberd. It covers a basic single node ejabberd server and also the setup of an ejabberd cluster, including errors and DNS SRV record examples. Last but not least federation is also covered.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Turn Bonjour off or on via the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet switches off Bonjour on OS X via the command line or Apple Remote Desktop. This is useful when you want to disable iChat or Messages chatting on the local network. Bonjour is Apple's implementation of Zero configuration networking (Zeroconf), a group of technologies that includes service discovery, address assignment, and hostname resolution. Bonjour locates devices such as printers, other computers, and the services that those devices offer on a local network using multicast Domain Name System (mDNS) service records.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Turn off sleep from the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_off_sleep_from_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_off_sleep_from_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet turns off Sleep on an OS X machine, either iMac or Macbook. Normally when a Mac is not used it goes in sleep mode, this turns that off.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Create Hardware report SPX and save it to a AFP share</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS_X_Create_Hardware_report_spx_and_save_it_to_a_AFP_share.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS_X_Create_Hardware_report_spx_and_save_it_to_a_AFP_share.html</guid>
                <description>This script creates a OS X hardware report (an SPX file) and saves it to a AFP share. This is usefull when you are rolling out new machines. Run this script via Apple Remote Desktop and you have all your administration in your AFP share, which you can later put in your CMDB. The report has all the hardware data, from firmware, serial number, model, MAC addresses, disk and memory information, in short everything you need for your CMDB and support contracts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Gitlab Active Directory LDAP Authentication</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Gitlab_and_Active_Directory_LDAP_Authentication.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Gitlab_and_Active_Directory_LDAP_Authentication.html</guid>
                <description>Gitlab is a self hosted git based source control application similair to Github, written in Ruby on Rails. It is used by many organisations and is a wonderfull piece of software. It supports LDAP Authentication (via the OmniAuth Gem), but it is tricky to set up with Active Directory and Windows Server 2003/2008/2012. This tutorials shows you how to set up Gitlab to authenticate against Active Directory LDAP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Turn firewall on or off from the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_-_Turn_firewall_on_or_off_from_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_-_Turn_firewall_on_or_off_from_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This command lets you turn the build in OS X firewall on and off, on both for specific services or essential services. It works with OS X 10.5, 10.6, 10.7 and 10.8.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2007/2010 Autodiscovery DNS SRV record for BIND</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</guid>
                <description>This is a BIND configuration example to set up Exchange Autodiscovery. Autodiscovery is the ability for Outlook to automatically configure itself to an Exchange 2007/2010 server. The main benefit is for remote users to use Outlook on the Internet as if it was connected on the LAN, this is called Outlook Anywhere or Outlook RPC over HTTP. This is very easily accomplished by having a specific DNS record available for the domain. However, the only examples Microsoft gives you are for their own software. This is the BIND version of the record.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Hide or determine BIND version number</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Get_DNS_server_version_and_hide_it_in_BIND.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Get_DNS_server_version_and_hide_it_in_BIND.html</guid>
                <description>The BIND nameserver (and many others) return their version number when queried a special DNS query. This tutorial shows you how to query the BIND version and how to stop your own BIND server sending its version out.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check an OCSP server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_OCSP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_OCSP.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin to check an OCSP server. You can give it a hard coded certificate or your own one. This is sent to the OCSP server and the response is then parsed to give the correct nagios result. It is targeted at administrators who have their own OCSP and need to know when it is not working.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if on specific distribution (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS or RHEL) or distribution version (ubuntu lucid, ubuntu precise)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if you are on a certain distribution. You might have a mixed environment with CentOS and Debian and when using Ansible to execute actions on nodes you don't need to run Yum on Debian, or Apt on CentOS. Some package names are different and such, so this helps you with an only if statement to select a specific distribution. As a bonus, you also get an only_if for specific distribution versions, like Ubuntu Lucid or Ubuntu Precise.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check Safenet HSM</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_Plugin_to_check_a_Safenet_HSM.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_Plugin_to_check_a_Safenet_HSM.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin which checks a Safenet Protectserver External HSM via the Safenet tools.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check CRL expiry in minutes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_CRL_expiry.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_CRL_expiry.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin which you can use to check if a CRL (Certificate Revocation List, public list with revoked certificates) is still valid.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Join Mac OS X to an Active Directory / OpenDLAP directory from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet joins an Mac OS X computer to a Windows Active Directory or OpenLDAP Directory domain from the Command Line or via Apple Remote Desktop.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>HTTP Strict Transport Security for Apache, NGINX and Lighttpd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security_for_Apache_NGINX_and_Lighttpd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security_for_Apache_NGINX_and_Lighttpd.html</guid>
                <description>HTTP Strict Transport Security (often abbreviated as HSTS) is a security feature that lets a web site tell browsers that it should only be communicated with using HTTPS, instead of using HTTP. This tutorial will show you how to set up HSTS in Apache2, NGINX and Lighttpd.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>HP ILO - Quickly gather ILO version and firmware information via CURL</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/HP-ILO-Quickly-gather-firmware-and-version-information-with-CUR.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/HP-ILO-Quickly-gather-firmware-and-version-information-with-CUR.html</guid>
                <description>Have a lot of HP servers with ILO cards, and want to gather information from them quicly? By default you can get some information in XML format, for ILO, ILO2, ILO3 and ILO4, with curl.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin plugin to show Logstash/Kibana messages per hour</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Munin_plugin_Logstash_Kibana_messages_per_hour.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Munin_plugin_Logstash_Kibana_messages_per_hour.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple munin plugin which shows you the amount of log messages your logstash/kibana server receives per hour.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd client</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd client for use with a collectd server. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;).</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd server with web frontend</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd server. It also shows you how to set up the collectd-web frontend, an interactive gui for collectd, and has it all firewalled. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;). A collectd server is able to receive data from collectd clients.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NGINX: Proxy folders to different root</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NGINX_proxy_folder_to_different_root.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NGINX_proxy_folder_to_different_root.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to have NGINX use different folders as different upstream proxy's, without the proxy also having the folder. For example, if you proxy www.example.com/wiki to server wiki.example.com, by default it will go to wiki.example.com/wiki. This tutorial has a rewrite rule to fix that.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Silent unatended apt-get upgrade</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Silent-automatic-apt-get-upgrade.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Silent-automatic-apt-get-upgrade.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to setup completely silent apt-get upgrade via cron. It also defaults to not overwriting config files if a package has a newer version.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if host is also in other hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This trick helps you execute actions only when a host is in another hostgroup in Ansible. For example, you might deploy munin-node via ansible, but you only want your apache and NGINX plugins deployed on your webservers, not on your database servers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - /etc/sudoers safety and sanity checking in playbook</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</guid>
                <description>Using Ansible to manage the /etc/sudoers file is fine, except when you have a syntax error in your template. This method helps you to only deploy a correct sudoers file.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Shared Git repository over ssh for multiple users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to set up a shared git repo with multiple accounts over ssh. Only ssh, not gitolite or any other software. This is usefull if you have a small team of people that don't often need access to the repo and don't want something like github or bitbucket. With this you can use existing infrastructure.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NGINX: Hide / Block .git and .svn folders</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Block_access_to_.git_or_.svn_project_folders.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Block_access_to_.git_or_.svn_project_folders.html</guid>
                <description>This little nginx config snippets helps you prohibit access to .git or .svn folders in nginx</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - pure ssh based configuration management and deployment</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will get you started with Ansible. Ansible is a radically simple model-driven configuration management, deployment, and command execution framework. Other tools in this space have been too complicated for too long, require too much bootstrapping, and have too much learning curve. By comparison, Ansible is dead simple and painless to extend. Puppet and Chef have about 60k lines of code. Ansibles core is a little over 2000 lines.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - pure ssh based configuration management and deployment</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will get you started with Ansible. Ansible is a radically simple model-driven configuration management, deployment, and command execution framework. Other tools in this space have been too complicated for too long, require too much bootstrapping, and have too much learning curve. By comparison, Ansible is dead simple and painless to extend. Puppet and Chef have about 60k lines of code. Ansibles core is a little over 2000 lines.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Hosted Piwik</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/static/Hosted_Piwik.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/static/Hosted_Piwik.html</guid>
                <description>Piwik is an open source alternative to Google Analytics. I provide a free hosted version for your website at hosted-oswa.org</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Screenfetch installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install screenfetch, a bash information tool. It displays handy system information at login, including distro name, kernel, uptime, cpu, ram and nice distro-based artwork. The tutorial includes support for bash and zsh, for every supported linux OS (ubuntu, centos, arch, redhat, solusOS, linux mint and more.)</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Better Cron env and shell control with the SHELL variable</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html</guid>
                <description>Have better control over env variables and shell settings in cron via the SHELL variable and a few scripts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Word occurrence counter and analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Word_occurrence_counter_and_analyzer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Word_occurrence_counter_and_analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>With these commands you can analyze a text file. It will count all the occurrences of all words and put out the stats. It is usefull for song lyrics, books, notes and everything.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Create a VMWare ESXi 5 / 5.1 USB install disk</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare-ESXi-5-USB-installer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare-ESXi-5-USB-installer.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how you can convert a VMWare ESXi 5 and 5.1 iso image to a USB install disk. You will learn how to create a USB drive from which you can install VMWare ESXi 5.1. This also works for the special HP version of ESXi with all the drivers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Basic website and database backups with Duplicity</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will help you backup your website and database with Duplicity. You can safely backup your MySQL, MongoDB, website and other data to an off-site location.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Systemd rosetta / cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</guid>
                <description>A reference for systemd, for sysadmins who love plain old init.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL Generate CSR non-interactive</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_generate_CSR_non-interactivemd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_generate_CSR_non-interactivemd.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short command to generate a CSR (certificate signing request) with openssl without being prompted for the values which go in the certificate's Subject field.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL match certificate and private key</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_match_certificate_with_private_key.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_match_certificate_with_private_key.html</guid>
                <description>This check lets you know if a certificate matches a private key. Today I had to set up something but I kept getting ssl errors. Turns out, the certificate did not match the private key, because the private key file was damaged. This is how I found out.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Fix MySQL plugin on Ubuntu 12.04 and Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Debian 6 and Ubuntu 12.04 the Munin MySQL plugin does not work by default because of a missing package. Here is a little trick on fixing it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Set up the NGINX status plugin on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This little tutorial will show you how to set up the Munin plugin to monitor NGINX (nginx_request and nginx_status) and graph it. You need to change some URLs in the config because by default this is wrong.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exploring /proc/ - tips and tricks for the procfs</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Procfs_tips_and_tricks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Procfs_tips_and_tricks.html</guid>
                <description>This article has a lot of nice tips and trics on using the procfs linux virtual file system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL one liner to get expiry date from SSL Certificate of any website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Get_Certificate_Expiry_Date_and_Other_Info.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Get_Certificate_Expiry_Date_and_Other_Info.html</guid>
                <description>This little openssl one liner gets the expiry date from a website's ssl certificate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Fix CentOS IPTables rule saving (iptables: Saving firewall rules to /etc/sysconfig/iptables: /etc/init.d/iptables: line 274: restorecon: command not found)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_Save_iptables_restorecon_error.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_Save_iptables_restorecon_error.html</guid>
                <description>On a default CentOS installation, when trying to execute the iptables save command you can get an error like iptables: Saving firewall rules to /etc/sysconfig/iptables: /etc/init.d/iptables: line 274: restorecon: command not found. This is fixed easily by installing...</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Restrict SSH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html</guid>
                <description>restrict_ssh.sh is a bash script which restricts ssh for a user to a set of commands via .ssh/authorized_keys, and log it verbosely.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP email backup to HTML archive.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a HTML archive, nicely browsable, instead of weird folders (Maildir), one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view (thunderbird) and no propritary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP email backup to HTML archive.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a HTML archive, nicely browsable, instead of weird folders (Maildir), one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view (thunderbird) and no propritary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>RT (Request Tracker) - find and delete big attachments</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/RT_find__and_delete_big_attachments.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/RT_find__and_delete_big_attachments.html</guid>
                <description>RT (Request Tracker) can save attachments. It saves these in the database (mysql). I had an issue where my mysqldump used in backupping RT would fail due to an `mysqldump: Error 2020: Got packet bigger than 'max_allowed_packet' bytes when dumping table Attachments at row: xxxxx error. Adding the --max_allowed_packet=500M parameter to the mysqldump command didn't work, so here is how to search and find big attachments in RT using mysql.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install python 2.7 or 3 under Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_Python_2.7_or_3_on_debian_6.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_Python_2.7_or_3_on_debian_6.html</guid>
                <description>Debian 6 by default ships with python 2.6.6. If for some reason need a newer version of python you can either mess with repo's, compile from source or use pythonbrew. This tutorial will show you how to install python 2.7 or 3 under debian 6 using pythonbrew.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC/L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 12.10 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.10.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.10.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC/L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 12.04 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC/L2TP VPN on CentOS 6 / Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 / Scientific Linux 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_CentOS_-_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_or_Scientific_-_Linux_6.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_CentOS_-_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_or_Scientific_-_Linux_6.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python script to monitor a file for changes and then mail the report with the file attached.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script which checks a file's md5 hash, compares it to a previous (or given) hash and mails a report with the option of attaching the file with the email. I wrote it because I use AIDE on some systems, and I let it auto update the database. This script runs via cron before and after the AIDE run, so I have an archive of databases. But it can be used for all kind of files, not just for the AIDE database.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2010 - OWA - Lock user after x amount of failed logins</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to set up automatic user lockout in Exchange 2010 - Outlook Web Acces (OWA). When a user does 5 wrong login attempts, he/she is locked out from the webinterface. After for example 5 minutes he or she is unlocked again automaticly. This helps you mitigate brute force attacks, since an attacker can only try 1 password/minute, but the user will not be blocked for to long. Exchange 2010 has some special register settings to make IIS stop caching, otherwise it would not work. As a bonus you get an LDAP saved search query to view locked out users</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Restore iptables rules after a reboot on debian</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Restore-iptables-rules-after-a-reboot-on-debian.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Restore-iptables-rules-after-a-reboot-on-debian.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial will help you set up iptables to survive a reboot.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>CIDR Cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/CIDR-Cheatsheet.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/CIDR-Cheatsheet.html</guid>
                <description>This is a handy CIDR cheatsheet.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Resize OS X Mountain Lion installer to fit on a single layer 4.7 GB DVD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OS-X-Mountain_Lion_iso_resize_to_fit_on_a_single_layer_dvd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OS-X-Mountain_Lion_iso_resize_to_fit_on_a_single_layer_dvd.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you resize the OS X Mountain Lion InstallESD.dmg file to fit on a single layer DVD. The normal .dmg file will give an error that it is to big for a single layer DVD. The install works fine afterwards, the .dmg file just has a defined size of 4.75 GB. Resizing it via the Disk Utility will not work because it is a read only dmg image.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ingsoc</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ingsoc.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ingsoc.html</guid>
                <description>ingsoc is a static site generator written in Python with the purpose of generating raymii.org. It differs from other static site generators because it does not create a blog-like site, but it is focused on pages and structure. It also does not use a template engine. It generates categories, pages, tags and a RSS feed. It takes markdown files with a yaml config header as input, and outputs html.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin optimalization guide for Debian (rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice and nice)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to help you tune the performance of Munin using rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice, nice and a few other tricks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set OS X hostname from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Change-Hostname.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Change-Hostname.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet helps you change the hostname of a computer running OS X. OS X defines the hostname/computer name in three places and you need to change all of them.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ClamAV installation and daily scan + report on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ClamAV.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ClamAV.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Limit access to openssh features with the Match option</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Limit_access_to_openssh_features_with_the_Match_keyword.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Limit_access_to_openssh_features_with_the_Match_keyword.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Git-clean</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Git-clean.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Git-clean.html</guid>
                <description>git-clean - bash script to find big (binary) files in a git repo and history, and clean them</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up your own distributed, redundant, and encrypted storage grid with Tahoe-LAFS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tahoe_LAFS_Storage_Grid.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tahoe_LAFS_Storage_Grid.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers the installation and configuration of Tahoe/LAFS, a distributed, encrypted and redundant storage clustering grid.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Small low cost linux pc's, an overview from 11-2012</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_PCs.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_PCs.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of small linux computers, mostly ARM based.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ray-Mon - PHP/Bash server status monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</guid>
                <description>Ray-Mon is a linux server monitoring script written in PHP and Bash, utilizing JSON as data storage. It requires only bash and a webserver on the client side, and only php on the server side. The client currently supports monitoring processes, uptime, updates, amount of users logged in, disk usage, RAM usage and network traffic.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Codename Geld</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Codename_Geld.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Codename_Geld.html</guid>
                <description>Codename Geld is a finance manager written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the values and the visual side is created with the excellent HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke. It is not as fancy as mint.com or gnucash, so if you need advanced features (multiple accounts for example) you might want to use another piece of software. Also, the code is quite messy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ed cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ed_cheatsheet.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ed_cheatsheet.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Persistent reverse (NAT bypassing) SSH access with autossh</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Autossh_persistent_tunnels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Autossh_persistent_tunnels.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check certificates on local file system</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_check_local_certificate_files.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_check_local_certificate_files.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin to check local ssl certifcates for expiry.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef-Solo code snippets</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Chef-solo_code_snippets.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Chef-solo_code_snippets.html</guid>
                <description>This article is a collection of snippets for Chef. Chef is an open-source systems integration framework supporting Linux, Windows, BSD and more.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NutsManager</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/NutsManager.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/NutsManager.html</guid>
                <description>NutsManager is a power/gas/water usage tracker written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the values and the visual side is created with the excellent HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke. The graphs are made with the flot framework. It helps me to keep track of my power usage, and shows me on which days I use a lot, and on which days I do not. That way, I know that a LAN party costs me a lot. Also, the code is quite messy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>PHP Task/Todo list</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/PHP-task-list-v2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/PHP-task-list-v2.html</guid>
                <description>This is a task/todo list written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the tasks, and the visual side is created with the HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Complete word count analasys of Security Now, episode 1 trough 370.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Security_Now_Word_Analyzer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Security_Now_Word_Analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>Bash-based analasys of which words are used in the security now podcast by Steve Gibson and Leo Laporte</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Correctly grep and display the uptime, load average and amount of users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Packages</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Software_packages.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Software_packages.html</guid>
                <description>Some software I encounter does not have a debian .deb package available. Via the ./configure, make, sudo checkinstall I compile them into a package and put it up here for download.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Tiny Tiny RSS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS.html</guid>
                <description>Tiny Tiny RSS is an open source web-based news feed (RSS/Atom) reader and aggregator, designed to allow you to read news from any location, while feeling as close to a real desktop application as possible. I will go over the features of TIny Tiny RSS, compare it to Google Reader and write some things I like about it, and things I miss about it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a semi-HA GlusterFS replicated webroot (RAID-1 via software)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Gluster-webroot-cluster.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Gluster-webroot-cluster.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Wallbase.cc commandline bash wget downloader</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Wallbase.cc_Command_line_script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Wallbase.cc_Command_line_script.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script to download wallpapers from wallbase.cc with bash and wget.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Small Operating Systems / Linux Distributions</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_Distros.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_Distros.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of small operating systems and Linux distributions, most of them work well on older hardware (pre-dual core era). It provides screenshots, package information, size and specs and project information on the distro.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Postfix snippets - not finished</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Set_up_an_IMAPS_and_SMTPS_mail_server_with_Postfix_and_Dovecot.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Set_up_an_IMAPS_and_SMTPS_mail_server_with_Postfix_and_Dovecot.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ProxBash - a bash script to manage Proxmox VE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</guid>
                <description>ProxMox VE is a very nice piece of software to setup a VM host very fast, which also is easy managable via a webinterface. It supports both OpenVZ and KVM. I use it to manage a few VM's to test stuff on and it works really great. However, I'm a command line lover, and I thought it would be nice to be able to 'Manage' Proxmox VE from a bash shell. And I've written a script to do just that. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ubuntu/Debian update mailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</guid>
                <description>This is a bash script for Ubuntu and Debian, to be run by cron on a set interval. It checks if there are apt-updates, and if so, mails an overview of the packages which can be updated, whith their local version, the version available and an URL to the Ubuntu package site where you can see the changelog. I wrote this as an addition for my Nagios monitoring, that only shows how many updates there are, this is a lot more verbose. It also runs on Debian since 1 Nov 2012. Only the links don't work then, because the packages are different.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Terrible Start</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Terrible-start.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Terrible-start.html</guid>
                <description>This is a python based Linux start/welcome screen written for Terrible Linux</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encryption on EVERY cloud service!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Encryption-on-ANY-cloud-service.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Encryption-on-ANY-cloud-service.html</guid>
                <description>As you maybe know, there are a lot of cloud providers out there. They all offer kind of the same thing, a place for you to store your files. Main differences are the storage space you get and collaborative/syncing features. And, a lot of providers say they are secure, but they do not have 'Trust No One' encryption (which means, you have the key to your data and only you can access it. If you loose the key or password, you're out of luck.) Those companies, like dropbox or google drive at the time of writing, all state that in their terms of service, and/or you are not able to check the source code to verify they can or cannot access your data. What we are going to do to prevent this? Very simple, provide our own pre-internet encryption with truecrypt.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash - do something in every subdirectory</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html</guid>
                <description>Snippet which has a copy paste bash for loop to do something in a directory.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash script to list all changed files in certain peroid</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/List-all-changed-files-in-a-certain-period.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/List-all-changed-files-in-a-certain-period.html</guid>
                <description>This is a little script I wrote and use to get a daily report of all the files that have changed on my servers. What it does is list all the files that are modified within a certain time period from a given directory. It can also be run from a desktop machine, or any machine which runs bash, find and ls. Usage is simple, save the script, chmod +x it, then run (./report.sh). If you want a specific directory to be scanned run it like ./report.sh /var/www/my/dir</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a local Ubuntu (apt) repository with apt-mirror</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_local_Ubuntu_debian_apt_mirror.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_local_Ubuntu_debian_apt_mirror.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to setup your own debian/ubuntu package repository with apt-mirror.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NurseCalc o2 - Bash script and online app for Oxygen Calculations</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-o2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-o2.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you with nursing-related oxygen calculations. Available as bash script and as online HTML5 application.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NurseCalc Infuus - Bash script and Online app for infusion and drip (speed) Calculations </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-Infuus.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-Infuus.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you with nursing-related infusion and drip speed calculations. Available as bash script and as online HTML5 application.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Some Bash and Arch Tweaks </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>MagicProg: Magic the Gathering (RPG/TGC) Life Program </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Magicprog.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Magicprog.html</guid>
                <description>I'm a fervent [Magic the Gathering][7] player. If you do not know what magic is, scroll down for an explanation. I play it a lot in my free time, and I participate in bootserdrafts and casual tournaments here locally. I've developed a program to keep the life in a 2 player game. It's called MagicProg. It will also work for TGC's like pokemon, yu-gi-oh, WoW TCG or any other TGC. And it has a note area.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chrome Extensions for Privacy, Adblocking and anti-tracking</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chrome-extensions-for-privacy.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chrome-extensions-for-privacy.html</guid>
                <description>This is a list with extensions for google chrome which help you block tracking and ads, and help you protect your privacy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Stopping fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication error and other errors in fail2ban on ubuntu 9.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to stop fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication errors on Ubuntu 9.04.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Introduction to DokuWiki</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dokuwiki_Overview.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dokuwiki_Overview.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Introduction to Markdown</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Markdown_Introduction_Tutorial_Overview.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Markdown_Introduction_Tutorial_Overview.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Tether your Sonim XP3 phone with Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tether-your-sonim-xp3-phone-with-linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tether-your-sonim-xp3-phone-with-linux.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how tot tether your sonim xp3 phone with (arch) linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Switch To The Command Line - Part 3.1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Switch-to-the-command-line-part-3.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Switch-to-the-command-line-part-3.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers the following linux command line programs: the cone email client</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>What to do if you cannot execute CHMOD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/What-to-do-if-you-cannot-execute-chmod.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/What-to-do-if-you-cannot-execute-chmod.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to execute chmod when you have screwed up the permissions of chmod.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Switch To The Command Line - Part 2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Switch-to-the-command-line-part-2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Switch-to-the-command-line-part-2.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers the following linux command line programs: snownews and nano. The next part covers screen and cone.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Switch To The Command Line - Part 1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Switch-to-the-command-line-part-1.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Switch-to-the-command-line-part-1.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers the following linux command line programs: elinks and moc. The next part covers Snownews and Vim</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Customize your Clonezilla Live CD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Customize-your-clonezilla-live-CD.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Customize-your-clonezilla-live-CD.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Debian packages clean up commands</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Debian-apt-get-dpkg-packages-cleanup-commands.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Debian-apt-get-dpkg-packages-cleanup-commands.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>EasyConverter</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Easyconverter.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Easyconverter.html</guid>
                <description>Zenity wrapper around ffmpeg to convert media files</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSHdialog</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html</guid>
                <description>SSHdialog - Small command line SSH helper</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clonezilla Backup Script v0.2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Clonezilla-custom-backup-script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Clonezilla-custom-backup-script.html</guid>
                <description>Clonezilla is wonderfull software. At work we use it daily to image laptops. We have a windows PC with a big hard drive, which is shared via samba. Because we image an average of 10 laptops every morning, I decided to customize the script. So together with a colleague we made a script which automatically grabs our latest image from the share and restores it. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Postfix: log message from, to and subject</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Postfix_Log_message_from_to_and_subject_headers.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Postfix_Log_message_from_to_and_subject_headers.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up postfix to log email subject and other headers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSH: Key and user restrictions</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH-Key-Restrictions.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH-Key-Restrictions.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will help you set restrictions for specific ssh keys and users. For example, how to allow only tunneling and how to restrict port forwards.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash script for massive rename to numbers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html</guid>
                <description>Older snippet which was used for dynamic wallpaper switching.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Javascript tricks</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Javascript-tricks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Javascript-tricks.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Convert FLV's to MP3</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html</guid>
                <description>Bash snippet to convert all .flv files to .mp3.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Setting up Motion with FTP and Email! support</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Setting-up-motion-with-ftp-and-email-support.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Setting-up-motion-with-ftp-and-email-support.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash ja/nee keuze</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html</guid>
                <description>Dutch snippet on adding a yes/no choice in a bash script</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Imagemagick thumbnailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html</guid>
                <description>Create some nice thumbnails with Imagemagick</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set your IP as wallpaper</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set-your-ip-as-wallpaper.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set-your-ip-as-wallpaper.html</guid>
                <description>This older tutorial shows you how to set your IP address as wallpaper.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Vim Cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Vim_Cheatsheet.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Vim_Cheatsheet.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Contact</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/static/Contact.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/static/Contact.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Terrible Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Terrible-Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Terrible-Linux.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Disclaimer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/static/Disclaimer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/static/Disclaimer.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    