<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag ab on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/ab.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag ab on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/ab.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Distributed load testing with Tsung</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Basic_Website_load_testing_with_Tsung.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Basic_Website_load_testing_with_Tsung.html</guid>
                <description>At $dayjob I manage a large OpenStack Cloud. Next to that I also build high-performance and redundant clusters for customers. Think multiple datacenters, haproxy, galera or postgres or mysql replication, drbd with nfs or glusterfs and all sorts of software that can (and sometimes cannot) be clustered (redis, rabbitmq etc.). Our customers deploy their application on there and when one or a few components fail, their application stays up. Hypervisors, disks, switches, routers, all can fail without actual service downtime. Next to building such clusters, we also monitor and manage them. When we build such a cluster (fully automated with Ansible) we do a basic load test. We do this not for benchmarking or application flow testing, but to optimize the cluster components. Simple things like the mpm workers or threads in Apache or more advanced topics like MySQL or DRBD. Optimization there depends on the specifications of the servers used and the load patterns. Tsung is a high-performance but simple to configure and use piece of software written in Erlang. Configuration is done in a simple readable XML file. Tsung can be run distributed as well for large setups. It has good reporting and a live web interface for status and reports during a test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    