<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag adventure on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/adventure.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag adventure on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/adventure.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Toggling in a simple program DEC PDP-8 and PiDP-8 using the switch register</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Toggling_in_a_simple_program_on_the_DEC_PDP-8_and_PiDP-8_using_the_switch_register.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Toggling_in_a_simple_program_on_the_DEC_PDP-8_and_PiDP-8_using_the_switch_register.html</guid>
                <description>In this guide I'll show you how to toggle in a simple program on the DEC PDP-8 or the PiDP-8, or in a front-panel simulator named BlinkenBone if you lack the hardware. I have a replica of the PDP-8/I (the PiDP-8) but lacked the actual knowledge on the front panel and switches to get started and do something cool. This guide has step by step instructons, with pictures, and basic explanation. After all, what is an expensive blinking light panel without fun stuff to toggle in?</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Running TSS/8 on the DEC PiDP-8/i and SIMH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_TSS_8_on_the_DEC_PiDP-8_i_and_SIMH.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_TSS_8_on_the_DEC_PiDP-8_i_and_SIMH.html</guid>
                <description>In this guide I'll show you how run the TSS/8 operating system on the PiDP replica by Oscar Vermeulen, and on SIMH on any other computer. I'll also cover a few basic commands like the editor, user management and system information. TSS-8 was a little time-sharing operating system  released in 1968 and requires a minimum of 12K words of memory and a swapping device; on a 24K word machine, it supports up to 17 users. Each user gets a virtual 4K PDP-8; many of the utilities users ran on these virtual machines were only slightly modified versions of utilities from the Disk Monitor System or paper-tape environments. Internally, TSS-8 consists of RMON, the resident monitor, DMON, the disk monitor (file system), and KMON, the keyboard monitor (command shell). BASIC was well supported, while restricted (4K) versions of FORTRAN D and Algol were available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Running Adventure on the DEC PDP-8 with SIMH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_ADVENT-on-the-PDP-8-with-SIMH.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_ADVENT-on-the-PDP-8-with-SIMH.html</guid>
                <description>In this guide I'll show you how run the classic Colossal Cave Adventure game on a PDP-8, emulated by the SIMH emulator. The PDP-8 was an 12 bit minicomputer made in 1964 by DEC, the Digital Equipment Corporation. We will install and set up SIMH, the emulator with a RK05 diskimage running OS/8. We will use FORTRAN on OS/8 to load ADVENTURE, then we use our brain to play the game. As a bonus, I also show you how to edit files using EDIT, and show you a bit of the OS/8 system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    