<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag allwinner on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/allwinner.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag allwinner on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/allwinner.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 mainline 4.0.0 kernel, u-boot and debian rootfs image building tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_A20_Lime2_Kernel_3.19_uBoot_Debian_7_image_building.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_A20_Lime2_Kernel_3.19_uBoot_Debian_7_image_building.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 45, and has 160 GPIO pins. This is a guide to build a linux image with Debian and the mainline 4.0.0 kernel for the Olimex A20-Lime2 board, from scratch. By default it comes with an 3.4 kernel with binary blobs and patches from Allwinner. Recently the mainline kernel has gained support for these boards, you can now run and use the mainline kernel without these awfull non-free binary blobs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 Minimal Debian 7 Image</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A20-OLinuXino-LIME2_minimal_debian_7_image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A20-OLinuXino-LIME2_minimal_debian_7_image.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 45, and has 160 GPIO pins. The default Debian image from OlimeX is quite huge and bloated, over 2,5 GB, with X and all. I do not want a huge image, so I stripped it down to a 200 MB image with only dhcp and ssh and a few basic tools. It uses about 15 MB of RAM. This image allows you to start with almost nothing and build up only what you need.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino a10 Lime uBoot, Kernel and root image guide</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino _10 Lime_uBoot_Kernel.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino _10 Lime_uBoot_Kernel.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A10 LIME is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 30, and has 160 GPIO. This guide is a cleaned up version of theirs with instructions to build your own kernel and u-boot image on Ubuntu 14.04.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino a10 Lime Minimal Debian 7 Image</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A10-OLinuXino-LIME_minimal_debian_7_image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A10-OLinuXino-LIME_minimal_debian_7_image.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A10 LIME is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 30, and has 160 GPIO. The default Debian image from OlimeX is quite huge and bloated, over 2 GB, with X and all. I do not want a huge image, so I stripped it down to a 200 MB image with only dhcp and ssh and a few basic tools. It uses about 20 MB of RAM. This image allows you to start with almost nothing and build up only what you need.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Small low cost linux pc's, an overview from 11-2012</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_PCs.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_PCs.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of small linux computers, mostly ARM based.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    