<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag alpha on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/alpha.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag alpha on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/alpha.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86, Getting Started part 1, install guide with VirtualBox</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS on x86 is now available for hobbyists! Almost a year after [the official release](/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html). This is a part 1 of my getting started guide, showing you how to install OpenVMS on VirtualBox on Windows 10/11. More parts will follow, documenting license installation, network setup, ssh, application installation etc.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86 is finally available for hobbyists!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_is_finally_available_for_hobbyists.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_is_finally_available_for_hobbyists.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS x86 is now available for (most) hobbyists! Almost a year after [the official release](/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html) most hobbyists can now login to the [Service Portal](https://sp.vmssoftware.com) to download their copy of OpenVMS 9.2 for x86, `X86E921OE.ZIP` and the PAK (license) files (`x86community-20240401.zip`), valid until April 2024. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 23:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 23:59:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86 will be released tomorrow (2022-07-14), so exciting!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html</guid>
                <description>On July 8th, a few days ago, I saw the following post on the VMS Software Inc (VSI) blog, titled 'Release of OpenVMS V9.2 for x86 Scheduled for July 14, 2022'. That is tomorrow! I'm so excited, I can't wait to start playing around with it. This short post goes over the announcement and the status of the community license, and hopes to make you just as enthusiastic as I am for the coming release!</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:27:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install NetBSD 9.2 on a DEC Alpha CPU with AXPBox</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/NetBSD_Alpha_AXPbox.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/NetBSD_Alpha_AXPbox.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing and running NetBSD 9.2 for the DEC Alpha CPU architecture on AXPbox, the open source Alpha Emulator. I recently wrote an article on how to install NetBSD in QEMU for Alpha and since I'm involved with the AXPbox project this article was just a matter of time. This guide shows you how to compile AXPbox and install NetBSD 9.2. It also shows you how to install packages without networking available and includes `openssl` and `sysbench` benchmarks, which we compare to NetBSD running inside QEMU.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install NetBSD 9.2 on a DEC Alpha CPU in QEMU with X11</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/NetBSD_on_QEMU_Alpha.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/NetBSD_on_QEMU_Alpha.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing and running NetBSD 9.2 for the DEC Alpha CPU architecture in QEMU, including a GUI (X11 via VNC). It requires you to patch and compile QEMU yourself. It was never possible, until now, to run an actual operating system easily with QEMU Alpha, so this is amazing! It is very cool that Jason Thorpe is putting in so much effort on the QEMU side, as all but one patch is upstream already. Alpha emulation has always been a niche of a niche, so seeing this improve in QEMU is wonderful. OpenVMS does not boot yet since many more things are missing on the QEMU side, but who knows what the future might bring? Maybe even Windows NT for Alpha will boot on QEMU one day?</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Reset the SYSTEM password on OpenVMS 8.4</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_reset_SYSTEM-password.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_reset_SYSTEM-password.html</guid>
                <description>This short post shows you how to reset the SYSTEM account password on a single OpenVMS 8.4 ALpha machine via the serial console. You need physical access to the machine and the procedure looks a lot like linux and appending `init=/bin/bash` to the GRUB commandline to boot into single user mode. It is tested on the AXPbox Alpha emulator, I forgot my password after not using it for a month.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS CDE Desktop Remote X session GUI (on AXPbox)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html</guid>
                <description>Last year November, I posted on a new OpenVMS related project, AXPbox, the open source Alpha emulator, a fork of es40 by Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron; Glozar. Last week I put together the first official release of AXPbox, one of the changes being in the network code, making it more stable, thus being able to run a remote X session. Meaning, you can run the CDE desktop and enjoy everything the OpenVMS GUI has to offer. This article shows you how to run the CDE GUI in a remote X session, including switching between the old Motif look and the new DECWindows and how to run Tetris.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>AXPbox version 1.0.0 released! (Open source Alpha emulator)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/AXPBox-version-1.0.0-released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/AXPBox-version-1.0.0-released.html</guid>
                <description>Last year November, I posted on a new OpenVMS related project, AXPbox, the open source Alpha emulator, a fork of es40 by Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron; Glozar. I got involved a bit in the project, submitting a few patches here and there, editing the Wiki and thus now have contributer rights on the github repository. After discussing a bit back and forth with Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron;, I put together the first official release of AXPbox, very exciting news. The release can be found here on github. This article has the release notes and a bunch of screenshots of OpenVMS inside AXPbox running GUI applications over the network.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing OpenVMS 8.4 Alpha inside AXPbox on Debian 10 / Ubuntu 20.04 with networking</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Installing_OpenVMS_8.4_Alpha_in_AXPbox_with_networking.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Installing_OpenVMS_8.4_Alpha_in_AXPbox_with_networking.html</guid>
                <description>In my previous article I announced the fork of the `es40` emulator to `AXPbox` by Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron; including bug fixes and rework allowing it to install OpenVMS 8.4 without problems. Since then I've contributed a few patches and doc updates, now NetBSD boots as well (the patches for netbsd were from other es40 forks). I've also looked into getting networking setup, since that is a bit of a tedious process due to pcap and linux, pcap being used for network emulation. SIMH (among others, a great VAX emulator) suffers from the same problems with networking. This guide will show you how to install AXPbox and get OpenVMS 8.4 ready and running with networking inside AXPbox. It's a rather long guide with a lot of information and output.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exciting OpenVMS Alpha Emulation news, es40 has been forked to Axpbox (and works!)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Exciting_OpenVMS_Alpha_emulation_news_es40_has_been_forked_to_axpbox.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Exciting_OpenVMS_Alpha_emulation_news_es40_has_been_forked_to_axpbox.html</guid>
                <description>Back in 2018 I was playing around with OpenVMS a lot, as it continues on the legacy of the PDP-8 and PDP-11. OpenVMS 7.3 on the VAX emulated via SIMH runs perfectly, OpenVMS 8.4 for Alpha was kind of a disaster, or, the es40 emulator was. Real hardware is available via IslandCo, but shipping to the Netherlands is horribly expensive.
The only options back then for emulation of Alpha were FreeAXP or AlphaVM, both paid, closed sourced products with watered down free versions. Nothing wrong with that, it enables us to play around, and now that OpenVMS is in the hands of VMS Software with an x86 port coming along we may hope for a bright future ahead for OpenVMS. VSI currently provides a hobbyist version, but it's a FreeAXP bundle for Windows only.
Recently I got an email from Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron; regarding his fork of the es40 emulator, axpbox. This short post is intended to give this emulator more visibility and exposure, since I find this to be amazingly cool and exciting. It lists the bugs fixed and new features, which allow OpenVMS 8.3 and 8.4 to install perfectly.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Multiple passwords for one user, UIC uniqueness and the system password on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Multiple_passwords_for_one_user_UIC_uniqueness_and_the_system_password_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Multiple_passwords_for_one_user_UIC_uniqueness_and_the_system_password_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>In the book I bought about OpenVMS for the previous post on filesystems, 'Getting Started with OpenVMS by M. Duffy', I've read a few interesting things in the chapter that introduces user accounts and system login. Namely that a user can have multiple passwords, that user ID's are not unique and that there can be a system password. This article goes in to those three topics.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Mount ISO and execute scripts on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_Mount_ISO_and_execute_scripts.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_Mount_ISO_and_execute_scripts.html</guid>
                <description>I'm playing around with OpenVMS on Alpha using a trial of AlphaVM Basic, but was not able to copy paste in my Hobbyist License. I suspect Putty pasting too quickly, so I had to get the license script on the OpenVMS, without using the network. In this article you'll learn some OpenVMS filesystem history, how OpenVMS handles line endings and in the end I get my license installed by creating an ISO with the script on it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>File locking, grep and process killing on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/File_locking_grep_and_process_killing_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/File_locking_grep_and_process_killing_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>On the DECUS OpenVMS system there is no curl or wget installed. I wanted to download a remote `C` file to play around with the compiler and some simple Hello World code, to get a feel of the build system. After a bit of searching around the internet I was not able to find a command like curl or wget to download a remote file. But, the searches led me to the OpenVMS port of curl, which, I hoped, might be able to run on the DECUS system. Just like on a linux system, running the binary under my user account, not install it system wide. This ended up to be another adventure in which I figured out how to trace a locked file to a process, grep the output of a process on OpenVMS and kill a process. I did not get curl to work or compile my code, yet.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>The sad state of Alpha emulators (for OpenVMS)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_sad_state_of_Alpha_emulators_for_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_sad_state_of_Alpha_emulators_for_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS 7.3 was the last version for the VAX architecture. All later versions (like 8.4) are only available for the Alpha CPU architecture or Intel's Itanium platform. Since I don't want hardware running, which is suprisingly hard to get in The Netherlands, Alpha machines, I want to be able to run it in an emulator. simh is the best open source VAX emulator, but it does not support Alpha. My adventure with es40, the only open source Alpha emulator (development halted 10 years ago) ended prematurely since it crashes all the time. The only other available options are FreeAXP, Charon-AXP, vtAlpha and EmuVM AlphaVM. Only FreeAXP is available as a free (but not open source) download, Charon had a personal version but that is nowhere to be found nowdays, vtAlpha doesn't offer a trial or free version and EmuVM Alphaserver also stopped with their free version. In this article I'll go over my adventure with FreeAXP and EmuVM.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing the es40 AlphaServer emulator 0.18 on Ubuntu 16.04, and trying to install OpenVMS 8.4 on es40</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Installing_the_es40_AlphaServer_emulator_0.18_on_Ubuntu_16.04_and_trying_to_install_openVMS_8.4_on_es40.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Installing_the_es40_AlphaServer_emulator_0.18_on_Ubuntu_16.04_and_trying_to_install_openVMS_8.4_on_es40.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS 7.3 is the latest version of OpenVMS for the VAX architecture. Since the DECUS system uses OpenVMS 8.4 there were some version differences. I could not set my 'BACKSPACE=DELETE' on 7.3. The hobbyist license also covers the Alpha and Itanium versions of OpenVMS so I want to try the Alpha version, which is consequently also 8.4, the latest release. This article describes my attempt to compile and install the es40 open source Alpha emulator on Ubuntu 16.04 and subsequently the installation of OpenVMS Alpha. The emulator is not under active development since 2008, and the installation of OpenVMS fails. OpenVMS does boot however, very very slowly. </description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Small OpenVMS titbits</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Small_OpenVMS_titbits.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Small_OpenVMS_titbits.html</guid>
                <description>Here are some small titbits I found out this week on the DECUServe OpenVMS system. Not enough to write a blogpost on their own, but collected together.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 7.3 install log with simh VAX on Ubuntu 16.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_7.3_install_log_with_simh_vax_on_Ubuntu_16.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_7.3_install_log_with_simh_vax_on_Ubuntu_16.04.html</guid>
                <description>Using a guide I was able to install OpenVMS 7.3 for VAX on simh on Ubuntu 16.04. This is a copy-paste of my terminal for future reference. This is not one of my usual articles, a guide with comprehensive information an background. Just a log of my terminal.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>File versioning and deleting on OpenVMS with DELETE and PURGE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/File_versioning_and_deleting_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/File_versioning_and_deleting_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>I'm now a few weeks into my OpenVMS adventure and my home folder on the [DECUS](http://decus.org) system is quite cluttered with files. More specifically, with different versions of files, since OpenVMS by default has file versioning built in. This means that when you edit a file, or copy a file over an existing file, the old file is not overwritten but a new file with a new version is written. The old file still is there. This is one of the best things in my humble opinion so far on OpenVMS, but it does require maintenance to not have the disk get filled up fast. This article goes into the PURGE and DELETE commands which help you deal with file versioning and removal.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Backspace and delete key behaviour on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Backspace_and_delete_key_behaviour_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Backspace_and_delete_key_behaviour_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>While working on the DECUServe OpenVMS system I found out quickly that pressing BACKSPACE moves the cursor on the shell to the beginning of the line instead of deleting the character to the left of the cursor. This made me very aware of my typing, since when I made an error I had to retype the entire line (the terminal is in insert mode it seems). After reading through some documentation it seems that is default behaviour but there are terminal options to change it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSH public key authentication on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/SSH_public_key_authentication_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/SSH_public_key_authentication_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>My OpenVMS adventure continues, after my rabbit hole of folder removal, this time I actually get public key authentication working with OpenSSH so that I don't have to type my password to login.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Delete a directory on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Delete_a_directory_in_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Delete_a_directory_in_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>My OpenVMS adventure continues, in this small item I talk about the removal of folders on OpenVMS. As you might expect, different than on linux. This rabbit hole got started when I made a typo in the creation of a folder, which I created in the process of SSH public key authentication. Pubkey auth still doens't work but my OpenVMS knowledge increased.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Mail on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_second_OpenVMS_-_MAIL.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_second_OpenVMS_-_MAIL.html</guid>
                <description>Last week I registered myself with the DECUServe OpenVMS system. I found out how to navigate the filesystem and create files and folders, it was awesome. This week I learned how to use the OpenVMS MAIL program to read and reply to an email I got from George Cornelius, another user on the DECUServe system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My first OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_first_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_first_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>Last week I registered myself with the DECUServe OpenVMS system. I also registered with HP as an OpenVMS hobbyist and got OpenVMS 7.3 for VAX. This small blog item describes my first steps with the hosted DECUS OpenVMS system. I'm excited since I now know how to create folders, navigate the filesystem and edit files. Oh and I had a nice chat with another OpenVMS user via the PHONE program. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    