<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag android on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/android.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag android on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/android.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>A docker image for Qt 5.15 LTS for Android, including OpenSSL and the KDE patch collection</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15_LTS_Docker_Image_for_Android_with_OpenSSL.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15_LTS_Docker_Image_for_Android_with_OpenSSL.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I got an email from Google regarding the API level of [Leaf Node Monitoring](https://leafnode.nl), my open source monitoring app for Windows, Linux and Android. The Play Store version must be updated to target API level 33.
For Windows and Linux I'm building the app automatically in a CI environment but the Android build was still a manual process. Until now, because after a bunch of messing around with Android NDK versions, OpenSSL library paths and Qt compile flags I can automatically build Leaf Node Monitoring in my CI.

I'm using Woodpecker CI and that requires every build step to be executed in a Docker image. There are a few Qt docker images floating around but they are all using the pre-built 5.15.2 version by extracting it from the Qt Online Installer. That version is quite old, 5.15.15 LTS was released [a few days ago for Commercial License Holders](http://web.archive.org/web/20230902132649/https://www.qt.io/blog/commercial-lts-qt-5.15.15-released) on August 31, so after 1 year it will become available as open source.
My docker image builds Qt from source using the `5.15 KDE Qt Patch Collection` branch for Android and it includes OpenSSL. This is as far as I know the most up to date docker image for Qt 5.15, currently at 5.15.10 LTS.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2023.01 released, major performance improvements, new layout and new checks!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2023.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2023.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include a responsive and adjustable layout, massive performance improvements and a new check type, allowing you to execute external processes, for example, the nagios/monitoring plugins. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Responsive Qt/QML layout coming to Leaf Node Monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Responsive_Qt_QML_Layout_coming_to_Leaf_Node_Monitoring.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Responsive_Qt_QML_Layout_coming_to_Leaf_Node_Monitoring.html</guid>
                <description>[Leaf Node Monitoring](https://leafnode.nl) is my own open source (GPLv3), paid, network monitoring program for Windows, Linux &amp; Android. Written in C++ &amp; Qt 5. Perfect to run on your desktop and monitor your servers. Simple setup, auto-detects running services, runs checks concurrently and alerting. This post shows another upcoming feature in the next version, responsive layouting to more effectively use screen real estate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>What's coming in the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Whats_coming_in_leaf_node_monitoring_v2022_02.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Whats_coming_in_leaf_node_monitoring_v2022_02.html</guid>
                <description>Leaf Node Monitoring is my own open source (GPLv3), paid, network monitoring program for Windows, Linux &amp; Android. Written in C++ &amp; Qt 5. Perfect to run on your desktop and monitor your servers. Simple setup, auto-detects running services, runs checks concurrently, open port scanning and alerting. I've recently released the first version, and this post goes over the features that will come in the next release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Selling my own GPL software part 3, prior art (existing GPL software for sale)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Existing_GPL_software_for_sale.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Existing_GPL_software_for_sale.html</guid>
                <description>In my earlier posts I described the hurdles I faced with my plan to [sell my own](/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html) GPL software and I described how to [embed the source code directly inside the app] (/s/articles/Embed_the_source_code_directly_in_your_Qt_app.html) (for mobile platforms). This post looks at a few other projects that sell GPL software and it's a bit of a progress update regarding my plans and software.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Selling my own GPL software, part 1: a lot of hurdles</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html</guid>
                <description>For as long as I can remember I've got this dream of a passive income software project. At first I thought of it as a hosted service, probably something monitoring related, or high-available cloud hosting-ish. That's the kind of stuff a sysadmin dreams of.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now that I'm a developer for a couple of years, exposed to a few different languages, design patterns and software architectures, that idea is still lingering around, but no longer focused on a hosted piece of software. The web is just too fast paced, bloated and way too much work compared to a piece of cross platform software.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In my spare time I've been chugging along on a piece of software, which I'm contemplating selling. In my case the commercial aspect is made more difficult because I also want to release the software with a GPL license.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This post describes the initial hurdles I'm encountering, next to just programming the software.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Run CLion native on Android, ditch your desktop!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Run_CLion_on_Android.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Run_CLion_on_Android.html</guid>
                <description>How often do you read articles that state that people have replaced their main computer with an iPad and are fully content? Now, how many of those articles just use a linux server (vps) somewhere with some native apps, but mostly SSH to that server? Well, what if I told you that you can run a full blown IDE, the best IDE for C++ there is, CLion by JetBrains, on Android? Including compiling, just native GCC, CMake, GDB and all the stuff you are used to? Just for fun I've installed CLion on an old Samsung Tab S2 I had lying around, using Ubuntu in a chroot. It works way better than I'd expected, with a Bluetooth keyboard and mouse it's almost as if your on a desktop. I wonder if you could run Android Studio and use the tablet to compile app's for itself. This article shows some photo's, including a mechanical keyboard, different window managers and had instructions to replicate this setup.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My phone serves me 400+ ads and trackers per hour. Blokada, the best android adblocker, beats 'm all!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_phone_serves_me_400_ads_per_hour_blokada_blocks_beats_them_all.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_phone_serves_me_400_ads_per_hour_blokada_blocks_beats_them_all.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I switched to a new phone. After a few years (!) my old phone stopped receiving calls making it time for a new one. The new phone has Android, which allowed me to install a system wide adblocker, Blokada. It works by posing itself as a local VPN, filtering advertisements, trackers and all kinds of nasty things that spy on you or bring in malware. It does not require root access on Android, it's open source and best of all, it works very well. In the first three days of usage it has blocked over 5000 ads and trackers, including 400 when I was asleep.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    