<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag apple on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/apple.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag apple on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/apple.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 50, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_50_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_50_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 50 of 2015, covering open source and sysadmin related stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a $35 Time Capsule - Raspberry Pi Time Machine Backup Server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple guide on building a $35 Time Capsule with a Raspberry Pi. A Time Capsule is a network attached storage device from Apple for use with their Time Machine. Time Machine gives users a very easy and userfriendly way to automatically create and restore (encrypted) backups. A Time Capsule is basically an expensive NAS that only talks the AFP/netatalk protocol. The 2 TB version costs $299 at this time, a Raspberry Pi only $35. </description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Remove all Apple Remote Dekstop settings</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Remove_all_Apple_Remote_Desktop_settings.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Remove_all_Apple_Remote_Desktop_settings.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to remove all Apple Remote Desktop settings. My ARD installation recently stopped working correctly, having problems discovering new machines and connecting to already set up machines. These commands wipe all settings and the ARD installation is clean again. This solved my problem.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Enable access for assistive devices via the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Enable-Access-for-assistive-devices-via-command-line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Enable-Access-for-assistive-devices-via-command-line.html</guid>
                <description>This command enables access for assistive devices on Apple OS X machines via the command line. This is needed for software like SpectacleApp or SizeUp. This article has methods for OS X Mavericks 10.9 as for 10.8 and 10.7</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Applescript to lock date and time preference panel to fix local sudo exploit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS-X-Applescript-To-Lock-Date-Time-Settings-Panel-for-Sudo-Exploit.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS-X-Applescript-To-Lock-Date-Time-Settings-Panel-for-Sudo-Exploit.html</guid>
                <description>This applescript locks the OS X Date and Time Preference Panel. It can be run via Apple Remote Desktop. This is related to CVE-2013-1775, a local sudo root exploit on OS X. If the date and time preference panel is locked, setting the date and time also requires a sudo password</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Disable Notification Center</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Disable_Notification_Centre.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Disable_Notification_Centre.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to disable the OS X Notification Center completely, the menu item and the sidebar. It also gives you the command to enable it again.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Turn Bonjour off or on via the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet switches off Bonjour on OS X via the command line or Apple Remote Desktop. This is useful when you want to disable iChat or Messages chatting on the local network. Bonjour is Apple's implementation of Zero configuration networking (Zeroconf), a group of technologies that includes service discovery, address assignment, and hostname resolution. Bonjour locates devices such as printers, other computers, and the services that those devices offer on a local network using multicast Domain Name System (mDNS) service records.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Turn off sleep from the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_off_sleep_from_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_off_sleep_from_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet turns off Sleep on an OS X machine, either iMac or Macbook. Normally when a Mac is not used it goes in sleep mode, this turns that off.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Create Hardware report SPX and save it to a AFP share</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS_X_Create_Hardware_report_spx_and_save_it_to_a_AFP_share.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OS_X_Create_Hardware_report_spx_and_save_it_to_a_AFP_share.html</guid>
                <description>This script creates a OS X hardware report (an SPX file) and saves it to a AFP share. This is usefull when you are rolling out new machines. Run this script via Apple Remote Desktop and you have all your administration in your AFP share, which you can later put in your CMDB. The report has all the hardware data, from firmware, serial number, model, MAC addresses, disk and memory information, in short everything you need for your CMDB and support contracts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Turn firewall on or off from the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_-_Turn_firewall_on_or_off_from_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_-_Turn_firewall_on_or_off_from_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This command lets you turn the build in OS X firewall on and off, on both for specific services or essential services. It works with OS X 10.5, 10.6, 10.7 and 10.8.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Join Mac OS X to an Active Directory / OpenDLAP directory from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet joins an Mac OS X computer to a Windows Active Directory or OpenLDAP Directory domain from the Command Line or via Apple Remote Desktop.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Resize OS X Mountain Lion installer to fit on a single layer 4.7 GB DVD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OS-X-Mountain_Lion_iso_resize_to_fit_on_a_single_layer_dvd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OS-X-Mountain_Lion_iso_resize_to_fit_on_a_single_layer_dvd.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you resize the OS X Mountain Lion InstallESD.dmg file to fit on a single layer DVD. The normal .dmg file will give an error that it is to big for a single layer DVD. The install works fine afterwards, the .dmg file just has a defined size of 4.75 GB. Resizing it via the Disk Utility will not work because it is a read only dmg image.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set OS X hostname from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Change-Hostname.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Change-Hostname.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet helps you change the hostname of a computer running OS X. OS X defines the hostname/computer name in three places and you need to change all of them.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    