<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag apt on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/apt.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag apt on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/apt.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 53, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_53_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_53_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 53 of 2015, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do action if on specific distribution (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS or RHEL) or distribution version (ubuntu precise, ubuntu trusty)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if you are on a certain distribution. You might have a mixed environment with CentOS and Debian and when using Ansible to execute actions on nodes you don't need to run Yum on Debian, or Apt on CentOS. Some package names are different and such, so this helps you with an only if statement to select a specific distribution. As a bonus, you also get an only_if for specific distribution versions, like Ubuntu precise (12.04 LTS) or Ubuntu trusty (14.04 LTS).</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do something if another action changed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how execute actions only if another action has changed. For example, a playbook which downloads a remote key for package signing but only executes the apt-add command if the key has changed. Or a playbook which clones a git repository and only restarts a service if the git repository has changed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Sudo sometimes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how run some actions via sudo and some not. It also shows you how to run an entire role via sudo or not.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Silent unatended apt-get upgrade</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Silent-automatic-apt-get-upgrade.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Silent-automatic-apt-get-upgrade.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to setup completely silent apt-get upgrade via cron. It also defaults to not overwriting config files if a package has a newer version.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ubuntu/Debian update mailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</guid>
                <description>This is a bash script for Ubuntu and Debian, to be run by cron on a set interval. It checks if there are apt-updates, and if so, mails an overview of the packages which can be updated, whith their local version, the version available and an URL to the Ubuntu package site where you can see the changelog. I wrote this as an addition for my Nagios monitoring, that only shows how many updates there are, this is a lot more verbose. It also runs on Debian since 1 Nov 2012. Only the links don't work then, because the packages are different.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a local Ubuntu (apt) repository with apt-mirror</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_local_Ubuntu_debian_apt_mirror.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_local_Ubuntu_debian_apt_mirror.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to setup your own debian/ubuntu package repository with apt-mirror.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    