<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag arch on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/arch.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag arch on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/arch.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a Flexible and Powerful System with Arch Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Build_a_Flexible_and_Powerful_System_with_Arch_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Build_a_Flexible_and_Powerful_System_with_Arch_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers the basic installation and configuration of Arch Linux, the distro that adheres to the Keep It Simple, Stupid principle. Arch Linux is a rolling release, that means that you always have the latest and greatest software. With Arch, you're on your own. In a world where where technology is taking your personal responsibility and giving it to the cloud, or to an internet search filter or the device manufacturers, getting your hands dirty with an operating system can be a revelation. Not only will you learn a great deal about how Linux works and what holds the whole thing together, you'll get a system you understand from the inside-out, and one that can be instantly upgraded to all the latest packages. You may also learn something about yourself in the process. And despite its reputation, it's not that difficult.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Arch Linux AUR PKGBUILD generate new checksums</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch_Linux_AUR_PKGBUILD_generate_new_checksums.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch_Linux_AUR_PKGBUILD_generate_new_checksums.html</guid>
                <description>The AUR is a nice feature from Arch Linux, it allows anyone to create and upload a simple package build script, PKGBUILD, for a piece of software which is not in the repositories. Sometimes however, the PKGBUILD is outdated. You then need to manually fix it, by changing the download link or version. With a new version you get new checksums, and the makepkg command has a neat feature which generates the checksums for you.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Arch Linux on a Raspberry Pi with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_a_Raspberry_Pi_with_Arch_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_a_Raspberry_Pi_with_Arch_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Arch Linux on a Raspberry Pi using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a $35 Time Capsule - Raspberry Pi Time Machine Backup Server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple guide on building a $35 Time Capsule with a Raspberry Pi. A Time Capsule is a network attached storage device from Apple for use with their Time Machine. Time Machine gives users a very easy and userfriendly way to automatically create and restore (encrypted) backups. A Time Capsule is basically an expensive NAS that only talks the AFP/netatalk protocol. The 2 TB version costs $299 at this time, a Raspberry Pi only $35. </description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPv6 at Home</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/IPv6_at_Home.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/IPv6_at_Home.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's was running a test setup of the Citadel groupware service. The test was sucessfull, so I set up a real world setup. The Raspberry Pi would serve another purpose, namely, a Linux Torrent seedbox. As in, to seed Linux torrents from linuxtracker.org. I choose Transmission for this, because it is simple, fast and stable. Transmission has a good webinterface, plus it allows access from remote clients with the transmission-remote gui packages. This article shows you how to set it up on a Raspberry Pi running Arch Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Transmission Web on a Raspberry Pi with Arch Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's was running a test setup of the Citadel groupware service. The test was sucessfull, so I set up a real world setup. The Raspberry Pi would serve another purpose, namely, a Linux Torrent seedbox. As in, to seed Linux torrents from linuxtracker.org. I choose Transmission for this, because it is simple, fast and stable. Transmission has a good webinterface, plus it allows access from remote clients with the transmission-remote gui packages. This article shows you how to set it up on a Raspberry Pi running Arch Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>rc.local support on Arch Linux with systemd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/rc.local_support_on_Arch_Linux_and_systemd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/rc.local_support_on_Arch_Linux_and_systemd.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple tutorial on how to get /etc/rc.local support back in Arch Linux or any distro with systemd. Arch Linux uses systemd. Therefore, init functions like rc.local are not supported anymore. This systemd service allows you to have support for `/etc/rc.local`.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My Todo.txt Workflow, including Unison, Todour and Android</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/My_Todo.txt_Workflow.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/My_Todo.txt_Workflow.html</guid>
                <description>Todo.txt is a way to manage your tasks/todo items in a plaintext format. It has a few simple rules, there are a lot of applications to work with it, but in its core it is a plaintext file, so a text editor is sufficient to use it. Recently I started using todo.txt, including syncing on all my devices via my own servers. This article shows you my workflow, and how to set up a similar environment, including ssh, unison, todour for OS X, DayTasks for Ubuntu and Simpletasks Cloudless for Android.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Screenfetch installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install screenfetch, a bash information tool. It displays handy system information at login, including distro name, kernel, uptime, cpu, ram and nice distro-based artwork. The tutorial includes support for bash and zsh, for every supported linux OS (ubuntu, centos, arch, redhat, solusOS, linux mint and more.)</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Some Bash and Arch Tweaks </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    