<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag arm on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/arm.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag arm on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/arm.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Using nodeSelector to deploy a Kubernetes Helm chart only on x86/amd64 nodes, not arm64</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Using_nodeSelector_to_deploy_a_Kubernetes_Helm_chart_only_on_x86_or_amd64_nodes_not_arm64.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Using_nodeSelector_to_deploy_a_Kubernetes_Helm_chart_only_on_x86_or_amd64_nodes_not_arm64.html</guid>
                <description>My [k3s cluster](/s/tutorials/My_First_Kubernetes_k3s_cluster_on_3_Orange_Pi_Zero_3s_including_k8s_dashboard_hello-node_and_failover.html) runs on Orange Pi Zero 3 small board computers, with a 1.5 GHz Allwinner H618 Quad-Core Cortex-A53 ARM64 CPU. Nowadays most popular software has support for `aarch64` due to the popularity of boards like the Raspberry Pi and the Apple M1 series processors, but smaller projects or niche software often can only run on x86/amd64. If you write your own yaml files for deployment you can use a `nodeSelector` combined with the `kubernetes.io/arch=amd64`, but with a Helm Chart this is not that obvious. This small snippets shows you the correct syntax to force deploy a Helm Chart to only amd64 nodes in your cluster. This assumes you have a mixed cluster, I added a small virtual machine to it for testing. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:39:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Yocto boot2qt for the Seeed reTerminal (Qt 6)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Yocto_boot2qt_for_the_Seeed_reTerminal_qt6.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Yocto_boot2qt_for_the_Seeed_reTerminal_qt6.html</guid>
                <description>In this guide we'll build a linux distribution for Seeed reTerminal, using the Yocto project and the `boot2qt` stack provided by Qt. This `boot2qt` image can be written to the internal eMMC and when booted up, the Seeed reTerminal runs a software stack that integrates nicely with Qt Creator (the Qt IDE), for example, one click deployment to the device. You can run your own Qt application on the reTerminal, full screen, it will boot right into it.
This guide covers Qt 6.2. The guide also covers changing the default startup app to your own app, Qt Creator integration and rotating your Qt app, both Widgets and QML, the latter via Wayland and Weston.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi Compute Module 4 eMMC flashing issue (nRPI_BOOT)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Raspberry_Pi_Compute_Module_4_eMMC_flashing_issues.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Raspberry_Pi_Compute_Module_4_eMMC_flashing_issues.html</guid>
                <description>I recently got my hands on a Raspberry Pi 4 Compute Module, 4 GB with 32 GB eMMC flash and a Compute Module 4 IO board. Due to the global chip shortage it's hard to find one in stock but I got lucky by checking [rpilocator.com] (https://rpilocator.com/) regularly (thanks to [Jeff Geerling] (https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2022/its-dire-raspberry-pi-availability-tracker-launched) for that site. He's got amazing Raspberry Pi related content next to a bunch of high-quality Ansible playbooks, go give him a visit).
The eMMC edition I have can only be flashed if you put a jumper on a pin on the I/O board (to put the cm4 in a special mode, `nRPI_BOOT`) and use a special tool, [usbboot](https://github.com/raspberrypi/usbboot). [Jeff has a great guide](https://web.archive.org/web/20220226203155/https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2020/how-flash-raspberry-pi-os-compute-module-4-emmc-usbboot) on flashing the cm4 eMMC edition. My `cm4` however, was not showing up whenever I put it in this special flashing mode. This article goes over the troubleshooting I did and the eventual solution (hint: hardware problem).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Execute a script in a Yocto package on every image build</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Execute_a_script_in_a_Yocto_package_on_every_image_build.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Execute_a_script_in_a_Yocto_package_on_every_image_build.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small snippet showing a Yocto recipe that executes a script on every build of an image that includes that recipe. I use it to write the build hosts date/time to a file on the image, but you could do anything you want inside the script.
It's not recommended to do this, for example, if you want to place a binary on your image you should version it correctly. Yocto can build from a git repo, no need to copy binaries. If you include the `buildinfo` class your image or the `os-release` recipe, build info is also written to your image. </description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Yocto boot2qt for the Raspberry Pi 4, both Qt 5.15 and 6.2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Yocto_boot2qt_for_the_Raspberry_Pi_4_both_Qt_6_and_Qt_5.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Yocto_boot2qt_for_the_Raspberry_Pi_4_both_Qt_6_and_Qt_5.html</guid>
                <description>In this guide we'll build a linux distribution for Raspberry Pi 4, using the Yocto project and the `boot2qt` stack provided by Qt. This `boot2qt` image can be written to an SD card and when booted up, the Raspberry Pi runs a software stack that integrates nicely with Qt Creator (the Qt IDE), for example, one click deployment to the device. You can run your own Qt application on the Pi, full screen, it will boot right into it.
This guide covers both Qt 5.15 and Qt 6.2. The 5.15 build process is a bit convoluted due to a few upstream issues. The guide also covers changing the default startup app to your own app and Qt Creator integration.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing Freedombox on Armbian on the Olimex Pioneer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Installing_Freedombox_On_Armbian_On_The_Olimex_A20_Pioneer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Installing_Freedombox_On_Armbian_On_The_Olimex_A20_Pioneer.html</guid>
                <description>FreedomBox is a private server for non-experts: it lets you install and configure server applications with only a few clicks. It runs on cheap hardware of your choice, uses your internet connection and power, and is under your control. Last year the Pioneer became available, officially supported and sanctioned by the Freedombox Foundation. This is a home server you can buy from Olimex, comes in a nice metal case with a proper power supply, network cable, battery and SD card preloaded with Freedombox. Plug in and go. Perfect for users that don't want to tinker but do want their freedom and control. With the Pioneer, both the hardware and software are fully open source. In the default provided distribution for the Pioneer there are a few things I dislike. This guide covers the installation of Freedombox and Debian for the Olimex A20 Lime2 Pioneer with Armbian including reinstalling, Apache SSL certificate and LDAP issues.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get serial port data on the web with live updating</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Get_serial_port_data_on_the_web_with_live_updating.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Get_serial_port_data_on_the_web_with_live_updating.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I was asked to build a test setup to measure the accuracy of a few loadcells (weight sensors) in a frame. Someone other than me would execute the test and required access to the measured data, preferably live and without needing knowledge of ssh or linux. The weight sensors can be read with an openscale board from sparkfun via a serial connection which the board emulates over USB (via an FTDI chip), via that same serial connection you can also calibrate them or change settings like amount of decimals. As a quick solution I created a webpage that uses a small amount of javascript to live update the readings from the board. screen is used to capture the output of the serial connection to a file which the webpage displays and updates. In this article I'll talk about how I put various bits of software together to get the output of the serial connection onto a nice webpage with live updating.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Building opkg .ipk packages by hand (for OpenEmbedded/Yocto/OpenWRT)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Building_IPK_packages_by_hand.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Building_IPK_packages_by_hand.html</guid>
                <description>.ipk packages are used by a variety of embedded linux systems, like routers running OpenWRT and appliances running on OpenEmbedded (Yocto). The opkg command installs these packages and OpenEmbedded comes with a set of tools to build .ipk packages. Recently I had to create ipk packages in a scripted fashion for a few hundred systems, all unique per system. The .ipk packages includes a few software changes for debugging, a systemd service and one precompiled binary. The yocto build tools were not available on the machine where these packages would be made so I had to figure out how to make them by hand, which means, automatically. The packages are actually just compressed files containing a few control files and the data to be extracted on the filesystem. This article will walk you through the steps of creating these packages by hand.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 mainline 4.0.0 kernel, u-boot and debian rootfs image building tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_A20_Lime2_Kernel_3.19_uBoot_Debian_7_image_building.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_A20_Lime2_Kernel_3.19_uBoot_Debian_7_image_building.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 45, and has 160 GPIO pins. This is a guide to build a linux image with Debian and the mainline 4.0.0 kernel for the Olimex A20-Lime2 board, from scratch. By default it comes with an 3.4 kernel with binary blobs and patches from Allwinner. Recently the mainline kernel has gained support for these boards, you can now run and use the mainline kernel without these awfull non-free binary blobs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 Minimal Debian 7 Image</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A20-OLinuXino-LIME2_minimal_debian_7_image.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A20-OLinuXino-LIME2_minimal_debian_7_image.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 45, and has 160 GPIO pins. The default Debian image from OlimeX is quite huge and bloated, over 2,5 GB, with X and all. I do not want a huge image, so I stripped it down to a 200 MB image with only dhcp and ssh and a few basic tools. It uses about 15 MB of RAM. This image allows you to start with almost nothing and build up only what you need.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino a10 Lime uBoot, Kernel and root image guide</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_10_Lime_uBoot_Kernel.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_10_Lime_uBoot_Kernel.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A10 LIME is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 30, and has 160 GPIO. This guide is a cleaned up version of theirs with instructions to build your own kernel and u-boot image on Ubuntu 14.04.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino a10 Lime Minimal Debian 7 Image</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A10-OLinuXino-LIME_minimal_debian_7_image.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A10-OLinuXino-LIME_minimal_debian_7_image.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A10 LIME is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 30, and has 160 GPIO. The default Debian image from OlimeX is quite huge and bloated, over 2 GB, with X and all. I do not want a huge image, so I stripped it down to a 200 MB image with only dhcp and ssh and a few basic tools. It uses about 20 MB of RAM. This image allows you to start with almost nothing and build up only what you need.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up your own truly secure, encrypted and shared file synchronization, aka Dropbox clone</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html</guid>
                <description>This article describes my truly secure, encrypted file synchronization service. It used EncFS and dvcs-autosync which lets me share only the encrypted data and mount that locally to get the plaintext. It works on OS X, Linux and ARM linux. This article has setup instructions for all those platforms.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    