<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag backup on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/backup.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag backup on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/backup.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>The yearly backup restore test</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Yearly_Backup_Restore_test.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Yearly_Backup_Restore_test.html</guid>
                <description>In my calendar there is a yearly recurring item named 'backup restore test'. This is an article on my backup scheme and the yearly restore test, covering all aspects, such as data validation, backup scheme, time and cost involved.
I started doing personal restore tests each year around 2012, when I did them for my first job. At work back then, the restore test was monthly, for my own backups I decided that yearly was okay enough, since the backup scheme, software and provider do not change. I'm using Azure cold storage for my (locally encrypted) personal backups, since it's both cheap and supported by my local NAS.

Have you done your backup restore test recently?</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Backup OpenStack object store or S3 with rclone</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Backup_or_Sync_OpenStack_object_store_or_other_cloud_storage_with_rclone.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Backup_or_Sync_OpenStack_object_store_or_other_cloud_storage_with_rclone.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide that shows you how to make backups of an object storage service like OpenStack swift or S3. Most object store services save data on multiple servers, but deleting a file also deletes it from all servers. Tools like rsync or scp are not compatible most of the time with these services, unless there is a proxy that translates the object store protocol to something like SFTP. rclone is an rsync-like, command line tool that syncs files and directories from cloud storage services like OpenStack swift, Amazon S3, Google cloud/drive, dropbox and more. By having a local backup of the contents of your cloud object store you can restore from accidental deletion or easily migrate between cloud providers. Syncing between cloud providers is also possible. It can also help to lower the RTO (recovery time objective) and backups are just always a good thing to have and test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Soft Delete - recover deleted instances</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_Soft_Delete_-_recover_deleted_instances.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_Soft_Delete_-_recover_deleted_instances.html</guid>
                <description>This article contains both an end user and OpenStack administrator guide to set up and use soft_delete with OpenStack Nova. If an instance is deleted with nova delete, it's gone right away. If soft_delete is enabled, it will be queued for deletion for a set amount of time, allowing end-users and administrators to restore the instance with the nova restore command. This can save your ass (or an end-users bottom) if the wrong instance is removed. Setup is simple, just one variable in nova.conf. There are some caveats we'll also discuss here. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenStack: Quick and automatic instance snapshot backup and restore (and before an apt upgrade) with nova backup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenStack_Quick_and_automatic_instance_snapshot_backups.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenStack_Quick_and_automatic_instance_snapshot_backups.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide that shows you how to create OpenStack instance snapshots automatically, quick and easy. This allows you to create a full backup of the entire instance. This guide has a script that makes creating snapshots from an OpenStack VM automatic via cron. The script uses the `nova backup` function, therefore it also has retention and rotation of the backups. It also features an option to create a snapshot before every apt action, upgrade/install/remove. This way, you can easily restore from the snapshot when something goes wrong after an upgrade. Snapshots are very usefull to restore the entire instance to an earlier state. Do note that this is not the same as a file based backup, you can't select a few files to restore, it's all or nothing.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>MySQL restore after a crash and disk issues</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to restore a MySQL server. The hardware had issues with the storage and required some FSCK's, disk replacements and a lot of RAID and LVM love to get working again. Which was the easy part. MySQL was a bit harder to fix. This post describes the proces I used to get MySQL working again with a recent backup. In this case it was a replicated setup so the client had no actual downtime. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi FM radio transmitter with Buttons</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_FM_Radio_With_Buttons.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_FM_Radio_With_Buttons.html</guid>
                <description>The PiFM project allows you to use a Raspberry Pi to send out a WAV file on the FM band. This is awesome because every normal radio then can receive your music/podcast without expensive (sonos) equipment. I've used a lasercutter to craft a new top plate for my Pi which has room for three buttons. These are hooked up to a python script which allows me to start and stop the transmission, and skip or go back songs. It also allows me to shut down the Pi instead of just pulling the power cable.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a $35 Time Capsule - Raspberry Pi Time Machine Backup Server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple guide on building a $35 Time Capsule with a Raspberry Pi. A Time Capsule is a network attached storage device from Apple for use with their Time Machine. Time Machine gives users a very easy and userfriendly way to automatically create and restore (encrypted) backups. A Time Capsule is basically an expensive NAS that only talks the AFP/netatalk protocol. The 2 TB version costs $299 at this time, a Raspberry Pi only $35. </description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Swift Objectstore Access via FTP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on accessing the Openstack Swift Object Storage system using an FTP client. Openstack Swift has a beautiful API which you can program to. However, sometimes it is handy to quickly be able to access your Swift/Objectstore data without programming around it. We will use ftp-cloudfs to do this. There is also Softlayers swftp, but that does not support Keystone Authentication (2.0). ftp-cloudfs does support this. The OS X Cyberduck FTP client also has Openstack Swift support, however that is a native implementation, not using FTP. With ftp-cloudfs we can use any ftp client, from Filezilla to midnight commander.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP Email Backup.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a bowsable HTML archive and a Maildir folder. Not one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view and no proprietary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password. This release has a few major new features, namely support to backup all available folders in one go and a conversion from HTML Kickstart to Bootstrap.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Basic website and database backups with Duplicity</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will help you backup your website and database with Duplicity. You can safely backup your MySQL, MongoDB, website and other data to an off-site location.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP email backup to HTML archive.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a HTML archive, nicely browsable, instead of weird folders (Maildir), one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view (thunderbird) and no propritary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clonezilla Backup Script v0.2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Clonezilla-custom-backup-script.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Clonezilla-custom-backup-script.html</guid>
                <description>Clonezilla is wonderfull software. At work we use it daily to image laptops. We have a windows PC with a big hard drive, which is shared via samba. Because we image an average of 10 laptops every morning, I decided to customize the script. So together with a colleague we made a script which automatically grabs our latest image from the share and restores it. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    