<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag backup on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/backup.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag backup on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/backup.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi FM radio transmitter with Buttons</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_FM_Radio_With_Buttons.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_FM_Radio_With_Buttons.html</guid>
                <description>The PiFM project allows you to use a Raspberry Pi to send out a WAV file on the FM band. This is awesome because every normal radio then can receive your music/podcast without expensive (sonos) equipment. I've used a lasercutter to craft a new top plate for my Pi which has room for three buttons. These are hooked up to a python script which allows me to start and stop the transmission, and skip or go back songs. It also allows me to shut down the Pi instead of just pulling the power cable.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a $35 Time Capsule - Raspberry Pi Time Machine Backup Server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple guide on building a $35 Time Capsule with a Raspberry Pi. A Time Capsule is a network attached storage device from Apple for use with their Time Machine. Time Machine gives users a very easy and userfriendly way to automatically create and restore (encrypted) backups. A Time Capsule is basically an expensive NAS that only talks the AFP/netatalk protocol. The 2 TB version costs $299 at this time, a Raspberry Pi only $35. </description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Swift Objectstore Access via FTP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on accessing the Openstack Swift Object Storage system using an FTP client. Openstack Swift has a beautiful API which you can program to. However, sometimes it is handy to quickly be able to access your Swift/Objectstore data without programming around it. We will use ftp-cloudfs to do this. There is also Softlayers swftp, but that does not support Keystone Authentication (2.0). ftp-cloudfs does support this. The OS X Cyberduck FTP client also has Openstack Swift support, however that is a native implementation, not using FTP. With ftp-cloudfs we can use any ftp client, from Filezilla to midnight commander.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP Email Backup.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a bowsable HTML archive and a Maildir folder. Not one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view and no proprietary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password. This release has a few major new features, namely support to backup all available folders in one go and a conversion from HTML Kickstart to Bootstrap.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Basic website and database backups with Duplicity</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will help you backup your website and database with Duplicity. You can safely backup your MySQL, MongoDB, website and other data to an off-site location.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP email backup to HTML archive.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a HTML archive, nicely browsable, instead of weird folders (Maildir), one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view (thunderbird) and no propritary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clonezilla Backup Script v0.2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Clonezilla-custom-backup-script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Clonezilla-custom-backup-script.html</guid>
                <description>Clonezilla is wonderfull software. At work we use it daily to image laptops. We have a windows PC with a big hard drive, which is shared via samba. Because we image an average of 10 laptops every morning, I decided to customize the script. So together with a colleague we made a script which automatically grabs our latest image from the share and restores it. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    