<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag badblocks on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/badblocks.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag badblocks on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/badblocks.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Spinrite 6.0 on UEFI and an NVMe SSD drive</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Spinrite_6.0_on_UEFI_and_NVMe_ssd_drives.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Spinrite_6.0_on_UEFI_and_NVMe_ssd_drives.html</guid>
                <description>Spinrite is a hard drive recovery and maintenance utility written by Steve Gibson from GRC. It is marketed on the Security Now TWiT podcast which I often listen to. I have bought a copy of it and sometimes use it on solid state disks or SD cards. Spinrite 6.0 is written is assembly language and runs on top of MS-DOS or FreeDOS, using the BIOS. UEFI is not supported and neither are NVMe drives. This post will show you how to run Spinrite 6.0 on such a system anyway, using a modern linux live USB drive that can boot on UEFI only system and VirtualBox, exposing the NVMe disk as a SATA drive.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 21:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Broken Corrupted Raspberry Pi SD Card</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Broken_Corrupted_Raspberry_Pi_SD_Card.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Broken_Corrupted_Raspberry_Pi_SD_Card.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's would not boot up after a reboot. The SD card was corrupted, sadly beyond repair. This article walks you through the steps I took to try to fix the SD card, including fsck, badblocks and other filesystem utilities. It also has tips to reduce the writing on the Raspberry Pi, this to save SD cards from some amount of wear and thus possible corruption.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    