<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag bash on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/bash.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag bash on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/bash.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Recursively find all [installed] package dependencies</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Recursively_find_all_installed_package_dependencies.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Recursively_find_all_installed_package_dependencies.html</guid>
                <description>This small script shows you all packages [installed] that are a dependency from a package, and the dependencies of those packages. I installed the build-essential package, but apt-get remove-ing that package doens't remove the development tools. So I was wondering what packages were installed, including those dependencies, to remove the ones I didn't want. This small script shows you all packages that are dependencies of a package, and repeats that for those packages.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Generate hashes of files with rhash for archival storage</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Generate_hashes_of_files_with_rhash_for_archival_storage.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Generate_hashes_of_files_with_rhash_for_archival_storage.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to archive a large amount of files to archival storage. To save space and reduce the amount of files I decided to create archives with tar. The files will be stored to tapes and DVD's, and will be restored in full, so random access times are not an issue, therefore the tar.gz choice. I do want to make sure that when the files need to be restored they still are correct. I first dabbled with some long shell commands to create checksums and verify them, but then I found the `rhash` tool in the repositories. It allows you to create checksums of files and folders, recursively, with all sorts of checksums, like CRC, MD5, SHA1 and many more. It also makes bulk validation very simple. This small article shows you how to create an archive file with the checksums included and shows you how to validate these checksums later on.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Automating Openstack with cloud init run a script on VM's first boot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to create a VM in Openstack and execute a script at the first boot using cloud-init's user-data feature. This way you can eliminate some more manual labor and keep a small base image, instead of requiring all kinds of specific images for specific tasks. This tutorial will also give you a few example scripts to use with cloud-init and to create Openstack virtual machines from the command line. </description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Solve word puzzles with bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Solve_word_puzzles_with_bash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Solve_word_puzzles_with_bash.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to solve word puzzles with Bash. It covers the grep tool including regular expressions to solve different kinds of word puzzles.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - pre-backup all container dump script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</guid>
                <description>This simple script creates a vzdump of all the OpenVZ containers on a machine. It can be used before an actual backup, in my case the actual backup excludes the container path /var/lib/vz/private. This because a dump is easier to backup because it has much less files in it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Shared Git repository over ssh for multiple users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to set up a shared git repo with multiple accounts over ssh. Only ssh, not gitolite or any other software. This is usefull if you have a small team of people that don't often need access to the repo and don't want something like github or bitbucket. With this you can use existing infrastructure.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clear Uncluttered SSH client config with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>Openssh allows you to configure parameters like username, port, proxycommand, key and more in the ~/.ssh/config file. If you have many servers this file can become cluttered and maintaining it can become a not so nice task. This simple guide shows you how you can use a conf.d directory with seperate smaller files which gets converted to the big config file by Ansible</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check and Fix SSL servers for SSLv3 connections or the Poodle CVE-2014-3566 bug</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html</guid>
                <description>The POODLE CVE-2014-3566 bug is a new bug discovered by Google in the SSLv3 protocol. The fix is easy, disable support for SSLv3. See https://cipherli.st for a good list of SSL ciphers. You can use this check from the shell to check your servers. This command can easily be automated with other shell scripts. It also allows you to check your services without exposing them to an external checking website.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Firefox History stats with Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small script to gather some statistics from your Firefox history. First we use sqlite3 to parse the Firefox history database and get the last three months, then we remove all the IP addresses and port numbers and finally we sort and count it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Patch Shellshock)with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple ansible playbook to patch Debian, CentOS, Ubuntu and derivatives for the Shellshock vulnerability (CVE-2014-6271).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set your IP as wallpaper</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set-your-ip-as-wallpaper.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set-your-ip-as-wallpaper.html</guid>
                <description>This  tutorial shows you how to set your IP address as wallpaper using Imagemagick</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>foaas.sh - Command Line Fuck Off as a Service client</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/foaas.sh_-_Command_Line_FOAAS_Client.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/foaas.sh_-_Command_Line_FOAAS_Client.html</guid>
                <description>foaas.sh is a command line [Fuck Off as a Service client](http://foaas.com/). It is written is bash and supports multiple forms of API interaction. It also supports `xclip`, when available, the result of an interaction is copied to the clipboard for later use.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get the current or all Firefox tab urls in Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This snippets gets the current firefox tab url or all the firefox tab url's. It uses the sessionstore.js file in your profile folder.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - Container to Template</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to convert an OpenVZ (Proxmox) container to a template. You can then use this template on any other OpenVZ (or proxmox) host. This can be used either to migrate containers or to create a kind of master image to deploy new hosts from.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Proxmox VE - One Public IP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to set up Proxmox with only one public IP. We will configure an extra interface bridge and make sure VM traffic is NATed. I have a few dedicated servers, some run Proxmox. Most of them however have only a few IP's. Therefore the VM's in proxmox cannot all have a public IP. For most of them that is not a problem. If needed I run a proxy or set up iptables to forward ports to the VM's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Get all certificates from a website in plain text</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to get all certificates of a website in plain text. With a few OpenSSL commands one can get the website certificate plus intermediate certificates, however, if you feed that output to OpenSSL it only works on the first certificate. Using a bit of sed and bash magic we can feed all certificates one by one to OpenSSL.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check if passwordless sudo can be used in a bash script or nagios check</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple trick to see if you can use passwordless sudo in a script. This for example can be usefull in a Nagios plugin which requires sudo. Instead of putting the sudo line in your README and otherwise having a NRPE Unable to parse result error, you could just give a nice warning message plus the right sudo configuration rule.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused CentOS/Red Hat kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This small article will show you how to remove unused kernels in Red Hat or CentOS. This is sometimes necessary because the /boot partition can fill up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Simple command line arguments</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add command line arguments to your script. It is very simple, non-positional and does not use getopts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused Ubuntu kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This one liner will help you remove unused Ubuntu kernels. Ubuntu does not remove kernels when they install a new one, however the default /boot partition is relatively small, about 100MB. So after 10 kernels, you can get No Space Left On Device errors with apt-get upgrading. Then you can eitehr remove them manually, or use this one liner to automatically remove them all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Check if item is in array</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how find out if an array has an item.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Add colour output to your script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to add coloured output to your scripts</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Debug Logging</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add debug logging to a bash script.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Trap Control C (SIGTERM)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to capture a Control C signal in a bash script, for example, to clean up any temp or pid files when your script is killed or closed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>bdsh - Whitelist Restricted Shell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</guid>
                <description>A shell where you whitelist commands and only those commands can be executed. Either via ssh, as an interactive shell or launched with commands. Logs everything and escapes dangerous characters. bdsh stands for Boa Diminish SHell. You can probably guess why. It might have to to with snakes and restricting users, no pun intended.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Incremental History Search / Autocomplete </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet for your .bashrc or your .inputrc changes the Up/Down arrow behavior to autocomplete what is already typed instead of just go back in history.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Screenfetch installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install screenfetch, a bash information tool. It displays handy system information at login, including distro name, kernel, uptime, cpu, ram and nice distro-based artwork. The tutorial includes support for bash and zsh, for every supported linux OS (ubuntu, centos, arch, redhat, solusOS, linux mint and more.)</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Better Cron env and shell control with the SHELL variable</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html</guid>
                <description>Have better control over env variables and shell settings in cron via the SHELL variable and a few scripts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Word occurrence counter and analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Word_occurrence_counter_and_analyzer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Word_occurrence_counter_and_analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>With these commands you can analyze a text file. It will count all the occurrences of all words and put out the stats. It is usefull for song lyrics, books, notes and everything.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Restrict SSH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html</guid>
                <description>restrict_ssh.sh is a bash script which restricts ssh for a user to a set of commands via .ssh/authorized_keys, and log it verbosely.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Git-clean</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Git-clean.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Git-clean.html</guid>
                <description>git-clean - bash script to find big (binary) files in a git repo and history, and clean them</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ray-Mon - PHP and Bash server status monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</guid>
                <description>Ray-Mon is a linux server monitoring script written in PHP and Bash, utilizing JSON as data storage. It requires only bash and a webserver on the client side, and only php on the server side. The client currently supports monitoring processes, uptime, updates, amount of users logged in, disk usage, RAM usage and network traffic.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Complete word count analysis of Security Now, episode 1 trough 370.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Security_Now_Word_Analyzer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Security_Now_Word_Analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>Bash-based analysis of which words are used in the security now podcast by Steve Gibson and Leo Laporte</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Correctly grep and display the uptime, load average and amount of users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Wallbase.cc commandline bash wget downloader</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Wallbase.cc_Command_line_script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Wallbase.cc_Command_line_script.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script to download wallpapers from wallbase.cc with bash and wget.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ProxBash - a bash script to manage Proxmox VE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</guid>
                <description>ProxMox VE is a very nice piece of software to setup a VM host very fast, which also is easy manageable via a webinterface. It supports both OpenVZ and KVM. I use it to manage a few VM's to test stuff on and it works really great. However, I'm a command line lover, and I thought it would be nice to be able to 'Manage' Proxmox VE from a bash shell. And I've written a script to do just that. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ubuntu/Debian update mailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</guid>
                <description>This is a bash script for Ubuntu and Debian, to be run by cron on a set interval. It checks if there are apt-updates, and if so, mails an overview of the packages which can be updated, whith their local version, the version available and an URL to the Ubuntu package site where you can see the changelog. I wrote this as an addition for my Nagios monitoring, that only shows how many updates there are, this is a lot more verbose. It also runs on Debian since 1 Nov 2012. Only the links don't work then, because the packages are different.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash - do something in every subdirectory</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html</guid>
                <description>Snippet which has a copy paste bash for loop to do something in a directory.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash script to list all changed files in certain period</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/List-all-changed-files-in-a-certain-period.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/List-all-changed-files-in-a-certain-period.html</guid>
                <description>This is a little script I wrote and use to get a daily report of all the files that have changed on my servers. What it does is list all the files that are modified within a certain time period from a given directory. It can also be run from a desktop machine, or any machine which runs bash, find and ls. Usage is simple, save the script, chmod +x it, then run (./report.sh). If you want a specific directory to be scanned run it like ./report.sh /var/www/my/dir</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NurseCalc o2 - Bash script and online app for Oxygen Calculations</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-o2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-o2.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you with nursing-related oxygen calculations. Available as bash script and as online HTML5 application.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NurseCalc Infuus - Bash script and Online app for infusion and drip (speed) Calculations </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-Infuus.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-Infuus.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you with nursing-related infusion and drip speed calculations. Available as bash script and as online HTML5 application.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Some Bash and Arch Tweaks </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Customize your Clonezilla Live CD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Customize-your-clonezilla-live-CD.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Customize-your-clonezilla-live-CD.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>EasyConverter</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Easyconverter.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Easyconverter.html</guid>
                <description>Zenity wrapper around ffmpeg to convert media files</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSHdialog</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html</guid>
                <description>SSHdialog - Small command line SSH helper</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash script for massive rename to numbers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html</guid>
                <description>Older snippet which was used for dynamic wallpaper switching.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Convert FLV's to MP3</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html</guid>
                <description>Bash snippet to convert all .flv files to .mp3.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash ja/nee keuze</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html</guid>
                <description>Dutch snippet on adding a yes/no choice in a bash script</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Imagemagick thumbnailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html</guid>
                <description>Create some nice thumbnails with Imagemagick</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    