<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag bash on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/bash.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag bash on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/bash.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Exclude lines in less (or journalctl)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Exclude_lines_in_less_or_journalctl.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Exclude_lines_in_less_or_journalctl.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small tip I want to give you when using a `less` based pager, for example in `journalctl` or when viewing a file interactively with `less` or `more`. You can exclude certain lines that match one or multiple words (or a regex) with a few keystrokes, once `less` is open. This is one of those tips you never knew you needed, but when you know it, you'll use it frequently. Like in my case today when searching through some logfiles to find out why my database stopped working.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Record your Linux Desktop with ffmpeg and slop to any format</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Record_your_Linux_Desktop_with_ffmpeg_and_slop.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Record_your_Linux_Desktop_with_ffmpeg_and_slop.html</guid>
                <description>This two-line shell script allows you to record a region of your linux desktop to a video file, or a `.gif`, using `slop` and `ffmpeg`. I use it often when a screenshot is not enough, or when you need to explain a sequence of events to someone.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash HTTP monitoring dashboard</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_HTTP_Monitoring_Dashboard.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_HTTP_Monitoring_Dashboard.html</guid>
                <description>This is a shell script that creates a webpage with the status of HTTP(s) sites. Parallel checking, thus very fast, only dependencies are curl and bash (version 4 or above). For all of you who want a simple script with a nice webpage to check a few websites. Perfect for a wall mounted monitoring display and a Raspberry Pi. Installation and configuration is easy to do inside the script. It scales well, both on the checking side as the information display page (dense on purpose). Failed checks appear right on top for you to act on. I had this script running at home for at least a year in that form, when I showed it to a friend he liked it,  asked me to make it public, but before I did that I polished it up a bit. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get number of incoming connections on specific port with ss</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_number_of_incoming_connections_on_specific_ports_with_ss.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_number_of_incoming_connections_on_specific_ports_with_ss.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to write a few monitoring plugins, one of which was a count of incoming connections to a specific network port. In the past I would have used netstat and a combination of grep and wc filter out only specific ports and established connections, but nowdays netstat is replaced by ss on ubuntu. ss has options to filter directly on all sorts of stuff, like state, ports, protocol, making the command I use more readable and use less pipes.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get all SSH public keys from gitlab</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_SSH_public_keys_from_gitlab.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_SSH_public_keys_from_gitlab.html</guid>
                <description>This small snippet gets all the SSH keys from a gitlab instance. You need to be an administrator, then you can query all keys at once using the API. On the web frontend you can only see the keys per user, not all at once in an overview.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Send commands or input to a detached screen session</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Sending_commands_or_input_to_a_screen_session.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Sending_commands_or_input_to_a_screen_session.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet will show you how to send commands to a running screen session. This includes actual shell commands or keyboard input, as well as screen commands, for example to set a logfile.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash bits: split a file in blocks and do something with each block</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Bash_bits_split_a_file_in_blocks_and_do_something_with_each_block.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Bash_bits_split_a_file_in_blocks_and_do_something_with_each_block.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for the bash shell. This bash bit shows you how to split a file into blocks (multiline) and do something with each block. This can be used for certificate chains or other files which have multiline blocks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash bits: find has a -delete flag</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_bits_find_has_a_delete_option.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_bits_find_has_a_delete_option.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for the bash shell. This bash bit shows you that find has a -delete option. I recently found this out, before I would always use -exec rm {} ;. The delete flag is shorter, performs better and is  easier to remember.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>GNUplot tips for nice looking charts from a CSV file</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/GNUplot_tips_for_nice_looking_charts_from_a_CSV_file.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/GNUplot_tips_for_nice_looking_charts_from_a_CSV_file.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to do some testing which resulted in a lot of log data. Looking at a bunch of text is not the same as seeing things graphically, this particular logdata was perfect to put in a graph. My goto favorite tool for graphs and charts is gnuplot. Not only is it very extensible, it is also reproducable. Give me a configfile and command over 'do this, then this and then such and such' in Excel to get a consistent result. In this article I'll give tips for using gnuplot, which include parsing a CSV file, a second axis, environment variables, A4 PDF's and a ton of styling options for a nice looking chart.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Match dig 127.0.0.53 server with systemd-resolvd server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Match_dig_127.0.0.53_server_with systemd-resolved_server.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Match_dig_127.0.0.53_server_with systemd-resolved_server.html</guid>
                <description>On systems that use systemd-resolved for DNS you will see the 127.0.0.53 IP address in dig output. dig is a tool to do DNS lookups, and for troubleshooting it's usefull to see which server is being queried. With systemd-resolved, you need to issue another command to view the actual server that is being queried, since systemd-resolvd also acts as a local caching server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Find all files containing specific text (and remove them)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Find_all_files_containing_specific_text.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Find_all_files_containing_specific_text.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to find all files containing specific text, and how to remove them.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Randomize a cronjob to run between 00:00 and 06:00 hours</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Randomize_cronjob_time.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Randomize_cronjob_time.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to randomize the time a cronjob runs in /etc/cron.d/</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Check if a program is installed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_if_command_is_available.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_if_command_is_available.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to check if a piece of software is installed on a machine. It's a function you can use in your shell scripts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>totext.py - Convert URL or RSS feed to text with readability</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/totext.py-Convert_URL_or_RSS_feed_to_plaintext_with_readability.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/totext.py-Convert_URL_or_RSS_feed_to_plaintext_with_readability.html</guid>
                <description> Love plaintext? This script downloads an URL, parses it with readability and returns the plaintext (as markdown). It supports RSS feeds (will convert every article in the feed) and saves every article. My usecase is twofold. One is to convert RSS feeds to a gopher site, the second is to get full text in my RSS reader. The script contains a few workarounds for so-called cookiewalls. It also pauses between RSS feed articles to not do excessive requests. The readability part is handled by Python, no external services are used.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Simple pygopherd log analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Simple_pygopherd_log_analyzer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Simple_pygopherd_log_analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>Simple log analyzer for pygopherd. Fun if you have a gopherhole and want statistics. If you ever used Logwatch you'll feel at home.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Disable motd news or (parts of) the dynamic motd on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Disable_dynamic_motd_and_motd_news_spam_on_Ubuntu_18.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Disable_dynamic_motd_and_motd_news_spam_on_Ubuntu_18.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Ubuntu 18.04 and up, when you login via SSH you are greeted with some news via motd (message of the day) that includes advertisements and messages from Canonical (via motd.ubuntu.com). This small guide shows you how to disable news, (parts of) the dynamic motd or just revert back to a plain old /etc/motd file.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Viewing PDF, .docx and .odt files in mutt (as text)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Viewing_PDF_docx_and_odt_files_in_Mutt.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Viewing_PDF_docx_and_odt_files_in_Mutt.html</guid>
                <description>mutt is my email client at work. I like the simple interface, the speed and the ability to customize the workflow. Email is synced with offlineimap and sent via msmtp, addresses are in abook, and calcurse is the Calendar for meetings, no complicated setup there. One aspect I especially like is the ability to view attachments on the command line right from mutt itself. Some departments at work send emails with an attached PDF or .docx file that contains the actual message, instead of just putting the text in the email itself. Using pandoc and pdftotext in mutt, the text of the attachments is displayed as a regular mail, no interruptions in my workflow by opening an external program. This article explains how to set up your .muttrc and .mailcap to use pandoc and pdf2text to view attachments as text in mutt.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get a JSON value with bash and sed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_json_value_with_sed.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_json_value_with_sed.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I was asked to get one value from a json object using only shell tools. The json in question is from a dutch radio station and it lists the current song that is played. Using this together with a few shell commands and notify-send we can show the current song when it changes as a desktop notification. I'd rather use Python or jq if it has to be shell. In this case the co-worker asked to just use simple shell tools and no external dependencies.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Line total (up+down sum) in PHP Network Weathermap</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Line_total_up_down_sum_in_php_weathermap.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Line_total_up_down_sum_in_php_weathermap.html</guid>
                <description>With PHP Network Weathermap you can create a birds-eye view of network components from your monitoring system (like LibreNMS, Cacti or anything else with an RRD database). It can display simple maps with components and links between, showing up and down traffic, but also complex systems with custom components, like Nagios status, temperature or other information. For network and system administrators seeing the seperate in and out traffic of a link is fine, we can sum up two numbers. A co worker filling the role of service manager asked me if it was possible to sum up in and out and show that, including the scale (different colours depending on link usage). This co worker is not interested in the seperate up/down link speed but wants to know how much traffic a location is using in total. Using a clever workaround, you can display a line's total usage, including the scale. This article also gives some more tips on weathermap, colouring and scale.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Find files in tar archives and extract specific files from tar archives</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_files_in_tar_archives_and_extract_them.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_files_in_tar_archives_and_extract_them.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small tip, to find specific files in tar archives and how to extract those specific files from said archive.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Service checks in LibreNMS (http, all other Nagios plugins)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Service_checks_in_LibreNMS_nagios_plugins.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Service_checks_in_LibreNMS_nagios_plugins.html</guid>
                <description>LibreNMS is becoming one of my favorite monitoring tools. Setup and getting started is easy and it has enough advanced options and tunables. I recently discovered that LibreNMS is able to check services as well. Services, in this context, means, executing Nagios plugins (like check_http, check_ping, etc). This allows you to check services that SNMP does not cover by default, like HTTP(s) health checks, certificate expiry, tcp port checks (e.g. rdp) and anything for which you can write a Nagios plugin yourself. The performance data, if available, is graphed automatically. Alerting is done with the regular LibreNMS alerts. This guide covers the setup of services (it's not enabled by default) and a few basic checks, like an http health check, certificate expiry and SSH monitoring.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>tping - ping with a timestamp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/tping_ping_with_a_timestamp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/tping_ping_with_a_timestamp.html</guid>
                <description>tping is a bash alias I once got from an old co-worker. It's ping, but with a timestamp. Instead of looking at the increased icmp_seq number you now have a timestamp.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Send email with multiple inline images via bash with a loop</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Send_email_with_multiple_inline_images_via_bash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Send_email_with_multiple_inline_images_via_bash.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had a request from a user that whished to receive a scheduled email with two screenshots. The screenshots were automated via AutoIt on a network share, the user manually logged in every evening to check the pictures. With bash and postfix/sendmail we can automate this process, the user now doesn't have to login but can just check their email. There are a lot of snippets and guides to attach emails via the shell, but displaying multiple images inline as an HTML mail was something I had to figure out. You cannot embed the image in base64 HTML because Outlook doesn't show that, you must use the Content-ID style embed. Like UUENCODE, but more complicated. (The next step in this process with the user is to automate the reason why they have to check those screenshots every night, that is something for another article)</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>GPG noninteractive batch sign, trust and send gnupg keys</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/GPG_noninteractive_batch_sign_trust_and_send_gnupg_keys.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/GPG_noninteractive_batch_sign_trust_and_send_gnupg_keys.html</guid>
                <description>Recently a team I consult for started using a shared password manager, pass. It uses GPG keys and presents itself as the standard unix password manager, but in essence it's nothing more than a wrapper around GPG encrypted files. We all had to generate new keys since the team is new and we were not allowed to use existing keys. Using a new, empty keyring, I generated my key and imported their keys. I wanted to trust, sign and publish all keys to a keyserver, this article shows how to do that noninteractively in batch form. Saves me doing the same thing four times, since now it's just four people, but next time it might be a hundred.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ncdu - for troubleshooting diskspace and inode issues</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/ncdu_-_for_troubleshooting_diskspace_and_inode_issues.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/ncdu_-_for_troubleshooting_diskspace_and_inode_issues.html</guid>
                <description>In my box of sysadmin tools there are multiple gems I use for troubleshooting servers. Since I work at a cloud provider sometimes I have to fix servers that are not mine. One of those tools is `ncdu`. It's a very usefull tool when a server has a full disk, both full of used space or full of used inodes. This article covers ncdu and shows the process of finding the culprit when you're out of disk space or inodes.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check HTTP status code for a page on all DNS records</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Check_HTTP_status_code_for_a_page_on_all_DNS_records.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Check_HTTP_status_code_for_a_page_on_all_DNS_records.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small snippet using curl to check the status code of a given URL on all DNS records for a given domain. This site has a few A records in round robin mode, and sometimes the automatic deployment fails. Using this query I can check which server is the culprit and fix it manually.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Firefox History stats with Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small script to gather some statistics from your Firefox history. First we use sqlite3 to parse the Firefox history database and get the last three months, then we remove all the IP addresses and port numbers and finally we sort and count it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Reset iptables to ACCEPT all (backup and remove all existing rules)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Reset_iptables_to_ACCEPT_all_-_backup_and_remove_all_existing_rules.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Reset_iptables_to_ACCEPT_all_-_backup_and_remove_all_existing_rules.html</guid>
                <description>Here's a small bash script that removes all iptables rules and sets up a default ACCEPT ALL state. Before the reset, it creates a backup of the current rules. I use this often to troubleshoot servers with networking issues. If you just blindly do an `iptables -F` you might lock yourself out of a server since the INPUT policy might be DROP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recursively find all [installed] package dependencies</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Recursively_find_all_installed_package_dependencies.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Recursively_find_all_installed_package_dependencies.html</guid>
                <description>This small script shows you all packages [installed] that are a dependency from a package, and the dependencies of those packages. I installed the build-essential package, but apt-get remove-ing that package doens't remove the development tools. So I was wondering what packages were installed, including those dependencies, to remove the ones I didn't want. This small script shows you all packages that are dependencies of a package, and repeats that for those packages.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Generate hashes of files with rhash for archival storage</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Generate_hashes_of_files_with_rhash_for_archival_storage.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Generate_hashes_of_files_with_rhash_for_archival_storage.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to archive a large amount of files to archival storage. To save space and reduce the amount of files I decided to create archives with tar. The files will be stored to tapes and DVD's, and will be restored in full, so random access times are not an issue, therefore the tar.gz choice. I do want to make sure that when the files need to be restored they still are correct. I first dabbled with some long shell commands to create checksums and verify them, but then I found the `rhash` tool in the repositories. It allows you to create checksums of files and folders, recursively, with all sorts of checksums, like CRC, MD5, SHA1 and many more. It also makes bulk validation very simple. This small article shows you how to create an archive file with the checksums included and shows you how to validate these checksums later on.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Automating Openstack with cloud init run a script on VM's first boot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to create a VM in Openstack and execute a script at the first boot using cloud-init's user-data feature. This way you can eliminate some more manual labor and keep a small base image, instead of requiring all kinds of specific images for specific tasks. This tutorial will also give you a few example scripts to use with cloud-init and to create Openstack virtual machines from the command line. </description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Solve word puzzles with bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Solve_word_puzzles_with_bash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Solve_word_puzzles_with_bash.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to solve word puzzles with Bash. It covers the grep tool including regular expressions to solve different kinds of word puzzles.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - pre-backup all container dump script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</guid>
                <description>This simple script creates a vzdump of all the OpenVZ containers on a machine. It can be used before an actual backup, in my case the actual backup excludes the container path /var/lib/vz/private. This because a dump is easier to backup because it has much less files in it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Shared Git repository over ssh for multiple users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to set up a shared git repo with multiple accounts over ssh. Only ssh, not gitolite or any other software. This is usefull if you have a small team of people that don't often need access to the repo and don't want something like github or bitbucket. With this you can use existing infrastructure.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clear Uncluttered SSH client config with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>Openssh allows you to configure parameters like username, port, proxycommand, key and more in the ~/.ssh/config file. If you have many servers this file can become cluttered and maintaining it can become a not so nice task. This simple guide shows you how you can use a conf.d directory with seperate smaller files which gets converted to the big config file by Ansible</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check and Fix SSL servers for SSLv3 connections or the Poodle CVE-2014-3566 bug</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html</guid>
                <description>The POODLE CVE-2014-3566 bug is a new bug discovered by Google in the SSLv3 protocol. The fix is easy, disable support for SSLv3. See https://cipherli.st for a good list of SSL ciphers. You can use this check from the shell to check your servers. This command can easily be automated with other shell scripts. It also allows you to check your services without exposing them to an external checking website.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Patch Shellshock)with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple ansible playbook to patch Debian, CentOS, Ubuntu and derivatives for the Shellshock vulnerability (CVE-2014-6271).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set your IP as wallpaper</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set-your-ip-as-wallpaper.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set-your-ip-as-wallpaper.html</guid>
                <description>This  tutorial shows you how to set your IP address as wallpaper using Imagemagick</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>foaas.sh - Command Line Fuck Off as a Service client</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/foaas.sh_-_Command_Line_FOAAS_Client.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/foaas.sh_-_Command_Line_FOAAS_Client.html</guid>
                <description>foaas.sh is a command line [Fuck Off as a Service client](http://foaas.com/). It is written is bash and supports multiple forms of API interaction. It also supports `xclip`, when available, the result of an interaction is copied to the clipboard for later use.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get the current or all Firefox tab urls in Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This snippets gets the current firefox tab url or all the firefox tab url's. It uses the sessionstore.js file in your profile folder.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - Container to Template</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to convert an OpenVZ (Proxmox) container to a template. You can then use this template on any other OpenVZ (or proxmox) host. This can be used either to migrate containers or to create a kind of master image to deploy new hosts from.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Proxmox VE - One Public IP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to set up Proxmox with only one public IP. We will configure an extra interface bridge and make sure VM traffic is NATed. I have a few dedicated servers, some run Proxmox. Most of them however have only a few IP's. Therefore the VM's in proxmox cannot all have a public IP. For most of them that is not a problem. If needed I run a proxy or set up iptables to forward ports to the VM's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Get all certificates from a website in plain text</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to get all certificates of a website in plain text. With a few OpenSSL commands one can get the website certificate plus intermediate certificates, however, if you feed that output to OpenSSL it only works on the first certificate. Using a bit of sed and bash magic we can feed all certificates one by one to OpenSSL.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check if passwordless sudo can be used in a bash script or nagios check</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple trick to see if you can use passwordless sudo in a script. This for example can be usefull in a Nagios plugin which requires sudo. Instead of putting the sudo line in your README and otherwise having a NRPE Unable to parse result error, you could just give a nice warning message plus the right sudo configuration rule.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused CentOS/Red Hat kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This small article will show you how to remove unused kernels in Red Hat or CentOS. This is sometimes necessary because the /boot partition can fill up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Simple command line arguments</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add command line arguments to your script. It is very simple, non-positional and does not use getopts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused Ubuntu kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This one liner will help you remove unused Ubuntu kernels. Ubuntu does not remove kernels when they install a new one, however the default /boot partition is relatively small, about 100MB. So after 10 kernels, you can get No Space Left On Device errors with apt-get upgrading. Then you can eitehr remove them manually, or use this one liner to automatically remove them all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Check if item is in array</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how find out if an array has an item.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Add colour output to your script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to add coloured output to your scripts</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Debug Logging</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add debug logging to a bash script.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Trap Control C (SIGTERM)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to capture a Control C signal in a bash script, for example, to clean up any temp or pid files when your script is killed or closed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>bdsh - Whitelist Restricted Shell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</guid>
                <description>A shell where you whitelist commands and only those commands can be executed. Either via ssh, as an interactive shell or launched with commands. Logs everything and escapes dangerous characters. bdsh stands for Boa Diminish SHell. You can probably guess why. It might have to to with snakes and restricting users, no pun intended.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Incremental History Search / Autocomplete </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet for your .bashrc or your .inputrc changes the Up/Down arrow behavior to autocomplete what is already typed instead of just go back in history.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Screenfetch installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install screenfetch, a bash information tool. It displays handy system information at login, including distro name, kernel, uptime, cpu, ram and nice distro-based artwork. The tutorial includes support for bash and zsh, for every supported linux OS (ubuntu, centos, arch, redhat, solusOS, linux mint and more.)</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Better Cron env and shell control with the SHELL variable</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html</guid>
                <description>Have better control over env variables and shell settings in cron via the SHELL variable and a few scripts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Word occurrence counter and analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Word_occurrence_counter_and_analyzer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Word_occurrence_counter_and_analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>With these commands you can analyze a text file. It will count all the occurrences of all words and put out the stats. It is usefull for song lyrics, books, notes and everything.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Restrict SSH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html</guid>
                <description>restrict_ssh.sh is a bash script which restricts ssh for a user to a set of commands via .ssh/authorized_keys, and log it verbosely.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Git-clean</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Git-clean.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Git-clean.html</guid>
                <description>git-clean - bash script to find big (binary) files in a git repo and history, and clean them</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ray-Mon - PHP and Bash server status monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</guid>
                <description>Ray-Mon is a linux server monitoring script written in PHP and Bash, utilizing JSON as data storage. It requires only bash and a webserver on the client side, and only php on the server side. The client currently supports monitoring processes, uptime, updates, amount of users logged in, disk usage, RAM usage and network traffic.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Complete word count analysis of Security Now, episode 1 trough 370.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Security_Now_Word_Analyzer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Security_Now_Word_Analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>Bash-based analysis of which words are used in the security now podcast by Steve Gibson and Leo Laporte</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Correctly grep and display the uptime, load average and amount of users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Wallbase.cc commandline bash wget downloader</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Wallbase.cc_Command_line_script.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Wallbase.cc_Command_line_script.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script to download wallpapers from wallbase.cc with bash and wget.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ProxBash - a bash script to manage Proxmox VE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</guid>
                <description>ProxMox VE is a very nice piece of software to setup a VM host very fast, which also is easy manageable via a webinterface. It supports both OpenVZ and KVM. I use it to manage a few VM's to test stuff on and it works really great. However, I'm a command line lover, and I thought it would be nice to be able to 'Manage' Proxmox VE from a bash shell. And I've written a script to do just that. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ubuntu/Debian update mailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</guid>
                <description>This is a bash script for Ubuntu and Debian, to be run by cron on a set interval. It checks if there are apt-updates, and if so, mails an overview of the packages which can be updated, whith their local version, the version available and an URL to the Ubuntu package site where you can see the changelog. I wrote this as an addition for my Nagios monitoring, that only shows how many updates there are, this is a lot more verbose. It also runs on Debian since 1 Nov 2012. Only the links don't work then, because the packages are different.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash - do something in every subdirectory</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html</guid>
                <description>Snippet which has a copy paste bash for loop to do something in a directory.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash script to list all changed files in certain period</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/List-all-changed-files-in-a-certain-period.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/List-all-changed-files-in-a-certain-period.html</guid>
                <description>This is a little script I wrote and use to get a daily report of all the files that have changed on my servers. What it does is list all the files that are modified within a certain time period from a given directory. It can also be run from a desktop machine, or any machine which runs bash, find and ls. Usage is simple, save the script, chmod +x it, then run (./report.sh). If you want a specific directory to be scanned run it like ./report.sh /var/www/my/dir</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NurseCalc o2 - Bash script and online app for Oxygen Calculations</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-o2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-o2.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you with nursing-related oxygen calculations. Available as bash script and as online HTML5 application.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NurseCalc Infuus - Bash script and Online app for infusion and drip (speed) Calculations </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-Infuus.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nursecalc-Infuus.html</guid>
                <description>This script will help you with nursing-related infusion and drip speed calculations. Available as bash script and as online HTML5 application.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Some Bash and Arch Tweaks </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Customize your Clonezilla Live CD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Customize-your-clonezilla-live-CD.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Customize-your-clonezilla-live-CD.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>EasyConverter</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Easyconverter.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Easyconverter.html</guid>
                <description>Zenity wrapper around ffmpeg to convert media files</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSHdialog</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html</guid>
                <description>SSHdialog - Small command line SSH helper</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash script for massive rename to numbers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html</guid>
                <description>Older snippet which was used for dynamic wallpaper switching.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Convert FLV's to MP3</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html</guid>
                <description>Bash snippet to convert all .flv files to .mp3.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash ja/nee keuze</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html</guid>
                <description>Dutch snippet on adding a yes/no choice in a bash script</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Imagemagick thumbnailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html</guid>
                <description>Create some nice thumbnails with Imagemagick</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    