<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag blog on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/blog.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag blog on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2024.02 released, autostart, ssl certificate expiry and minimize to tray</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.02_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.02_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include minimizing to the tray, automatic startup on Windows and Linux and a new check, SSL Certificate Expiry. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2024.01 released, better notifications and history</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include better alerting and history of events. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Using a 1965 Dutch Rotary Phone via VoIP (T65) in 2024</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_a_1965_Dutch_Rotaty_Phone_T65_via_VoIP_in_2024.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_a_1965_Dutch_Rotaty_Phone_T65_via_VoIP_in_2024.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I was gifted a T65 rotary telephone. This was **the** standard telephone in The Netherlands in the seventies and eighties. I remember my parents having one as well. Because this phone does not use DTMF but  pulse dialing it does not work with modern equipment, like the built in telephony / voip server on my FritzBox router. Using a hardware converter it is possible to convert pulse dialing to DTMF and to use your rotary phone again. This page covers two such devices, the DialGizmo and the GrandStream HT502 and a more homebrew approach.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Qt Property Macro (Q_PROPERTY with 95% less code)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_Property_Macro_Q_PROPERTY_with_95_percent_less_code.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_Property_Macro_Q_PROPERTY_with_95_percent_less_code.html</guid>
                <description>Adding [properties to QObject based classes](https://web.archive.org/web/20240529180113/https://doc.qt.io/qt-6/properties.html) is cumbersome. Although [the property system](https://web.archive.org/web/20240529180113/https://doc.qt.io/qt-6/properties.html) and [Signals and Slots](https://web.archive.org/web/20240529180002/https://doc.qt.io/qt-6/signalsandslots.html) are great to use, especially with QML, it takes a lot of boilerplate code to add such properties to a class, at least 15 to 20 lines for each property. I've cobbled up a macro that saves you about 95% of lines when using a `Q_PROPERTY`. (22 lines to 1 line).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 22:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>A docker image for Qt 5.15 LTS for Android, including OpenSSL and the KDE patch collection</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15_LTS_Docker_Image_for_Android_with_OpenSSL.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15_LTS_Docker_Image_for_Android_with_OpenSSL.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I got an email from Google regarding the API level of [Leaf Node Monitoring](https://leafnode.nl), my open source monitoring app for Windows, Linux and Android. The Play Store version must be updated to target API level 33.
For Windows and Linux I'm building the app automatically in a CI environment but the Android build was still a manual process. Until now, because after a bunch of messing around with Android NDK versions, OpenSSL library paths and Qt compile flags I can automatically build Leaf Node Monitoring in my CI.

I'm using Woodpecker CI and that requires every build step to be executed in a Docker image. There are a few Qt docker images floating around but they are all using the pre-built 5.15.2 version by extracting it from the Qt Online Installer. That version is quite old, 5.15.15 LTS was released [a few days ago for Commercial License Holders](http://web.archive.org/web/20230902132649/https://www.qt.io/blog/commercial-lts-qt-5.15.15-released) on August 31, so after 1 year it will become available as open source.
My docker image builds Qt from source using the `5.15 KDE Qt Patch Collection` branch for Android and it includes OpenSSL. This is as far as I know the most up to date docker image for Qt 5.15, currently at 5.15.10 LTS.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site update, self-hosted search via pagefind</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_self_hosted_search_via_pagefind.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_self_hosted_search_via_pagefind.html</guid>
                <description>This is a static site, meaning that no server-side processing occurs. All HTML is generated out of a few folders full of markdown source and then uploaded to the cluster. Searching on this site was always provided by a text-box form that sent you to google with 'site:raymii.org' appended to it. Works fine, but it sends all data to Google. With my recent removal of all Google Ads on this site, as well as tracking via Google Analytics, sending searches via Google seems wrong. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I recently found the `pagefind` program which I now use on here, it is a self hosted static site search engine of sorts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 21:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 21:32:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>The sad state of Alpha emulators (for OpenVMS)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_sad_state_of_Alpha_emulators_for_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_sad_state_of_Alpha_emulators_for_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS 7.3 was the last version for the VAX architecture. All later versions (like 8.4) are only available for the Alpha CPU architecture or Intel's Itanium platform. Since I don't want hardware running, which is suprisingly hard to get in The Netherlands, Alpha machines, I want to be able to run it in an emulator. simh is the best open source VAX emulator, but it does not support Alpha. My adventure with es40, the only open source Alpha emulator (development halted 10 years ago) ended prematurely since it crashes all the time. The only other available options are FreeAXP, Charon-AXP, vtAlpha and EmuVM AlphaVM. Only FreeAXP is available as a free (but not open source) download, Charon had a personal version but that is nowhere to be found nowdays, vtAlpha doesn't offer a trial or free version and EmuVM Alphaserver also stopped with their free version. In this article I'll go over my adventure with FreeAXP and EmuVM.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 22:31:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My 24 year old HP Jornada can do things your modern iPhone still can't do!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_24_year_old_HP_Jornada_can_do_things_your_modern_iPhone_still_cant_do.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_24_year_old_HP_Jornada_can_do_things_your_modern_iPhone_still_cant_do.html</guid>
                <description>I like to tinker with old hardware. The [DEC](https://raymii.org/s/tags/dec.html) PDP-8 is my favorite [retro computer](/s/tags/pdp-8.html) and [Office 2003](/s/blog/Using_a_Windows_Mobile_2003_PDA_hp_ipaq_in_2022_including_whatsapp.html) is the best version ever released IMHO.  One of my other favorite retro devices is the HP Jornada 720. A small `handheld PC` (smaller than a netbook) running Windows CE or in my case, Linux. It has a decent keyboard, CFL backlit screen, **32 MB of RAM(!)**, a compact Flash card for storage and a stylus for the resistive touchscreen. Oh and I got a 10Mbit PCMCIA network card, but wireless cards are also still available. It might be old, released in 1999, but can do one thing your modern iPhone can't. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 01:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bare Metal Vi, boot into Vi without an OS!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Bare_Metal_Boot_to_Vi.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Bare_Metal_Boot_to_Vi.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to run `Vi` without an operating system, bare metal. This is a follow up on my article from 2014 where I made a custom linux distro that would [Boot to Vim, VIM as PID 1](https://raymii.org/s/blog/Vim_as_PID_1_Boot_to_Vim.html). This time we go further, we boot into `Vi` without an operating system. This is made possible by [Cosmopolitan](https://justine.lol/cosmopolitan/index.html), a `libc` that outputs a POSIX-approved polyglot format that runs natively on Linux + Mac + Windows + FreeBSD + OpenBSD + NetBSD + BIOS with the best possible performance and the tiniest footprint imaginable.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86, Installing HAProxy and troubleshooting UNIX file paths</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Installing_HAProxy.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Installing_HAProxy.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to install HAProxy on OpenVMS 9.2 for x86. I've often used HAProxy in my career as a sysadmin and find it a very useful tool. HAProxy is an open source, fast, reliable load balancer for TCP and HTTP-based applications. This guide assumes you've set up your OpenVMS system via [my guide](https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started.html) and the [second part](https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started_part_2.html) of my guide, that will give you a fully licensed OpenVMS installation with networking and SSH access. Since I've used HAProxy so very often to set up high-available clusters and load balancers, I was surprised but happy to see it ported to OpenVMS. This guide shows the setup but also a few OpenVMS specific quirks, like file paths and troubleshooting error messages / logs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86, Getting Started part 3, the WebUI</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started_part_3.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started_part_3.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS on x86 is now available for hobbyists! Almost a year after [the official release](/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html). This is a part 3 of my getting started guide. Part 2 ended with a working network setup and SSH access. In part 3 we'll do something very exciting, installing the WebUI, a web based management interface for OpenVMS. I'll also share a few smaller tidbits, like how to use the interactive text editor via an `ssh` session and how to use `unzip`. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site update, cookie consent popup (for a static site)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_cookie_consent_popup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_cookie_consent_popup.html</guid>
                <description>A small site update this time, just to let you know that I've added a cookie consent popup to this static site. If you reject all cookies, you should not see any advertisements and aren't tracked by Google Analytics. It's open source, cookieconsent by Orest Bida.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 19:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86, Getting Started part 2, auto boot, licenses, PAKs, networking and SSH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started_part_2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started_part_2.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS on x86 is now available for hobbyists! Almost a year after [the official release](/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html). This is a part 2 of my getting started guide. [Part 1](https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started.html) ended with an installed system, this part continues with automatic startup, activating the license files (PAKs) and setting up networking including SSH access.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86, Getting Started part 1, install guide with VirtualBox</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS on x86 is now available for hobbyists! Almost a year after [the official release](/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html). This is a part 1 of my getting started guide, showing you how to install OpenVMS on VirtualBox on Windows 10/11. More parts will follow, documenting license installation, network setup, ssh, application installation etc.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86 is finally available for hobbyists!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_is_finally_available_for_hobbyists.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_is_finally_available_for_hobbyists.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS x86 is now available for (most) hobbyists! Almost a year after [the official release](/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html) most hobbyists can now login to the [Service Portal](https://sp.vmssoftware.com) to download their copy of OpenVMS 9.2 for x86, `X86E921OE.ZIP` and the PAK (license) files (`x86community-20240401.zip`), valid until April 2024. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 23:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 22:29:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Named Booleans prevent C++ bugs and save you time</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Named_Booleans_prevent_bugs.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Named_Booleans_prevent_bugs.html</guid>
                <description> During a recent code review I found a hard to spot bug, a misplaced parenthesis in an `if` statement. I often employ a technique I call `named booleans`, which would have prevented this bug. It's a simple technique, instead of a long `if` statement, give every comparison a seperate boolean variable with a descriptive name and use those variables is the `if` statement. This post shows the bug in question, an example of my `named booleans` technique and another tip regarding naming magic numbers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 20:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 20:21:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>APT keeps complaining that the HTTPS certificate cannot be validated?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Syncthing_apt_repo_keeps_complaining_HTTPS_certificate_could_not_be_validated.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Syncthing_apt_repo_keeps_complaining_HTTPS_certificate_could_not_be_validated.html</guid>
                <description>Recently a few of my Ubuntu 20.04 and Debian 11 servers failed to run an `apt update` because it insisted that the HTTPS certificate for a repository could not be validated, while `curl` on the same system had no issues connecting. Join me on a deep dive into certificate validation and troubleshooting `apt`, digging into the C++ source code for `apt` and `GnuTLS` and in the end, it turned out to be my own fault due to permission on a folder. However, the error messages were totally unhelpful resolving the mysterious validation problem. This article was written over the period of a few days, chronologically during troubleshooting.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 05:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 05:31:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2023.01 released, major performance improvements, new layout and new checks!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2023.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2023.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include a responsive and adjustable layout, massive performance improvements and a new check type, allowing you to execute external processes, for example, the nagios/monitoring plugins. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Add moc includes to speed up Qt compilation</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_add_moc_includes_to_speed_up_compilation.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_add_moc_includes_to_speed_up_compilation.html</guid>
                <description>The Meta-Object Compiler, `moc`, handles Qt's C++ extensions and it is required for signals and slots and properties in Qt. `moc` reads C++ header files and if the `Q_OBJECT` macro is used, it generates an extra `.cpp` file named `moc_filename.cpp` containing extra (meta-object) code. This post has a bit of background information and a shell script to automatically include `moc_*.cpp` files in your code whenever `Q_OBJECT` is used. If you use `qmake`, this will probably speed up your build and if you use `cmake`, this will probably speed up incremental builds (when `CMAKE_AUTOMOC` is `on`).</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Spinrite 6.0 on UEFI and an NVMe SSD drive</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Spinrite_6.0_on_UEFI_and_NVMe_ssd_drives.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Spinrite_6.0_on_UEFI_and_NVMe_ssd_drives.html</guid>
                <description>Spinrite is a hard drive recovery and maintenance utility written by Steve Gibson from GRC. It is marketed on the Security Now TWiT podcast which I often listen to. I have bought a copy of it and sometimes use it on solid state disks or SD cards. Spinrite 6.0 is written is assembly language and runs on top of MS-DOS or FreeDOS, using the BIOS. UEFI is not supported and neither are NVMe drives. This post will show you how to run Spinrite 6.0 on such a system anyway, using a modern linux live USB drive that can boot on UEFI only system and VirtualBox, exposing the NVMe disk as a SATA drive.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 21:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Responsive Qt/QML layout coming to Leaf Node Monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Responsive_Qt_QML_Layout_coming_to_Leaf_Node_Monitoring.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Responsive_Qt_QML_Layout_coming_to_Leaf_Node_Monitoring.html</guid>
                <description>[Leaf Node Monitoring](https://leafnode.nl) is my own open source (GPLv3), paid, network monitoring program for Windows, Linux &amp; Android. Written in C++ &amp; Qt 5. Perfect to run on your desktop and monitor your servers. Simple setup, auto-detects running services, runs checks concurrently and alerting. This post shows another upcoming feature in the next version, responsive layouting to more effectively use screen real estate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86 will be released tomorrow (2022-07-14), so exciting!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_will_be_released_tomorrow.html</guid>
                <description>On July 8th, a few days ago, I saw the following post on the VMS Software Inc (VSI) blog, titled 'Release of OpenVMS V9.2 for x86 Scheduled for July 14, 2022'. That is tomorrow! I'm so excited, I can't wait to start playing around with it. This short post goes over the announcement and the status of the community license, and hopes to make you just as enthusiastic as I am for the coming release!</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:27:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>What's coming in the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Whats_coming_in_leaf_node_monitoring_v2022_02.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Whats_coming_in_leaf_node_monitoring_v2022_02.html</guid>
                <description>Leaf Node Monitoring is my own open source (GPLv3), paid, network monitoring program for Windows, Linux &amp; Android. Written in C++ &amp; Qt 5. Perfect to run on your desktop and monitor your servers. Simple setup, auto-detects running services, runs checks concurrently, open port scanning and alerting. I've recently released the first version, and this post goes over the features that will come in the next release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Using a Windows Mobile 2003 PDA (HP iPAQ h4350) in 2022, including WhatsApp!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_a_Windows_Mobile_2003_PDA_hp_ipaq_in_2022_including_whatsapp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_a_Windows_Mobile_2003_PDA_hp_ipaq_in_2022_including_whatsapp.html</guid>
                <description>While cleaning out my collection of electronics, I found a PDA. Not the modern kind (voice assistant), but the old school precursor to the smartphone. It's a HP iPAQ h4350, it was a model used by the Dutch Railways. I picked it up in working condition years ago and was wondering, how does a mobile device from 2003 stack up to a modern smartphone? The first thing I did was run linux on it which worked surprisingly well, it however was noticeably slower than Windows Mobile. This post shows you how well the device still works in 2022, including using WhatsApp to chat. Almost all things I use my smartphone for, I can do with this PDA!</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 01:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Selling my own GPL software part 3, prior art (existing GPL software for sale)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Existing_GPL_software_for_sale.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Existing_GPL_software_for_sale.html</guid>
                <description>In my earlier posts I described the hurdles I faced with my plan to [sell my own](/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html) GPL software and I described how to [embed the source code directly inside the app] (/s/articles/Embed_the_source_code_directly_in_your_Qt_app.html) (for mobile platforms). This post looks at a few other projects that sell GPL software and it's a bit of a progress update regarding my plans and software.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Price of a guest post on dragonflydigest.com?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Price_of_a_guest_post_on_dragonflydigest.com.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Price_of_a_guest_post_on_dragonflydigest.com.html</guid>
                <description>I have a deep-seated hatred towards half-assed quick-moneygrabbing marketeers, but today they reached at an all-time low. This site is `raymii.org`, I received an email for a guest post on `dragonflydigest.com`. Not even remotely alike in spelling. I'm not called Justin, and I (sadly) don't maintain an excellent BSD distro. So dear telemarketers, every week I get emails like this, please put in a bit more effort. Normally I don't spend any time or effort, certainly not provide exposure, but this instance of Cunningham's Law does deserve a post, sadly.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Qt 5.15.3 Open Source released</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15.3_OpenSource_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15.3_OpenSource_released.html</guid>
                <description>Qt is a nice C++ framework with a GUI toolkit on top, actually, 2 toolkit, Widgets and Qml. Qt is available under the GPL and LPGL, open source licenses and a closed source license. [Back in 2020](https://lwn.net/Articles/817129/), the Qt company decided to [start a war](https://ev.kde.org/2020/04/06/changes-in-qt-and-the-kde-free-qt-foundation/) against their own users and contributors by withholding the 5.15 code, only releasing them under a closed license, making the offline installers available to paid customers and requiring a Qt account for the online installer. Due to [an agreement](https://www.qt.io/faq/3.2.-why-do-you-have-an-agreement-with-kde-about-your-licensing-what-kde-is-and-whats-the-history-of-qt-and-kde) with the [KDE project](https://kde.org/community/whatiskde/kdefreeqtfoundation/) they are obliged to release the code after one year under an open source license, and that time has come for 5.15.3. For most LTS releases, the Qt company writes a blog post, but this open source release only gets a [mailing list post](https://lists.qt-project.org/pipermail/development/2022-March/042262.html) (One day and 4 blog posts later, [no mention of 5.15.3 on their blog](https://archive.ph/IvMSn)). This short post is intended to give a bit more publicity to that release and to tell you about the KDE Qt 5.15 LTS patch collection. Even if I might not agree with the business practices, the framework is nice to work with.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I enforced the AGPL on my code, here's how it went</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_enforced_the_AGPL_on_my_code_heres_how_it_went.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_enforced_the_AGPL_on_my_code_heres_how_it_went.html</guid>
                <description>Five years ago I made a website that allowed you to put in a few domains and get an email when the SSL certificate was about to expire. No ads, no fuss, just an easy way for people to keep tabs on their sites without setting up their own monitoring like Nagios. As with all of my software, I released it under the AGPL due to it being web based software.
Recently I found a company that hosted certificatemonitor, with some modifications (branding and a dutch tanslation), without any reference to its origin, no source code provided and no mention of the license.
In this article I'll talk about what I did to enforce the license and how it went. TL;DR, not as expected. The company responded timely and friendly, but did a half assed attempt (added a link to my site with 'Inspired By Remy' as the text), then after my complaints, took down the entire site.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi Compute Module 4 eMMC flashing issue (nRPI_BOOT)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Raspberry_Pi_Compute_Module_4_eMMC_flashing_issues.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Raspberry_Pi_Compute_Module_4_eMMC_flashing_issues.html</guid>
                <description>I recently got my hands on a Raspberry Pi 4 Compute Module, 4 GB with 32 GB eMMC flash and a Compute Module 4 IO board. Due to the global chip shortage it's hard to find one in stock but I got lucky by checking [rpilocator.com] (https://rpilocator.com/) regularly (thanks to [Jeff Geerling] (https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2022/its-dire-raspberry-pi-availability-tracker-launched) for that site. He's got amazing Raspberry Pi related content next to a bunch of high-quality Ansible playbooks, go give him a visit).
The eMMC edition I have can only be flashed if you put a jumper on a pin on the I/O board (to put the cm4 in a special mode, `nRPI_BOOT`) and use a special tool, [usbboot](https://github.com/raspberrypi/usbboot). [Jeff has a great guide](https://web.archive.org/web/20220226203155/https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2020/how-flash-raspberry-pi-os-compute-module-4-emmc-usbboot) on flashing the cm4 eMMC edition. My `cm4` however, was not showing up whenever I put it in this special flashing mode. This article goes over the troubleshooting I did and the eventual solution (hint: hardware problem).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Thank you, shotternail!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Thank_you_shotternail.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Thank_you_shotternail.html</guid>
                <description> Recently I got a new Github Sponsor, a one-time donor. Often, these github profiles list a name, email address or some information to contact the person, even a last-resort ssh key with a comment, but this profile has nothing. They joined github 8 days ago, and I suspect it was just to do a donation to me.
Because I have no other way of communicating, here is a public post to say thank you to [shotternail](http://web.archive.org/web/20220207192842/https://github.com/shotternail), whomever you are!</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Selling my own GPL software, part 1: a lot of hurdles</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html</guid>
                <description>For as long as I can remember I've got this dream of a passive income software project. At first I thought of it as a hosted service, probably something monitoring related, or high-available cloud hosting-ish. That's the kind of stuff a sysadmin dreams of.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now that I'm a developer for a couple of years, exposed to a few different languages, design patterns and software architectures, that idea is still lingering around, but no longer focused on a hosted piece of software. The web is just too fast paced, bloated and way too much work compared to a piece of cross platform software.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In my spare time I've been chugging along on a piece of software, which I'm contemplating selling. In my case the commercial aspect is made more difficult because I also want to release the software with a GPL license.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This post describes the initial hurdles I'm encountering, next to just programming the software.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>The yearly backup restore test</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Yearly_Backup_Restore_test.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Yearly_Backup_Restore_test.html</guid>
                <description>In my calendar there is a yearly recurring item named 'backup restore test'. This is an article on my backup scheme and the yearly restore test, covering all aspects, such as data validation, backup scheme, time and cost involved.
I started doing personal restore tests each year around 2012, when I did them for my first job. At work back then, the restore test was monthly, for my own backups I decided that yearly was okay enough, since the backup scheme, software and provider do not change. I'm using Azure cold storage for my (locally encrypted) personal backups, since it's both cheap and supported by my local NAS.

Have you done your backup restore test recently?</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Relegendable keycaps for your macropad, the best thing ever for developer productivity</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Relegendable_keycaps_for_your_macropad.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Relegendable_keycaps_for_your_macropad.html</guid>
                <description>As you might know, I've got a weird keyboard. It is an Ergodox EZ, it's split up in two halves and for me it's the best thing ever to combat RSI. I've also got a weird mouse, a left handed vertical mouse, for the same reason. Even 15 minutes on a regular setup and my wrists and shoulders hurt. The next best thing is my standing desk and number three is having regular breaks with small exercises. One downside to the Ergodox is that you have less keys than on a regular keyboard. This is solved with layers, just like when holding SHIFT or CTRL, a key does something different. SHIFT is the layer for capital letters and symbols, with the Ergodox you can define your own layers. I however cannot get used to layers, not even after 7 years of using the Ergodox. Not a problem, I've got an extra keyboard in the middle, next to my mouse, with 8 or 9 keys just for my most often used shortcuts. It's called a macropad, one I've soldered myself and one I've bought on a well-known chinese webstore. One at work and one at home, both run QMK, firmware that allows me to program the macropad with my own shortcuts. Recently a video from Atomic Shrimp (awesome channel) showed off relegendable keycaps. Those are transparent keycaps with an insert for your own label. Before I had relegendable keycaps, I had regular keycaps for the macropad, for example, the `L` key sends `CTRL+ALT+L` to lock the desktop. Now, with these awesome keycaps, I have a dedicated `LOCK` key. This is such a big quality of life improvement, especially when using the CLion debugger shortcuts. This post covers my usage of the macropads, the re-legendable keycaps and shows you a few pictures of the macropads, both before and after.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Using IceWM and a Raspberry Pi as my main PC, sharing my theme, config and some tips and tricks.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_IceWM_and_sharing_my_config_and_tips_tricks.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_IceWM_and_sharing_my_config_and_tips_tricks.html</guid>
                <description>KDE is my desktop environment of choice. KDE5 is rock-solid, configurable in any way possible and works great. It treats you like a responsible adult instead of a child like GNOME does these days, and after XFCE switched to GTK3, the RAM usage is on-par, more often than not a bare KDE install (Debian or Arch) uses around 300MB ram. This is with Baloo (search indexer) and Akonadi (PIM database backend) disabled. Great default behaviour, low resource usage and enourmous configurability, so why is this post then titled 'IceWM'? At home I'm using a small ARM device (Raspberry Pi 4 with an SSD) as my main computer, and there resources are limited. KDE runs fine, but you notice that it is a bit slower than on my work computer. IceWM on the other hand, uses less than 30 MB of RAM and even less CPU. The program that gives you a desktop background, icewmbg, uses double the RAM of IceWM itself! IceWM, next to Awesome, is one of my favorite window managers, very configurable and provides all I need. This PC doesn't have multiple screens, which would be a bit more of a hassle than with KDE. After switching, the machine feels a lot faster. It's the small details in which I notice it, like text input, a few seconds of lag here and there. This post shows my IceWM config including some options explained, my IceWM theme and a few tips and tricks to configure the rest of the desktop.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Firefox 89 Proton UI Tab Styling</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Firefox-89-proton-ui-tab-styling.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Firefox-89-proton-ui-tab-styling.html</guid>
                <description>Firefox 89 recently came out with a 'new' user interface (named proton). I'm not a fan of change because UX/UI people need to make it seem like their job is relevant. Also, the picture they show under the headline '17 billion clicks...' only scares the crap out of me, tracking every move a user makes in their browser seems to me to be a bad idea, but hey, lets see how long Mozilla can continue their war against their own users. Since the `about:config` flag to disable proton will probably be gone in a few releases I thought, why not try to get used to this new interface. It's so enormous and wide, lacking contrast. As you might have guessed, I cannot get used to the tab bar, so in this post I'll show you how to use the `userChrome.css` file to make the new tab bar look a bit more like the old tab bar. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I've packaged up CKermit as a snap, for Ubuntu 20.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_CKermit_as_a_snap_for_Ubuntu_20.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_CKermit_as_a_snap_for_Ubuntu_20.04.html</guid>
                <description>Last year I packaged up [gnash as a snap](/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html) because it was missing from the Ubuntu 20.04 apt repositories. Recently I found out that `ckermit` is also not in Ubuntu 20.04, as far as I can tell because it wasn't in the Debian repositories when the Ubuntu 20.04 initial sync happened. Which is very inconvenient for an LTS release.
I often use `ckermit` to connect to our hardware via a script, to automatically boot from NFS (via u-boot). I could do that manually via `screen` or `minicom`, but I have a `kermit` script that does it for me, which is very convenient. Since the snapping of `gnash` was so easy, I decided to do it for `ckermit` as well, since I now know how to convert deb packages to snaps. I also have a few colleagues who also use those kermit scripts and are going to update to 20.04 in the (near) future.
The snap packaging is based on work by Phil Roche, he wrote about re-packaging older debian packages with an Ubuntu 18.04/16.04 base layer as a snap. My `ckermit` package is confined (no `--classic` needed), the source code for the snap is on my github and on any snap-enabled distro you can now 'snap install ckermit-raymii' to enjoy CKermit.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I've packaged up Gnash as a snap, for modern linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html</guid>
                <description>I hate snaps just as much as the next guy but last week I did something unexpected. I packaged up Gnash as a snap.  Gnash is a GNU flash media player, not updated since 2011, and  thus removed from the Ubuntu 20.04 repositories. The snap packaging is based on work by phil roche, he wrote about re-packaging older debian packages with an Ubuntu 18.04/16.04 base layer as a snap. My gnash package is confined (no '--classic' needed), the source code for the snap is on my github and on any snap-enabled distro you can now 'snap install gnash-raymii' to enjoy Gnash again.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Run MS Teams on a coffee machine?!? (Or: Embedded Linux Framebuffer VNC client)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MS_Teams_on_a_Coffee_Machine_or_Framebuffer_VNC_Client.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MS_Teams_on_a_Coffee_Machine_or_Framebuffer_VNC_Client.html</guid>
                <description> To fill some time [during compiling](https://xkcd.com/303/) I tried to get a VNC client running on a coffee machine, specifically to show MS Teams. At work I develop software for these coffee machines in C++, which allows me to do such fun stuff, because from a software point of view, it's just an ARM PC running linux with a framebuffer for graphics. I compiled a few framebuffer VNC clients, fired up an SSH tunnel and used `x11vnc` to share one specific window and after a few attempts, Teams was up and running on my 'new' second monitor.
This post contains my little adventure in framebuffer VNC clients, but it's not a comprehensive guide as most of my other articles. Showing you how to set up an Openembedded server with a VariScite specific toolchain is way too much work to cross-compile a simple C program, but since that's my day job, why not use it for fun. It contains some tips for `x11vnc` and shows you two different framebuffer VNC clients, `fbvnc` and `directvnc`.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Reset the SYSTEM password on OpenVMS 8.4</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_reset_SYSTEM-password.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_reset_SYSTEM-password.html</guid>
                <description>This short post shows you how to reset the SYSTEM account password on a single OpenVMS 8.4 ALpha machine via the serial console. You need physical access to the machine and the procedure looks a lot like linux and appending `init=/bin/bash` to the GRUB commandline to boot into single user mode. It is tested on the AXPbox Alpha emulator, I forgot my password after not using it for a month.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>The Common Desktop Environment (CDE) is still developed and modern in 2021</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html</guid>
                <description>While playing around with the GUI on OpenVMS I was looking for CDE documentation and I found out CDE is still being developed and can be installed on modern linux. This quick post shows you how to install CDE on Debian 10 and includes a bit on compiling GENERIC TETRIS, the same program I installed on OpenVMS. Really cool to compile and run a game from 1992 on a retro/modern desktop environment.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS CDE Desktop Remote X session GUI (on AXPbox)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html</guid>
                <description>Last year November, I posted on a new OpenVMS related project, AXPbox, the open source Alpha emulator, a fork of es40 by Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron; Glozar. Last week I put together the first official release of AXPbox, one of the changes being in the network code, making it more stable, thus being able to run a remote X session. Meaning, you can run the CDE desktop and enjoy everything the OpenVMS GUI has to offer. This article shows you how to run the CDE GUI in a remote X session, including switching between the old Motif look and the new DECWindows and how to run Tetris.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>AXPbox version 1.0.0 released! (Open source Alpha emulator)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/AXPBox-version-1.0.0-released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/AXPBox-version-1.0.0-released.html</guid>
                <description>Last year November, I posted on a new OpenVMS related project, AXPbox, the open source Alpha emulator, a fork of es40 by Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron; Glozar. I got involved a bit in the project, submitting a few patches here and there, editing the Wiki and thus now have contributer rights on the github repository. After discussing a bit back and forth with Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron;, I put together the first official release of AXPbox, very exciting news. The release can be found here on github. This article has the release notes and a bunch of screenshots of OpenVMS inside AXPbox running GUI applications over the network.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, new font for better contrast and other small CSS fixes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_font_for_better_contrast.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_font_for_better_contrast.html</guid>
                <description>New year, time for some site updates. This site is generated with my self-written open source static site generator named ingsoc (named after 1984) and this update is a collection of  small improvements. A new font, internal code updates to the generator and a few CSS fixes here and there. This article goes over all of them including screenshots before and after!</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Lets talk about changelogs, or, how I loathe 'bugfixes and performance improvements'</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Rant_Lets_talk_about_changelogs.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Rant_Lets_talk_about_changelogs.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short personal rant to start the new year off. When you're a multi billion dollar company with more software developers than you'd ever need, how on earth is it possible that your public changelog in an app store is just 'bugfixes and performance improvements'? If that is all you're going to put there, then just leave it blank. Or be honest and put 'We can't be arsed to fill this in' there. For me as a technical user it's not actionable, and your non technical users are not going to read that page anyway.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exciting OpenVMS Alpha Emulation news, es40 has been forked to Axpbox (and works!)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Exciting_OpenVMS_Alpha_emulation_news_es40_has_been_forked_to_axpbox.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Exciting_OpenVMS_Alpha_emulation_news_es40_has_been_forked_to_axpbox.html</guid>
                <description>Back in 2018 I was playing around with OpenVMS a lot, as it continues on the legacy of the PDP-8 and PDP-11. OpenVMS 7.3 on the VAX emulated via SIMH runs perfectly, OpenVMS 8.4 for Alpha was kind of a disaster, or, the es40 emulator was. Real hardware is available via IslandCo, but shipping to the Netherlands is horribly expensive.
The only options back then for emulation of Alpha were FreeAXP or AlphaVM, both paid, closed sourced products with watered down free versions. Nothing wrong with that, it enables us to play around, and now that OpenVMS is in the hands of VMS Software with an x86 port coming along we may hope for a bright future ahead for OpenVMS. VSI currently provides a hobbyist version, but it's a FreeAXP bundle for Windows only.
Recently I got an email from Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron; regarding his fork of the es40 emulator, axpbox. This short post is intended to give this emulator more visibility and exposure, since I find this to be amazingly cool and exciting. It lists the bugs fixed and new features, which allow OpenVMS 8.3 and 8.4 to install perfectly.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>What does raymii.org cost to run?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Costs_to_run_raymii.org.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Costs_to_run_raymii.org.html</guid>
                <description>Inspired by recent articles from Kev Quirk, Horst Gutmann and Jan-Lukas where they do a cost breakdown of their sites, I decided to do one as well. Kev is around USD 30, Horst is around USD 13 and Jan-Lukas is around 5 USD. Their breakdowns are interesting, from specific wordpress plugins to CDN or DNS costs. I don't have those, but I do have a multitude of small servers running this site, which add up to around USD 20, adding up two domain names gives me around USD 22 per month. It could be a lot cheaper, I only need one server for the gigantuous amounts of static HTML this site consists of, but I do have around 10.000 unique visitors each day, so having redundancy is nice. If I would go all cheap, this site would cost me no more than 2 USD a month including the domain name, but that would take the fun out of it. This article features a list of similar, how much does my site cost articles and a cost breakdown of this site.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ubuntu Snap auto updates broke my development setup and there is no way to turn them off</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ubuntu_Snap_auto_updates_broke_my_development_setup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ubuntu_Snap_auto_updates_broke_my_development_setup.html</guid>
                <description>After updating-by-reinstall to Ubuntu 20.04, I installed CLion via snap since that  seemed more convinient than manually downloading a java installation. CLion is the best thing since sliced bread, or I mean a C/C++ IDE by JetBrains. Ubuntu snap is  a packaging system made by Canonical and pushed hard in Ubuntu. Today I found out the hard way that snap auto-updates and that there is no way to turn that off permanently. CLion was updated, which I noticed because the process was killed. The update broke several key plugins for my workflow  and the theme was weird. In this article I'll discuss my disgust, I as the owner of the computer want to be in full control, not some developer that decides I need auto updates. I ended up removing snap completely, and my next install will not be Ubuntu due to this.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>The Twitter Bitcoin hack can happen anywhere humans are involved</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_twitter_bitcoin_hack_can_happen_anywhere_humans_are_involved.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_twitter_bitcoin_hack_can_happen_anywhere_humans_are_involved.html</guid>
                <description>The recent twitter hack involved social engineering and access to the twitter backend. This opinion piece will show you that this sort of incident can happen everywhere as long as humans are involved. Everywhere there are manual actions or admin / backend panels, this can happen. Pay a support-slave enough and they'll delete an account 'by accident'. Or a rougue sysadmin that disables logging, does something horrible and enables logging again. I'll show you that there is no one size fits all solution. Or at least, not a single fix for all. Treating your employees well, educatingthem on risks and automating as much as possible will get you a long way.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I had to jailbreak my iPhone to change the default browser...</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_had_to_jailbreak_my_iPhone_to_change_the_default_browser.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_had_to_jailbreak_my_iPhone_to_change_the_default_browser.html</guid>
                <description>The title of this article says enough. To change the default browser on an iOS device you need to jailbreak your device (root it). It's 2020 and Apple does not allow you to switch Safari with Firefox. Recently a new jailbreak for iOS was released which support the lastest firmware, 13.5. I currently have an iPhone SE 2020 running 13.5, the jailbreak was a welcome addition to fix some small and some big annoyances with iOS. Like switching to Firefox as default browser. This post contains both a small rant on the state of iOS as wel as links to the jailbreak and applications used to switch the default browser.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Here be dragons, or, invalidated iterators</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Here_be_dragons_or_invalidated_iterators.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Here_be_dragons_or_invalidated_iterators.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had a new 'first-time' moment. You know the ones, the, 'oh right', moments, after you put in a bit of research. Mine was, as you might expect from all the other recent content, related to C++. I learned, the hard way, that 'iterator-based for loops' don't like to be resized during the loop. Well, they don't really care, but some precautions are to be taken since the 'iterator' used in the loop might be invalidated. Or as the very helpfull error during the crash prints to the console, 'munmap_chunk(): invalid pointer' and your debugger points you to somewhere deep in 'new_allocator.h'. In this article I'll give a few examples, both using index based for loops and iterator based for loops, plus some more details on what's going on with iterator invalidation.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Cancellation notice: cipherli.st, txtn.ws, ssldecoder.org and certificatemonitor.org</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Cancellation_notice_for_cipherlist_ssldecoder_and_certificatemonitor.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Cancellation_notice_for_cipherlist_ssldecoder_and_certificatemonitor.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short notice that the public services I was providing, cipherli.st, txtn.ws, ssldecoder.org and certificatemonitor.org are suspended and cancelled as of now. The source code is still available via my github, but the domains and hosting are stopped. If you want to use these services, you now must host them yourself.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Windows 10 updates with PowerShell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Windows_10_Updates_with_PowerShell_PSWindowsUpdpate.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Windows_10_Updates_with_PowerShell_PSWindowsUpdpate.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had issues updating one of my machines that runs Windows 10. Turns out the firewall was to restrictive. However, the information provided by the update dialog was just, 'Oh, updating failed, maybe try again'. Nothing useful, so I tried to figure out if it's possible to use Powershell for updating. Since Windows 10 build 1709 Microsoft provides a built in module, but that is not that user friendly. In this article I'll talk about using PSWindowsUpdate and the built in Microsoft WindowsUpdateProvider to update a Windows 10 machine via the commandline</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Run CLion native on Android, ditch your desktop!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Run_CLion_on_Android.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Run_CLion_on_Android.html</guid>
                <description>How often do you read articles that state that people have replaced their main computer with an iPad and are fully content? Now, how many of those articles just use a linux server (vps) somewhere with some native apps, but mostly SSH to that server? Well, what if I told you that you can run a full blown IDE, the best IDE for C++ there is, CLion by JetBrains, on Android? Including compiling, just native GCC, CMake, GDB and all the stuff you are used to? Just for fun I've installed CLion on an old Samsung Tab S2 I had lying around, using Ubuntu in a chroot. It works way better than I'd expected, with a Bluetooth keyboard and mouse it's almost as if your on a desktop. I wonder if you could run Android Studio and use the tablet to compile app's for itself. This article shows some photo's, including a mechanical keyboard, different window managers and had instructions to replicate this setup.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>and &amp; or are valid in C++ (alternative tokens)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/and_or_are_valid_Cpp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/and_or_are_valid_Cpp.html</guid>
                <description>A post on lobste.rs on the C feature trigraphs triggered me to write this piece on the C++ feature, alternative tokens. I've recently suprised a co- worker by using an if statement with 'or' instead of '||', which works fine, but he never saw it before. It's in C++ since C++ 11, but MSVC requires a specific compiler flag ('/Za') or the 'iso646.h' header. This post has a few samples on the usage inclusing other alternative tokens like bitor, xor and or_eq.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Broken Corrupted Raspberry Pi SD Card</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Broken_Corrupted_Raspberry_Pi_SD_Card.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Broken_Corrupted_Raspberry_Pi_SD_Card.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's would not boot up after a reboot. The SD card was corrupted, sadly beyond repair. This article walks you through the steps I took to try to fix the SD card, including fsck, badblocks and other filesystem utilities. It also has tips to reduce the writing on the Raspberry Pi, this to save SD cards from some amount of wear and thus possible corruption.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Weight for Weight, a coding exercise that kept me busy</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Weight_for_Weight_a_coding_exersize_that_kept_me_busy.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Weight_for_Weight_a_coding_exersize_that_kept_me_busy.html</guid>
                <description>I'm using codewars to practice my development skills. The exercise I was working on the past couple of days was a level higher than the 'rank' codewars gives me, so a more difficult exercise. Using the sparse free time I have, this kata took a bit longer to complete, and had me thinking about the problem when I was not doing the exercise. If a problem fascinates me that way, I can't stop thinking about it until I've solved it. In this article I'll walk you through my work on this kata.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get serial port data on the web with live updating</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Get_serial_port_data_on_the_web_with_live_updating.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Get_serial_port_data_on_the_web_with_live_updating.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I was asked to build a test setup to measure the accuracy of a few loadcells (weight sensors) in a frame. Someone other than me would execute the test and required access to the measured data, preferably live and without needing knowledge of ssh or linux. The weight sensors can be read with an openscale board from sparkfun via a serial connection which the board emulates over USB (via an FTDI chip), via that same serial connection you can also calibrate them or change settings like amount of decimals. As a quick solution I created a webpage that uses a small amount of javascript to live update the readings from the board. screen is used to capture the output of the serial connection to a file which the webpage displays and updates. In this article I'll talk about how I put various bits of software together to get the output of the serial connection onto a nice webpage with live updating.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Dark Reader, dark mode for any website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Dark_Reader_dark_mode_for_any_website.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Dark_Reader_dark_mode_for_any_website.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I discovered a firefox extension that converts any website into a dark version. Works both on firefox for mobile and on the desktop (and all other major browsers), is open source, causes less strain on the eyes and improves battery life. Just as the earlier post on Blokada, I find this such a cool piece of software I wanted to share it with all my readers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Cooking with C++ templates and stronger types</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Cooking_with_Cpp_templates_and_stronger_types.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Cooking_with_Cpp_templates_and_stronger_types.html</guid>
                <description>To gain a better understanding of C++ templates I'm playing around with them. Most of the online guides stop at the example of a simple template to, for example, get the max of two inputs, or cover just a bit more (like how to overload operators for your specific template classes to make &lt;&lt; and + / - work). Combining templates with a stronger type to pass stuff around led me to a test kitchen. As in, some code with ingredients, amounts and an oven. One small thing kept it from working, after some feedback it turned out I was passing the wrong parameters to the template. Afterwards the error also made sense. This post covers both my learning and a small piece on stronger types.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, new layout</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updated_new_2019_layout.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updated_new_2019_layout.html</guid>
                <description>This site is generated with my self-written open source static site generator named ingsoc (named after 1984). I've updated the layout of the website to be less cluttered, allowing you to get to the content much faster. Inspired by my recent gopher adventures I decided to do away with the 2 column layout (drop the sidebar with menu) and have a smaller header with essential links. On mobile this makes a huge difference in scrolling, on the desktop it looks less cluttered. This article details all the changes with side by side images showing differences.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, raymii.org now also available on Gopher</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_raymii.org_now_on_gopher.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_raymii.org_now_on_gopher.html</guid>
                <description>I've made some new improvements to this website, you can now view raymii.org on Gopher! Building on the last site improvement, every article being available as plain text, it was easy to generate a gophermap file and bind it all together with pygopherd.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My phone serves me 400+ ads and trackers per hour. Blokada, the best android adblocker, beats 'm all!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_phone_serves_me_400_ads_per_hour_blokada_blocks_beats_them_all.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_phone_serves_me_400_ads_per_hour_blokada_blocks_beats_them_all.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I switched to a new phone. After a few years (!) my old phone stopped receiving calls making it time for a new one. The new phone has Android, which allowed me to install a system wide adblocker, Blokada. It works by posing itself as a local VPN, filtering advertisements, trackers and all kinds of nasty things that spy on you or bring in malware. It does not require root access on Android, it's open source and best of all, it works very well. In the first three days of usage it has blocked over 5000 ads and trackers, including 400 when I was asleep.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Reddit Gold for Caldera Openlinux 1.2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Reddit_Gold_for_Caldera_Openlinux_1.2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Reddit_Gold_for_Caldera_Openlinux_1.2.html</guid>
                <description>Someone liked my Reddit post regarding a few old CD's I found of Caldera Openlinux 1.2, including source code and floppies so much they gilded it. I got some special internet points today.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Linux on Microsoft Azure? Disable this built-in root-access backdoor (wa-linux-agent)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_on_Microsoft_Azure_Disable_this_built_in_root_access_backdoor.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_on_Microsoft_Azure_Disable_this_built_in_root_access_backdoor.html</guid>
                <description>Are you running Linux on Microsoft Azure? Then by default anyone with access to your Azure portal can run commands as root in your VM, reset SSH keys, user passwords and SSH configuration. This article explains what the backdoor (wa-linux-agent) is, what it is meant to do, how it can be disabled and removed and what the implications are. OpenStack/QEMU also have an agent/backdoor which is covered in this article as well.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates for accessibility, text only pages and skip to main content</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_Improvements_for_accessibility.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_Improvements_for_accessibility.html</guid>
                <description>I've made some new improvements to this website. Raymii.org is generated using my self-written static site generator named ingsoc, the new features are focussed on accessibility. If you are using a screen reader or command-line browser this will benefit you. Or if you like to archive stuff offline. The two main improvements are a text-only version of every content page (article/tutorial etc) and a 'Skip to main content' link.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>snap install mosaic, the first graphical webbrowser on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/snap_install_mosaic_the_first_graphical_webbrowser_on_Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/snap_install_mosaic_the_first_graphical_webbrowser_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>On one of my favorite podcasts from Jupiter Broadcasting, either Linux Action News or Linux unplugged (252 I think, not sure), Allan Pope was talking about Snap packages and how there are now WinePacks, a snap with Wine and a single (Windows) application packaged. During the discussion he dropped that Mosaic, the first graphical web browser, is available as a snap package, for modern distributions. I installed it, after huge download (1.5 MB), playing around with it is quite fun. In this post I'll discuss how to install it, what works and what doens't in the modern age on Ubuntu 18.04</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chrome 68 is depcrecating HPKP (HTTP Public Key Pinning)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Chrome_68_is_deprecating_HPKP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Chrome_68_is_deprecating_HPKP.html</guid>
                <description>In 2014 I published an article on HPKP, http public key pinning. It allows a site operator to send a public key in an http header, forcing the browser to only connect when that header is found. It was ment to redice the risk of a compromised certificate authority (since any CA can create a certificate for any website). Quite secure, but it was often wrongly configured, forgotten until certificates expired and there were some security issues like a false pin. Late 2017 Google announced that HPKP would be removed in Chrome 68 and that version is released now, so HPKP is no longer supported. This post goes into the reasoning behind the removal, the possible replacement (Expect-CT) and how to remove HPKP from your site.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>That time when one of my HP-UX servers lost half of it's RAM (and how to connect to an HP iLO 2 with modern OpenSSH (7.6+))</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/That_time_one_of_my_HP-UX_machines_lost_half_its_ram_openssh_7.3_ilo_2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/That_time_one_of_my_HP-UX_machines_lost_half_its_ram_openssh_7.3_ilo_2.html</guid>
                <description>One of my favorite sayings is: 'Hardware is stupid, move everything to the cloud!'. The cloud is just someone elses computer, but at least I'm not responsible for the hardware anymore, since hardware breaks. When a VM breaks, because you use configuration management and version control, just roll out a new one. We all know that's not true, but still, the thought of it is nice. Last week one of the HP-UX machines had a failing disk and this week it's back with a whole new issue. After it was rebooted (due to issues with the services running on it), the Event Monitoring Service (EMS) sent an email regarding RAM issues and after manual checking it seems the machine lost half of it's RAM. It should have 16 GB and now it only has 8 GB. You might imagine my suprise. This post goes into my troubleshooting, since I was not able to go to the machine, shut it down and check if the RAM was still there. I'll cover the use of cstm (Support Tool Manager), how to connect to the HP iLO (out of band access) with modern OpenSSH (7.2) and the steps I took to gather information on what might have happened. </description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Multiple passwords for one user, UIC uniqueness and the system password on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Multiple_passwords_for_one_user_UIC_uniqueness_and_the_system_password_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Multiple_passwords_for_one_user_UIC_uniqueness_and_the_system_password_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>In the book I bought about OpenVMS for the previous post on filesystems, 'Getting Started with OpenVMS by M. Duffy', I've read a few interesting things in the chapter that introduces user accounts and system login. Namely that a user can have multiple passwords, that user ID's are not unique and that there can be a system password. This article goes in to those three topics.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Mount ISO and execute scripts on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_Mount_ISO_and_execute_scripts.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_Mount_ISO_and_execute_scripts.html</guid>
                <description>I'm playing around with OpenVMS on Alpha using a trial of AlphaVM Basic, but was not able to copy paste in my Hobbyist License. I suspect Putty pasting too quickly, so I had to get the license script on the OpenVMS, without using the network. In this article you'll learn some OpenVMS filesystem history, how OpenVMS handles line endings and in the end I get my license installed by creating an ISO with the script on it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>File locking, grep and process killing on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/File_locking_grep_and_process_killing_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/File_locking_grep_and_process_killing_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>On the DECUS OpenVMS system there is no curl or wget installed. I wanted to download a remote `C` file to play around with the compiler and some simple Hello World code, to get a feel of the build system. After a bit of searching around the internet I was not able to find a command like curl or wget to download a remote file. But, the searches led me to the OpenVMS port of curl, which, I hoped, might be able to run on the DECUS system. Just like on a linux system, running the binary under my user account, not install it system wide. This ended up to be another adventure in which I figured out how to trace a locked file to a process, grep the output of a process on OpenVMS and kill a process. I did not get curl to work or compile my code, yet.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, new layout for overview pages</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_layout_for_overview_pages.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_layout_for_overview_pages.html</guid>
                <description>This site is generated with my self-written open source static site generator named ingsoc (named after 1984). I've updated the overview pages with a new layout so that items are sorted by their publishing date instead of alphabetically. I've also rewritten some internal logic regarding tags and categories. This article shows the difference before and after and includes some old screenshots of raymii.org.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Introducing the Yubikey Nano XL Rugged edition</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Introducing_the_Yubikey_Nano_XL_Rugged_Edition.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Introducing_the_Yubikey_Nano_XL_Rugged_Edition.html</guid>
                <description>Last month my Yubikey broke. I had a second one as a backup so there were no problems for me. This second yubikey is a Nano model, that means it is about 1 cm by 1 cm, the normal yubikey is 2 cm by 5. It fits inside the USB port and is meant to be inserted in the computer all the time. Extracting it from the port is hard as well, since it is so small. I use my yubikey on different machines and don't like the idea of it being in a computer when I'm not there, so I wanted to fix this. I did not fix it by buying a regular sized yubikey, but I found a clever workaround, which I name the Yubikey nano XL Rugged. You'll understand when you see the pictures.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing the es40 AlphaServer emulator 0.18 on Ubuntu 16.04, and trying to install OpenVMS 8.4 on es40</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Installing_the_es40_AlphaServer_emulator_0.18_on_Ubuntu_16.04_and_trying_to_install_openVMS_8.4_on_es40.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Installing_the_es40_AlphaServer_emulator_0.18_on_Ubuntu_16.04_and_trying_to_install_openVMS_8.4_on_es40.html</guid>
                <description>OpenVMS 7.3 is the latest version of OpenVMS for the VAX architecture. Since the DECUS system uses OpenVMS 8.4 there were some version differences. I could not set my 'BACKSPACE=DELETE' on 7.3. The hobbyist license also covers the Alpha and Itanium versions of OpenVMS so I want to try the Alpha version, which is consequently also 8.4, the latest release. This article describes my attempt to compile and install the es40 open source Alpha emulator on Ubuntu 16.04 and subsequently the installation of OpenVMS Alpha. The emulator is not under active development since 2008, and the installation of OpenVMS fails. OpenVMS does boot however, very very slowly. </description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Small OpenVMS titbits</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Small_OpenVMS_titbits.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Small_OpenVMS_titbits.html</guid>
                <description>Here are some small titbits I found out this week on the DECUServe OpenVMS system. Not enough to write a blogpost on their own, but collected together.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 7.3 install log with simh VAX on Ubuntu 16.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_7.3_install_log_with_simh_vax_on_Ubuntu_16.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_7.3_install_log_with_simh_vax_on_Ubuntu_16.04.html</guid>
                <description>Using a guide I was able to install OpenVMS 7.3 for VAX on simh on Ubuntu 16.04. This is a copy-paste of my terminal for future reference. This is not one of my usual articles, a guide with comprehensive information an background. Just a log of my terminal.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>File versioning and deleting on OpenVMS with DELETE and PURGE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/File_versioning_and_deleting_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/File_versioning_and_deleting_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>I'm now a few weeks into my OpenVMS adventure and my home folder on the [DECUS](http://decus.org) system is quite cluttered with files. More specifically, with different versions of files, since OpenVMS by default has file versioning built in. This means that when you edit a file, or copy a file over an existing file, the old file is not overwritten but a new file with a new version is written. The old file still is there. This is one of the best things in my humble opinion so far on OpenVMS, but it does require maintenance to not have the disk get filled up fast. This article goes into the PURGE and DELETE commands which help you deal with file versioning and removal.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Backspace and delete key behaviour on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Backspace_and_delete_key_behaviour_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Backspace_and_delete_key_behaviour_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>While working on the DECUServe OpenVMS system I found out quickly that pressing BACKSPACE moves the cursor on the shell to the beginning of the line instead of deleting the character to the left of the cursor. This made me very aware of my typing, since when I made an error I had to retype the entire line (the terminal is in insert mode it seems). After reading through some documentation it seems that is default behaviour but there are terminal options to change it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSH public key authentication on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/SSH_public_key_authentication_on_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/SSH_public_key_authentication_on_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>My OpenVMS adventure continues, after my rabbit hole of folder removal, this time I actually get public key authentication working with OpenSSH so that I don't have to type my password to login.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Delete a directory on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Delete_a_directory_in_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Delete_a_directory_in_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>My OpenVMS adventure continues, in this small item I talk about the removal of folders on OpenVMS. As you might expect, different than on linux. This rabbit hole got started when I made a typo in the creation of a folder, which I created in the process of SSH public key authentication. Pubkey auth still doens't work but my OpenVMS knowledge increased.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Mail on OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_second_OpenVMS_-_MAIL.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_second_OpenVMS_-_MAIL.html</guid>
                <description>Last week I registered myself with the DECUServe OpenVMS system. I found out how to navigate the filesystem and create files and folders, it was awesome. This week I learned how to use the OpenVMS MAIL program to read and reply to an email I got from George Cornelius, another user on the DECUServe system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My first OpenVMS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_first_OpenVMS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_first_OpenVMS.html</guid>
                <description>Last week I registered myself with the DECUServe OpenVMS system. I also registered with HP as an OpenVMS hobbyist and got OpenVMS 7.3 for VAX. This small blog item describes my first steps with the hosted DECUS OpenVMS system. I'm excited since I now know how to create folders, navigate the filesystem and edit files. Oh and I had a nice chat with another OpenVMS user via the PHONE program. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My Yubikey broke, but I had a backup. So should you with your 2FA</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_Yubikey_Broke_-_Important_tip_for_two_factor_BACKUP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_Yubikey_Broke_-_Important_tip_for_two_factor_BACKUP.html</guid>
                <description>Today my trusty old first generation Yubikey didn't light up when I plugged it in. No problem for me, I had a backup key. But most people don't, so here's an important tip when you use two factor authentication like a Yubikey, Nitrokey or Google Authenticator (HOTP). TL;DR: Have a second hardware token stored away safely and backup your QR codes (print/screenshot) somewhere secure. Swap the hardware tokens often to make sure they both work with all services. Just as with regular data, make backups and test restores.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Burn in testing for new Hypervisor and Storage server hardware</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Burn_in_testing_for_Hypervisor_and_Storage_servers.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Burn_in_testing_for_Hypervisor_and_Storage_servers.html</guid>
                <description>This article talks over how and why to do burn in testing on hypervisor and storage servers. I work at a fairly large cloud provider, where we have a lot of hardware. Think thousands of hardware servers and multiple ten thousand harddisks. It's all technology, so stuff breaks, and at our scale, stuff breaks often. One of my pet projects for the last period has been to automate the burn-in testing for our virtualisation servers and the storage machines. We run OpenStack and use KVM for the hypervisors and a combination of different storage technology for the volume storage servers. Before they go in production, they are tested for a few days with very intensive automated usage. We've noticed that they either fail then, or not. This saves us from having to migrate customers off of new production servers just a few days after they've gone live. The testing is of course all automated.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Overflow the Investigatory Powers Bill!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Overflow_the_Investigatory_Powers_Bill.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Overflow_the_Investigatory_Powers_Bill.html</guid>
                <description>I read an article on The Register regarding the Investigatory Powers Bill. The part were ISP's are forced to save their customers browsing history for a year is the most horryfing part, just as that whole bill. Let's hope the political process and organizations like the Open Rights Group and the EFF have enough lobbying power to change people's minds.	If that fails, then we can all try to overflow the logging. Just as some people put keywords in their mail signatures to trigger automatic filters and generate noise, we should all generate as much data and noise as possible. This way the information they do gather will not be usefull, it will take too much time, storage and effort to process it and thus the project will fail. 2 years ago I wrote a small Python script which browser the web for you, all the time. Running that on one or two Raspberry Pi's or other small low power computers 24/7 will generate a lot of noise in the logging and filtering.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>MySQL restore after a crash and disk issues</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to restore a MySQL server. The hardware had issues with the storage and required some FSCK's, disk replacements and a lot of RAID and LVM love to get working again. Which was the easy part. MySQL was a bit harder to fix. This post describes the proces I used to get MySQL working again with a recent backup. In this case it was a replicated setup so the client had no actual downtime. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Mouse movement via the keyboard with xdotool and xbindkeys</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Mouse_movement_via_the_keyboard_with_xdotool_and_xbindkeys.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Mouse_movement_via_the_keyboard_with_xdotool_and_xbindkeys.html</guid>
                <description>I had a request from a friend to figure out how she could use her mouse via the keyboard. Normally you would use Mouse Keys, but she uses a kinesis freestyle2 keyboard which has no numpad. By using xbindkeys together with xdotool we can use our own key combination to move the mouse keys, in any window manager. </description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Reset iptables to ACCEPT all (backup and remove all existing rules)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Reset_iptables_to_ACCEPT_all_-_backup_and_remove_all_existing_rules.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Reset_iptables_to_ACCEPT_all_-_backup_and_remove_all_existing_rules.html</guid>
                <description>Here's a small bash script that removes all iptables rules and sets up a default ACCEPT ALL state. Before the reset, it creates a backup of the current rules. I use this often to troubleshoot servers with networking issues. If you just blindly do an `iptables -F` you might lock yourself out of a server since the INPUT policy might be DROP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi unattended upgrade Raspbian to Debian Testing</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Raspberry_Pi_Raspbian_Unattended_Upgrade_Jessie_to_Testing.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Raspberry_Pi_Raspbian_Unattended_Upgrade_Jessie_to_Testing.html</guid>
                <description>I'm working on a Nitrokey/SmartCard-HSM cluster article and therefore I needed three identical computers. The current version of Raspbian (2016-05-27) is based on Debian Jessie and comes with a version of OpenSC that is too old (0.14) to work with the Nitrokey/SmartCard-HSM. Since there is no Ubuntu 16.04 official image yet I decided to upgrade Raspbian to Debian Testing. Since I don't want to answer yes to any config file changes or service restarts I figured out how to do an unattended dist-upgrade.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Migrating personal webapps and services</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I've migrated some of my personal servers and services to new machines and newer operating system versions. I prefer to migrate instead of upgrading the OS for a number of reasons. I'll also talk about the migration process and some stuff to remember when migrating web applications and services.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Forward or save outgoing email with Exim</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Forward_or_save_all_outgoing_email_with_exim.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Forward_or_save_all_outgoing_email_with_exim.html</guid>
                <description>I have a specific server where requirements state that all outgoing email should be saved for archival and auditing purposes. The server uses the Exim mail transfer agent, which makes this easy to configure. The outgoing email is also forwarded to an off-site mailbox, both for backup and easy consulting. This captures all outgoing email, sent by PHP scripts or cronjobs, or user accounts that send via exim. This tutorial also shows how to forward or save all outgoing email for a specific domain.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Generate hashes of files with rhash for archival storage</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Generate_hashes_of_files_with_rhash_for_archival_storage.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Generate_hashes_of_files_with_rhash_for_archival_storage.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to archive a large amount of files to archival storage. To save space and reduce the amount of files I decided to create archives with tar. The files will be stored to tapes and DVD's, and will be restored in full, so random access times are not an issue, therefore the tar.gz choice. I do want to make sure that when the files need to be restored they still are correct. I first dabbled with some long shell commands to create checksums and verify them, but then I found the `rhash` tool in the repositories. It allows you to create checksums of files and folders, recursively, with all sorts of checksums, like CRC, MD5, SHA1 and many more. It also makes bulk validation very simple. This small article shows you how to create an archive file with the checksums included and shows you how to validate these checksums later on.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>How I got a valid SSL certificate for my ISP's main domain, xs4all.nl</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/How_I_got_a_valid_SSL_certificate_for_my_ISPs_main_website.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/How_I_got_a_valid_SSL_certificate_for_my_ISPs_main_website.html</guid>
                <description>I got a valid SSL certificate for a domain that is not mine by creating an email alias. In this article I'll explain what happened, why that was possible and how we all can prevent this.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove Installatron from a (Directadmin) server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Remove_Installatron_from_a_(Directadmin)_server.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Remove_Installatron_from_a_(Directadmin)_server.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short guide which shows you how to remove Installatron from a server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Filtering IMAP mail with imapfilter</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Filtering_IMAP_mail_with_imapfilter.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Filtering_IMAP_mail_with_imapfilter.html</guid>
                <description>I have several email accounts at different providers. Most of them don't offer filtering capabilites like Sieve, or only their own non exportable rule system (Google Apps). My mail client of choice, Thunderbird, has filtering capabilities but my phone has not and I don't want to leave my machine running Thunderbird all the time since it gets quite slow with huge mailboxes. Imapfilter is a mail filtering utility written in Lua which connects to one or more IMAP accounts and filters on the server using IMAP queries. It is a lightweight command line utility, the configuration can be versioned and is simple text and it is very fast.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clear Uncluttered SSH client config with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>Openssh allows you to configure parameters like username, port, proxycommand, key and more in the ~/.ssh/config file. If you have many servers this file can become cluttered and maintaining it can become a not so nice task. This simple guide shows you how you can use a conf.d directory with seperate smaller files which gets converted to the big config file by Ansible</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Boot to Vim, Vim as Pid 1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Vim_as_PID_1_Boot_to_Vim.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Vim_as_PID_1_Boot_to_Vim.html</guid>
                <description>This is a response on a great article from Pascal Bourguignon, namely how to run Emacs as PID 1. As we all know, nobody uses emacs. No, all joking aside, I found it to be a good article and wanted to see how I could do that with Vim. Not in User Mode Linux, but by creating an actual ISO. Boot to Vim, as you might want to call it. This is actually fairly simple. Compile vim statically, set it as init= at boot and you're done. We are going to use small 9MB distro named Tiny Core, Core edition and customize that to boot right into our static build of Vim.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Statically (cross) compiled vim for x86, x86-64 and mipsel</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html</guid>
                <description>Sometimes I need to manage a few systems with either low resources or a very restricted set of packages. On those systems no compilers or development libraries are available, however it is allowed to bring binaries.A few of those systems are 32 bit x68 systems, some are MIPS systems, even worse. They serve a secure purpose, I cannot go in to much detail about them, except for they require a high level of security, they process certificates. I really like vim as my editor, the only editor available by default on those systems is ed. I have an ed cheatsheet for this purpose. The solution for this problem is to create a statically (cross) compiled version of vim. This article shows you how to create a statically compiled vim that runs everywhere.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Owncloud, DirectAdmin, Apache 2.4 and Error AH01797: client denied by server configuration</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Owncloud_DirectAdmin,_Apache_2.4_and_Error_AH01797_client_denied_by_server_configuration.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Owncloud_DirectAdmin,_Apache_2.4_and_Error_AH01797_client_denied_by_server_configuration.html</guid>
                <description>I keep a few servers around for shared webhosting for friends, family and some other domains. Most of them run Directadmin, because it is easier to work with for the target audience. I'm very good with the command line, they've never heard of it. One of my friends runs Owncloud, a wonderfull piece of software to get cloud services under your control. He does not use the file part but rather the calendar and contacts a lot. A recent update of Apache to 2.4.10 broke that functionality on a Directadmin machine with the error AH01797: client denied by server configuration. After a bit of searching and debugging, here's how I fixed it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPv6 at Home</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/IPv6_at_Home.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/IPv6_at_Home.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's was running a test setup of the Citadel groupware service. The test was sucessfull, so I set up a real world setup. The Raspberry Pi would serve another purpose, namely, a Linux Torrent seedbox. As in, to seed Linux torrents from linuxtracker.org. I choose Transmission for this, because it is simple, fast and stable. Transmission has a good webinterface, plus it allows access from remote clients with the transmission-remote gui packages. This article shows you how to set it up on a Raspberry Pi running Arch Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Transmission Web on a Raspberry Pi with Arch Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's was running a test setup of the Citadel groupware service. The test was sucessfull, so I set up a real world setup. The Raspberry Pi would serve another purpose, namely, a Linux Torrent seedbox. As in, to seed Linux torrents from linuxtracker.org. I choose Transmission for this, because it is simple, fast and stable. Transmission has a good webinterface, plus it allows access from remote clients with the transmission-remote gui packages. This article shows you how to set it up on a Raspberry Pi running Arch Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FreeBSD 10, Converting from RELEASE to STABLE </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_10_Converting_from_RELEASE_to_STABLE.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_10_Converting_from_RELEASE_to_STABLE.html</guid>
                <description>Because of a [bug in  mpd][1] which is fixed in 10-STABLE I wanted to move one of my FreeBSD machines from 10.0-RELEASE to 10.0-STABLE. The process to do so is fairly simple. Basically, you check out the new source code, build the world, build the kernel, install the kernel, install the world, merge some stuff and reboot. Read on to see the entire process</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Linux software raid, rebuilding broken raid 1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html</guid>
                <description>Last week Nagios alerted me about a broken disk in one of my clients testing servers. There is a best effort SLA on the thing, and there were spare drives of the same type and size in the datacenter. Lucky me. This particular data center is on biking distance, so I enjoyed a sunny ride there. Simply put, I needed to replace the disk and rebuild the raid 1 array. This server is a simple Ubuntu 12.04 LTS server with two disks running in raid 1, no spare. Client has a tight budget, and with a best effort SLA not in production, fine with me. Consultant tip, make sure you have those things signed. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FreeBSD Ports: remove config options</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_Ports_remove_config_options.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_Ports_remove_config_options.html</guid>
                <description>Today I wanted to upgrade a few packages on one of my FreeBSD servers. The vim port kept complaining: You must select one and only one option from the UI single. Read on to find out how I fixed this error.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>RET Metro ATB</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/RET_Metro_ATB.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/RET_Metro_ATB.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>RET Metro Type M MG/2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/RET_Metro_Type_M.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/RET_Metro_Type_M.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>RET Metro Type T SG/2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/RET_Metro_Type_T.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/RET_Metro_Type_T.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>RET Metro ZUB</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/RET_Metro_ZUB.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/RET_Metro_ZUB.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    