<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag boost on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/boost.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag boost on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/boost.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>CookieNumberPrinter, incremental / idle game style numbers in C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/CookieNumberPrinter_incremental_game_style_numbers.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/CookieNumberPrinter_incremental_game_style_numbers.html</guid>
                <description>To level up my software development skills, I'm programming a command line game in my spare  time.  It is a clone of the famous cookieclicker game by ortiel. A clone of a game is simple enough to get up and running  fairly quickly, but also extensible enough when needed. How do you store huge score numbers  when they don't fit in a long long? How do you write a game loop, how to use threads to handle  user input? Saving a game (how to design a proper save format)? Also a great way to learn about project organization, software architecture and to try out design patterns. As the game is a clone of CookieCliker, which itself is an incremental game, I had to figure out how to work with large numbers. Since this is not a university math project, I allowed myself the luxury of using Boosts Multiprecision.  The library handles the large numbers, including caluclation and operations with such a number. I did want to print the numbers in Idle Style, where large numbers are displayed with a suffix, like '1 million' instead of '1000000' and so on. This 'C++' class can be used to print Boost's 'cpp_dec_float' numbers in incremental style. It's just one header.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>std::string to lowercase or uppercase in C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/std_string_to_lowercase_or_uppercase_in_cpp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/std_string_to_lowercase_or_uppercase_in_cpp.html</guid>
                <description>I'm using codewars to practice my development skills. Today I learned a method to transform a std::string's casing, either to uppercase or lowercase. Researching it further, I also found out how to do unicode strings with boost. This article also includes a mini howto on installing Boost on Windows 10 via mingw for use with CLion.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>C++ project setup with CMake &amp; unit tests (google test)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Cpp_project_setup_with_cmake_and_unit_tests.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Cpp_project_setup_with_cmake_and_unit_tests.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to setup a new C++ project with CMake and unit tests via Google's test framework. With this setup you can get started right away with test-driven-development in C++. It is also simple enough to look and figure out how to add gtest to your existing project and start doing TDD on your legacy (existing) codebase.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    