<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag browser on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/browser.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag browser on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/browser.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Firefox 89 Proton UI Tab Styling</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Firefox-89-proton-ui-tab-styling.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Firefox-89-proton-ui-tab-styling.html</guid>
                <description>Firefox 89 recently came out with a 'new' user interface (named proton). I'm not a fan of change because UX/UI people need to make it seem like their job is relevant. Also, the picture they show under the headline '17 billion clicks...' only scares the crap out of me, tracking every move a user makes in their browser seems to me to be a bad idea, but hey, lets see how long Mozilla can continue their war against their own users. Since the `about:config` flag to disable proton will probably be gone in a few releases I thought, why not try to get used to this new interface. It's so enormous and wide, lacking contrast. As you might have guessed, I cannot get used to the tab bar, so in this post I'll show you how to use the `userChrome.css` file to make the new tab bar look a bit more like the old tab bar. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I had to jailbreak my iPhone to change the default browser...</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_had_to_jailbreak_my_iPhone_to_change_the_default_browser.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_had_to_jailbreak_my_iPhone_to_change_the_default_browser.html</guid>
                <description>The title of this article says enough. To change the default browser on an iOS device you need to jailbreak your device (root it). It's 2020 and Apple does not allow you to switch Safari with Firefox. Recently a new jailbreak for iOS was released which support the lastest firmware, 13.5. I currently have an iPhone SE 2020 running 13.5, the jailbreak was a welcome addition to fix some small and some big annoyances with iOS. Like switching to Firefox as default browser. This post contains both a small rant on the state of iOS as wel as links to the jailbreak and applications used to switch the default browser.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Dark Reader, dark mode for any website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Dark_Reader_dark_mode_for_any_website.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Dark_Reader_dark_mode_for_any_website.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I discovered a firefox extension that converts any website into a dark version. Works both on firefox for mobile and on the desktop (and all other major browsers), is open source, causes less strain on the eyes and improves battery life. Just as the earlier post on Blokada, I find this such a cool piece of software I wanted to share it with all my readers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>snap install mosaic, the first graphical webbrowser on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/snap_install_mosaic_the_first_graphical_webbrowser_on_Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/snap_install_mosaic_the_first_graphical_webbrowser_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>On one of my favorite podcasts from Jupiter Broadcasting, either Linux Action News or Linux unplugged (252 I think, not sure), Allan Pope was talking about Snap packages and how there are now WinePacks, a snap with Wine and a single (Windows) application packaged. During the discussion he dropped that Mosaic, the first graphical web browser, is available as a snap package, for modern distributions. I installed it, after huge download (1.5 MB), playing around with it is quite fun. In this post I'll discuss how to install it, what works and what doens't in the modern age on Ubuntu 18.04</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    