<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag caon Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/ca.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag caon Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/ca.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypt and decrypt files to public keys via the OpenSSL Command Line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypt_and_decrypt_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypt_and_decrypt_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial will show you how to use the openssl command line to encrypt and decrypt a file using a public key. We will first generate a random key, encrypt that random key against the public key of the other person and use that random key to encrypt the actual file with using symmetric encryption.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Sign and verify text/files to public keys via the OpenSSL Command Line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Sign_and_verify_text_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Sign_and_verify_text_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</guid>
                <description>This small guide will shows you how to use the OpenSSL Command Line to sign a file, and how to verify the signing of this file. You can do this to prove ownership of a key, or to prove that a file hasn't been modified since you signed it. This works both with small text files as well as huge photo's, documents or PDF files.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL command line Root and Intermediate CA including OCSP, CRL and revocation</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL and_revocation.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL and_revocation.html</guid>
                <description>These are quick and dirty notes on generating a certificate authority (CA), intermediate certificate authorities and end certificates using the OpenSSL command line tools. It includes OCSP, CRL and CA Issuer information and specific issue and expiry dates. We'll set up our own root CA. We'll use the root CA to generate an example intermediate CA. We'll use the intermediate CA to sign end user certificates.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>CentOS 5 CA Certificate Bundle Update</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_5_CA_Certificate_Bundle_Update.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_5_CA_Certificate_Bundle_Update.html</guid>
                <description>This simple snippet shows you how to update the root ca certificate bundle on CentOS 5. Some websites have certificates signed by authorities not in the default bundle and those websites will not work with tools like git, curl, wget or anything else that uses https.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    