<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag cde on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/cde.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag cde on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/cde.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Remote desktop on NetBSD with Xnest (no VNC)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Remote_desktop_on_NetBSD_with_Xnest_no_VNC.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Remote_desktop_on_NetBSD_with_Xnest_no_VNC.html</guid>
                <description>After I recently wrote about NetBSD on the DEC Alpha CPU in QEMU, I decided to play with NetBSD some more. One x86_64 virtual machine later, I'm starting to appreciate the beauty and simplicity. Great documentation, both online and via the manpages, low resource usage and boy oh boy does it feel fast. But, you're not here for my love letter, you want to have a remote desktop. In the earlier article, we set up VNC, both because it shows you how to install packages and because native X11 crashes. In this article, we are going to set up X11 forwarding via SSH, but with `Xnest` instead of VNC. `Xnest` allows you to have a full desktop / window manager inside a window. If you did a full install of NetBSD, then all you need is included on the system, no need to install any packages. This is an advantage if you are on an architecture that has no precompiled binary packages or if compiling from source takes too long.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>The Common Desktop Environment (CDE) is still developed and modern in 2021</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html</guid>
                <description>While playing around with the GUI on OpenVMS I was looking for CDE documentation and I found out CDE is still being developed and can be installed on modern linux. This quick post shows you how to install CDE on Debian 10 and includes a bit on compiling GENERIC TETRIS, the same program I installed on OpenVMS. Really cool to compile and run a game from 1992 on a retro/modern desktop environment.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS CDE Desktop Remote X session GUI (on AXPbox)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html</guid>
                <description>Last year November, I posted on a new OpenVMS related project, AXPbox, the open source Alpha emulator, a fork of es40 by Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron; Glozar. Last week I put together the first official release of AXPbox, one of the changes being in the network code, making it more stable, thus being able to run a remote X session. Meaning, you can run the CDE desktop and enjoy everything the OpenVMS GUI has to offer. This article shows you how to run the CDE GUI in a remote X session, including switching between the old Motif look and the new DECWindows and how to run Tetris.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    