<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag centos on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/centos.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag centos on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/centos.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Let's Encrypt with DirectAdmin, now built in!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin_Now_Built_In.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin_Now_Built_In.html</guid>
                <description>Let's Encrypt is a new certificate authority, recognized by all major browsers. They make it a breeze to set up TLS certificates for your web server. And for free! Let's Encrypt is supported by major players like Mozilla, Akamai, Cisco, the EFF, the Internet Security Research Group and others. Let's Encrypt provides free, automatic and secure certificates so that every website can be secured with an SSL certificate. This article shows you how to setup Let's Encrypt with the DirectAdmin web control panel. DirectAdmin now supports Lets Encrypt natively since 1.50, so no more ssh fiddling, just via the control panel, for all the users on the server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Deborphan cleanup until no more orphaned packages left</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html</guid>
                <description>Deborphan removes packages it thinks your system doesn't need anymore. It is a great tool for package cleanup and maintenance. Sometimes, after cleaning up the packages, it will find new packages that are orphaned (because you just cleaned up). This is a small script that cleans up with deborphan until there is nothing more to cleanup.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Let's Encrypt with DirectAdmin or other Web Control Panels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin.html</guid>
                <description>Let's Encrypt is a new certificate authority, recognized by all major browsers. They make it a breeze to set up TLS certificates for your web server. And for free! Let's Encrypt is supported by major players like Mozilla, Akamai, Cisco, the EFF, the Internet Security Research Group and others. Let's Encrypt provides free, automatic and secure certificates so that every website can be secured with an SSL certificate. This article shows you how to setup Let's Encrypt with the DirectAdmin web control panel. The guide is generic, so it works for other controlpanels as well. For now it works with the beta, and required some linux knowledge and root access to the hosting server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Find all services using libssl to restart after an OpenSSL update</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html</guid>
                <description>When you update OpenSSL, the software that currently has the ssl libraries loaded in memory do not automatically load the updated libraries. A full system reboot resolves that problem, but sometimes that is not possible. This command shows you all the software that has loaded the libraries, allowing you to restart only those services. If you don't restart or reload after an update, the software might still be vulnerable to issues that the update fixed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>systemd: Don't fear change</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/systemd_dont_fear_change.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/systemd_dont_fear_change.html</guid>
                <description>This article talks about systemd in Red Hat Enterprise Linux / CentOS 7. It gives some usage examples and talks about the differences between systemd, upstart and sysvinit.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing Virtual Machines with virt-install, plus copy pastable distro install one-liners</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</guid>
                <description>virt-install is a command line tool for creating new KVM , Xen or Linux container guests using the libvirt hypervisor management library. It allows you to create a VM and start an installation from the command line. This article has a few copy pastable getting started examples for different distro's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Centos 7 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_CentOS_7.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_CentOS_7.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server with CentOS 7 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSECP protocol stack because of recent vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on CentOS 6 / Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 / Scientific Linux 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_CentOS_-_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_or_Scientific_-_Linux_6.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_CentOS_-_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_or_Scientific_-_Linux_6.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check and Fix SSL servers for SSLv3 connections or the Poodle CVE-2014-3566 bug</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html</guid>
                <description>The POODLE CVE-2014-3566 bug is a new bug discovered by Google in the SSLv3 protocol. The fix is easy, disable support for SSLv3. See https://cipherli.st for a good list of SSL ciphers. You can use this check from the shell to check your servers. This command can easily be automated with other shell scripts. It also allows you to check your services without exposing them to an external checking website.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Configserver Firewall and Security (CSF and LFD)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Configserver_Firewall_and_Security_CSF_LFD.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Configserver_Firewall_and_Security_CSF_LFD.html</guid>
                <description>his page covers my notes about csf and lfd. csf is an easy SPI iptables firewall suite. lfd is the login failure daemon, which scans log files for failed authentication and blocks the IP's doing that. This page covers installation, populair command line options and popular config file options.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Patch Shellshock)with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple ansible playbook to patch Debian, CentOS, Ubuntu and derivatives for the Shellshock vulnerability (CVE-2014-6271).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>CentOS 5 CA Certificate Bundle Update</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_5_CA_Certificate_Bundle_Update.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_5_CA_Certificate_Bundle_Update.html</guid>
                <description>This simple snippet shows you how to update the root ca certificate bundle on CentOS 5. Some websites have certificates signed by authorities not in the default bundle and those websites will not work with tools like git, curl, wget or anything else that uses https.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Swift Objectstore Access via FTP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on accessing the Openstack Swift Object Storage system using an FTP client. Openstack Swift has a beautiful API which you can program to. However, sometimes it is handy to quickly be able to access your Swift/Objectstore data without programming around it. We will use ftp-cloudfs to do this. There is also Softlayers swftp, but that does not support Keystone Authentication (2.0). ftp-cloudfs does support this. The OS X Cyberduck FTP client also has Openstack Swift support, however that is a native implementation, not using FTP. With ftp-cloudfs we can use any ftp client, from Filezilla to midnight commander.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused CentOS/Red Hat kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This small article will show you how to remove unused kernels in Red Hat or CentOS. This is sometimes necessary because the /boot partition can fill up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Screenfetch installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install screenfetch, a bash information tool. It displays handy system information at login, including distro name, kernel, uptime, cpu, ram and nice distro-based artwork. The tutorial includes support for bash and zsh, for every supported linux OS (ubuntu, centos, arch, redhat, solusOS, linux mint and more.)</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Systemd rosetta / cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</guid>
                <description>A reference for systemd, for sysadmins who love plain old init.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Fix CentOS IPTables rule saving (iptables: Saving firewall rules to /etc/sysconfig/iptables: /etc/init.d/iptables: line 274: restorecon: command not found)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_Save_iptables_restorecon_error.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_Save_iptables_restorecon_error.html</guid>
                <description>On a default CentOS installation, when trying to execute the iptables save command you can get an error like iptables: Saving firewall rules to /etc/sysconfig/iptables: /etc/init.d/iptables: line 274: restorecon: command not found. Read this article to find out how to fix it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    