<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag certificate on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/certificate.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag certificate on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/certificate.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL generate self signed certificate with SAN in one command (subject alternative name)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_generate_self_signed_cert_with_Subject_Alternative_name_oneliner.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_generate_self_signed_cert_with_Subject_Alternative_name_oneliner.html</guid>
                <description>This small one liner lets you generate an OpenSSL self signed certificate with both a common name and a [Subject Alternative Name (SAN)](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subject_Alternative_Name). Most guides online require you to specify a separate config file but this guide uses a bash trick [(process substitution)](https://web.archive.org/web/20221014191420/https://superuser.com/questions/1059781/what-exactly-is-in-bash-and-in-zsh) to pass such a config file to OpenSSL via the command line. If you are using OpenSSL 1.1.1 or higher, there now finally is a built in command line option which I'll also cover. </description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 22:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 22:02:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL test TLSv1.3 connection and ciphersuites with s_client</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_test_TLSv1.3_connection_with_s_client.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_test_TLSv1.3_connection_with_s_client.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to test a server's TLSv1.3 connection and use specific ciphersuites with the command line s_client client from the OpenSSL project. With OpenSSL 1.1.1 you can use TLSv1.3. This guide covers the installation of OpenSSL 1.1.1 on Ubuntu, testing the connection to a server  and specific ciphersuites. It also covers the big differences between TLSv1.3 and lower.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL command line Root and Intermediate CA including OCSP, CRL and revocation</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL_and_revocation.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL_and_revocation.html</guid>
                <description>These are quick and dirty notes on generating a certificate authority (CA), intermediate certificate authorities and end certificates using the OpenSSL command line tools. It includes OCSP, CRL and CA Issuer information and specific issue and expiry dates. We'll set up our own root CA. We'll use the root CA to generate an example intermediate CA. We'll use the intermediate CA to sign end user certificates.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypt and decrypt files to public keys via the OpenSSL Command Line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypt_and_decrypt_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypt_and_decrypt_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial will show you how to use the openssl command line to encrypt and decrypt a file using a public key. We will first generate a random key, encrypt that random key against the public key of the other person and use that random key to encrypt the actual file with using symmetric encryption.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Let's Encrypt with DirectAdmin or other Web Control Panels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin.html</guid>
                <description>Let's Encrypt is a new certificate authority, recognized by all major browsers. They make it a breeze to set up TLS certificates for your web server. And for free! Let's Encrypt is supported by major players like Mozilla, Akamai, Cisco, the EFF, the Internet Security Research Group and others. Let's Encrypt provides free, automatic and secure certificates so that every website can be secured with an SSL certificate. This article shows you how to setup Let's Encrypt with the DirectAdmin web control panel. The guide is generic, so it works for other controlpanels as well. For now it works with the beta, and required some linux knowledge and root access to the hosting server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Let's Encrypt with DirectAdmin, now built in!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin_Now_Built_In.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin_Now_Built_In.html</guid>
                <description>Let's Encrypt is a new certificate authority, recognized by all major browsers. They make it a breeze to set up TLS certificates for your web server. And for free! Let's Encrypt is supported by major players like Mozilla, Akamai, Cisco, the EFF, the Internet Security Research Group and others. Let's Encrypt provides free, automatic and secure certificates so that every website can be secured with an SSL certificate. This article shows you how to setup Let's Encrypt with the DirectAdmin web control panel. DirectAdmin now supports Lets Encrypt natively since 1.50, so no more ssh fiddling, just via the control panel, for all the users on the server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Sign and verify text/files to public keys via the OpenSSL Command Line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Sign_and_verify_text_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Sign_and_verify_text_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</guid>
                <description>This small guide will shows you how to use the OpenSSL Command Line to sign a file, and how to verify the signing of this file. You can do this to prove ownership of a key, or to prove that a file hasn't been modified since you signed it. This works both with small text files as well as huge photo's, documents or PDF files.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Manually verify a certificate against a CRL</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_manually_verify_a_certificate_against_a_CRL.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_manually_verify_a_certificate_against_a_CRL.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to manually verfify a certificate against a CRL. CRL stands for Certificate Revocation List and is one way to validate a certificate status. It is an alternative to the OCSP, Online Certificate Status Protocol.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Manually verify a certificate against an OCSP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_Manually_Verify_a_certificate_against_an_OCSP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_Manually_Verify_a_certificate_against_an_OCSP.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to manually verfify a certificate against an OCSP server. OCSP stands for the Online Certificate Status Protocol and is one way to validate a certificate status. It is an alternative to the CRL, certificate revocation list. This article shows you how to manually validate a certificate against an OCSP server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Get all certificates from a website in plain text</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to get all certificates of a website in plain text. With a few OpenSSL commands one can get the website certificate plus intermediate certificates, however, if you feed that output to OpenSSL it only works on the first certificate. Using a bit of sed and bash magic we can feed all certificates one by one to OpenSSL.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ejabberd SSL Certificate</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_SSL_Certificate.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_SSL_Certificate.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up an SSL Certificate for use with Ejabberd. It covers both the creation of the Certificate Signing Request, the preparing of the certificate for use with Ejabberd and the installation of the certificate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    