<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag cgroups on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/cgroups.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag cgroups on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/cgroups.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Limit specific process memory on desktop linux with cgroups and earlyoom</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Limit_specific_process_memory_on_desktop_linux_with_cgroups.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Limit_specific_process_memory_on_desktop_linux_with_cgroups.html</guid>
                <description>On my laptop I recently had trouble with out of memory issues when running `clion`, `firefox`, `thunderbird`, `teams` and a virtualbox VM. To combat this, I've setup cgroups to limit how much RAM specific applications can use and configured `earlyoom`, a very nifty tool that checks available memory and kills the process with the highest `oom_score` if available memory falls below 5%. Otherwise, my laptop would first grind to a halt (even without swap) and only after half an hour of seemingly being stuck would the OOM killer kick in. With `earlyoom` this hanging behavior is gone, although sometimes applications get killed when I don't expect it. I've given firefox, thunderbird and teams a cgroup with memory limit and clion and virtualbox use their own configuration to limit their RAM usage.This post details how to setup `cgroups` to limit memory of specific processes including automatically placing process inside a cgroup.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Linux Containers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Linux_Containers.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Linux_Containers.html</guid>
                <description>This article goes over Linux Containers. It touches both bare linux cgroups and namespaces and goes over LXC (linux conrainers).</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    