<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag chef on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/chef.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag chef on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/chef.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: overwrite templates in wrapper-cookbooks</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chef_-_overwrite_templates_in_wrapper_cookbooks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chef_-_overwrite_templates_in_wrapper_cookbooks.html</guid>
                <description>This article describes how to use a template in a wrapper-cookbook in Chef. The Chef Cookbook Wrapper Pattern is based upon a design convention where you customize an existing library cookbook by using a separate wrapper cookbook, which wraps the original cookbook with any related configuration changes. a library cookbook is an existing cookbook, typically an open-source contribution from a user in the Chef community, designed for server configuration purposes. A wrapper cookbook is a cookbook that wraps the original library cookbook with custom modifications or additions such as overriding a Chef attribute, changing a Chef template, converting a Chef attribute to a user-definable input, etc. To override a template by just defining it again would result in it being written two times every Chef run, which is not what we want. Using this method, you can override the template from the default cookbook with a template in your wrapper-cookbook. It has an example for the graphite cookbook, where the wrapper ads LDAP login to the Apache server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: chef_gem vs gem_package and ORDER</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chef_-_chef_gem_vs_gem_package_and_ORDER.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chef_-_chef_gem_vs_gem_package_and_ORDER.html</guid>
                <description>This article describes a situation I had at one of my clients with Chef and the steps took to resolve this problem. They have a cookbook which builds a postgresql database node and it installs the pg ruby gem. However, it uses the chef_gem resource to do that, and it keeps failing.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: search in recipe based on roles or recipes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_search_in_recipe_on_roles_or_recipes.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_search_in_recipe_on_roles_or_recipes.html</guid>
                <description>Chef supports a very powerfull search syntax which allows you for example to search all nodes with the graphite-server role and get their IP addresses. This tutorial shows you how to search based on a role a node has or a recipe a node has, plus an example config file with erb syntax. It has an example cookbook which sets up collectd as client and graphite as server. It shows you how to use the search function of Chef to get the IP addresses of the graphite servers and place those in the collectd config files. This technique is applicable to all kinds of services that use a client-server model, for example, munin, haproxy, zabbix and many more.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chef: include_recipe only_if or not_if</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_include_recipe_only_if_not_if.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Chef_include_recipe_only_if_not_if.html</guid>
                <description>Chef supports including other recipes in cookbooks, for example, I can include the MySQL recipe from a PHP recipe. However, this is not a normal resource but a normal method. Therefore it ignores anything passed to it, including only_if or not_if. This tutorial shows you how to include or not include a recipe based on a variable, comparable with not_if or only_if.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Uninstall and Remove OSSEC</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial shows you how to remove an OSSEC installation. OSSEC is installed from source (via a script), so you have to remove all the things manually instead of with your package manager.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - pure ssh based configuration management and deployment</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will get you started with Ansible. Ansible is a radically simple model-driven configuration management, deployment, and command execution framework. Other tools in this space have been too complicated for too long, require too much bootstrapping, and have too much learning curve. By comparison, Ansible is dead simple and painless to extend. Puppet and Chef have about 60k lines of code. Ansibles core is a little over 2000 lines.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    