<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag chrome on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/chrome.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag chrome on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/chrome.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Firefox 89 Proton UI Tab Styling</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Firefox-89-proton-ui-tab-styling.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Firefox-89-proton-ui-tab-styling.html</guid>
                <description>Firefox 89 recently came out with a 'new' user interface (named proton). I'm not a fan of change because UX/UI people need to make it seem like their job is relevant. Also, the picture they show under the headline '17 billion clicks...' only scares the crap out of me, tracking every move a user makes in their browser seems to me to be a bad idea, but hey, lets see how long Mozilla can continue their war against their own users. Since the `about:config` flag to disable proton will probably be gone in a few releases I thought, why not try to get used to this new interface. It's so enormous and wide, lacking contrast. As you might have guessed, I cannot get used to the tab bar, so in this post I'll show you how to use the `userChrome.css` file to make the new tab bar look a bit more like the old tab bar. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Lets talk about changelogs, or, how I loathe 'bugfixes and performance improvements'</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Rant_Lets_talk_about_changelogs.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Rant_Lets_talk_about_changelogs.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short personal rant to start the new year off. When you're a multi billion dollar company with more software developers than you'd ever need, how on earth is it possible that your public changelog in an app store is just 'bugfixes and performance improvements'? If that is all you're going to put there, then just leave it blank. Or be honest and put 'We can't be arsed to fill this in' there. For me as a technical user it's not actionable, and your non technical users are not going to read that page anyway.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I had to jailbreak my iPhone to change the default browser...</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_had_to_jailbreak_my_iPhone_to_change_the_default_browser.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_had_to_jailbreak_my_iPhone_to_change_the_default_browser.html</guid>
                <description>The title of this article says enough. To change the default browser on an iOS device you need to jailbreak your device (root it). It's 2020 and Apple does not allow you to switch Safari with Firefox. Recently a new jailbreak for iOS was released which support the lastest firmware, 13.5. I currently have an iPhone SE 2020 running 13.5, the jailbreak was a welcome addition to fix some small and some big annoyances with iOS. Like switching to Firefox as default browser. This post contains both a small rant on the state of iOS as wel as links to the jailbreak and applications used to switch the default browser.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Dark Reader, dark mode for any website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Dark_Reader_dark_mode_for_any_website.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Dark_Reader_dark_mode_for_any_website.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I discovered a firefox extension that converts any website into a dark version. Works both on firefox for mobile and on the desktop (and all other major browsers), is open source, causes less strain on the eyes and improves battery life. Just as the earlier post on Blokada, I find this such a cool piece of software I wanted to share it with all my readers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install Ubuntu Linux on the LG Chromebase</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/LG_Chromebase_Linux.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/LG_Chromebase_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>I recently acquired the LG Chromebase 22CV241-W. It is an All in One type machine with Chrome OS. The hardware, excluding the screen and lack of battery, is largely the same as the Acer C720. Of course I removed Chrome OS and installed a real Linux on it, of which you'll find instructions below. In my case it is Ubuntu Mate. Arch Linux also works fine, but this was for someone else, so a more beginner friendly distro seemed to be a better choise. This article will cover the removal of Chrome OS and the installation of Ubuntu Mate on the LG Chromebase.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chrome Extensions for Privacy, Adblocking and anti-tracking</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chrome-extensions-for-privacy.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chrome-extensions-for-privacy.html</guid>
                <description>This is a list with extensions for google chrome which help you block tracking and ads, and help you protect your privacy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    