<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag cluster on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/cluster.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag cluster on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/cluster.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Nitrokey HSM/SmartCard-HSM and Raspberry Pi web cluster</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_HSM_web_cluster.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_HSM_web_cluster.html</guid>
                <description>This article sets up a Nitrokey HSM/SmartCard-HSM web cluster and has a lot of benchmarks. This specific HSM is not a fast HSM since it's very inexpensive and targeted at secure key storage, not performance. But, what if you do want more performance? Then you scale horizontally, just add some more HSM's and a loadbalancer in front. The cluster consists of Raspberry Pi's and Nitrokey HSM's and SmartCard-HSM's, softwarewise we use Apache, mod_nss and haproxy. We benchmark a small HTML file and a Wordpress site, with a regular 4096 bit RSA certificate without using the HSM's, a regular 2048 bit RSA certificate without using the HSM's, a 2048 bit RSA certificate in the HSM, a 1024 bit RSA certificate in the HSM and an EC prime256v1 key in the HSM. We do these benchmarks with the `OpenSC` module and with the `sc-hsm-embedded` module to see if that makes any difference.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack - (Manually) migrating (KVM) Nova compute virtual machines</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_-_(Manually)_migrating_(KVM)_Nova_Compute_Virtual_Machines.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_-_(Manually)_migrating_(KVM)_Nova_Compute_Virtual_Machines.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to migrate KVM virtual machines with the  Openstack Nova compute service, either manually or with the Openstack tooling. Openstack provides a few different ways to migrate virtual machines from one compute node to another. Each option has different requirements and restrictions, for example, you can't live-migrate without shared storage. You can't live-migrate if you have a configdrive enabled. You can't select the target host if you use the nova migrate (non-live) command etc. This article describes the most common migration scenario's including live and manual migration using native linux tools.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Affinity Groups, make sure instances are on the same or different compute hypervisor hosts</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_Affinity_Groups-make-sure-instances-are-on-the-same-or-a-different-hypervisor-host.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_Affinity_Groups-make-sure-instances-are-on-the-same-or-a-different-hypervisor-host.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to use Openstack Affinity groups. Affinity or Anti-Affinity groups allow you to make sure instances (VM/VPS) are on the same hypervisor host or on a different one. There are cases when you want two instances on different compute nodes, for example, when they are clustered servers like a load balancer or a database master-master setup. All VMs in each Affinity group are hosted in the same hypervisor, while no two VMs of a same Anti-Affinity group are hosted in the same hypervisor.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Keepalived notify script, execute action on failover</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived_notify_script_execute_action_on_failover.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived_notify_script_execute_action_on_failover.html</guid>
                <description>Keepalived supports running scripts on VRRP state change. This can come in handy when you need to execute an action when a failover occurs. In my case, I have a VPN running on a Virtual IP and want to make sure the VPN only runs on the node with the Virtual IP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Simple keepalived failover setup on Ubuntu 14.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived-Simple-IP-failover-on-Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived-Simple-IP-failover-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to set up very simple keepalived IP failover on Ubuntu 14.04. Keepalived is a piece of software which can be used to achieve high availability by assigning two or more nodes a virtual IP and monitoring those nodes, failing over when one goes down.  Keepalived can do more, like load balancing and monitoring, but this tutorial focusses on a very simple setup, just IP failover.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Corosync Pacemaker - Execute script on failover</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Corosync_Pacemaker_-_Execute_a_script_on_failover.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Corosync_Pacemaker_-_Execute_a_script_on_failover.html</guid>
                <description>With Corosync/Pacemaker there is no easy way to simply run a script on failover. There are good reasons for this, but sometimes you want to do something simple. This tutorial describes how to change the Dummy OCF resource to execute a script on failover.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Corosync Notes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Corosync_Notes.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Corosync_Notes.html</guid>
                <description>These are my notes and command snippets for usage with Corosync.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up your own distributed, redundant, and encrypted storage grid with Tahoe-LAFS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tahoe_LAFS_Storage_Grid.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tahoe_LAFS_Storage_Grid.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers the installation and configuration of Tahoe/LAFS, a distributed, encrypted and redundant storage clustering grid.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    