<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag codewars on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/codewars.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag codewars on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/codewars.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>std::accumulate in C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_std_accumulate.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_std_accumulate.html</guid>
                <description>I'm using codewars to practice my development skills. Today I found out about the std::accumulate method in C++ while doing an exercise there. I'm sharing it here because I never heard of it before. It is the numeric header, and it also accepts a custom binary function to apply instead of operator+. This snippet shows some examples including a lambda operator and the for loop you would use otherwise.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Weight for Weight, a coding exercise that kept me busy</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Weight_for_Weight_a_coding_exersize_that_kept_me_busy.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Weight_for_Weight_a_coding_exersize_that_kept_me_busy.html</guid>
                <description>I'm using codewars to practice my development skills. The exercise I was working on the past couple of days was a level higher than the 'rank' codewars gives me, so a more difficult exercise. Using the sparse free time I have, this kata took a bit longer to complete, and had me thinking about the problem when I was not doing the exercise. If a problem fascinates me that way, I can't stop thinking about it until I've solved it. In this article I'll walk you through my work on this kata.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>std::string to lowercase or uppercase in C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/std_string_to_lowercase_or_uppercase_in_cpp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/std_string_to_lowercase_or_uppercase_in_cpp.html</guid>
                <description>I'm using codewars to practice my development skills. Today I learned a method to transform a std::string's casing, either to uppercase or lowercase. Researching it further, I also found out how to do unicode strings with boost. This article also includes a mini howto on installing Boost on Windows 10 via mingw for use with CLion.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    