<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag configuration-management on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/configuration-management.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag configuration-management on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/configuration-management.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do action if on specific distribution (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS or RHEL) or distribution version (ubuntu precise, ubuntu trusty)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if you are on a certain distribution. You might have a mixed environment with CentOS and Debian and when using Ansible to execute actions on nodes you don't need to run Yum on Debian, or Apt on CentOS. Some package names are different and such, so this helps you with an only if statement to select a specific distribution. As a bonus, you also get an only_if for specific distribution versions, like Ubuntu precise (12.04 LTS) or Ubuntu trusty (14.04 LTS).</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if a file exists or does not exist</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_a_file_exists_or_does_not_exist.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_a_file_exists_or_does_not_exist.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if a file exists or does not exist. If you for example have a command you need to run to generate a certificate (or Diffie Hellman parameters for nginx) you only want to do that once. The command itself is not convergent so it will run with every ansible run. However, the command creates a file and Ansible is able to check if that file exists. If the file exists, it will not execute the action. The same goes for checking if a file does exist and only executing the action if it exists. (The action you want to do will remove that file).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if host is also in other hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet helps you execute actions only when a host is in another hostgroup in Ansible. For example, you might deploy munin-node via ansible, but you only want your apache and NGINX plugins deployed on your webservers, not on your database servers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Playbook Testing</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible article shows you how to run a basic test on your playbooks to check if their syntax is correct. It shows methods for both Ansible 1.3 and 1.4. When you get more complicated Ansible playbooks you sometimes have syntax (YAML) errors in them. It sometimes can take a while before those errors show up because they are lower in a playbook. By running the syntax check you make sure this won't happen.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do something if another action changed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how execute actions only if another action has changed. For example, a playbook which downloads a remote key for package signing but only executes the apt-add command if the key has changed. Or a playbook which clones a git repository and only restarts a service if the git repository has changed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Sudo sometimes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how run some actions via sudo and some not. It also shows you how to run an entire role via sudo or not.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - sudoers safety and sanity checking in playbook</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</guid>
                <description>Using Ansible to manage the /etc/sudoers file is fine, except when you have a syntax error in your template. This method helps you to only deploy a correct sudoers file.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - pure ssh based configuration management and deployment</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will get you started with Ansible. Ansible is a radically simple model-driven configuration management, deployment, and command execution framework. Other tools in this space have been too complicated for too long, require too much bootstrapping, and have too much learning curve. By comparison, Ansible is dead simple and painless to extend. Puppet and Chef have about 60k lines of code. Ansibles core is a little over 2000 lines.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    