<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag configuration-management on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/configuration-management.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag configuration-management on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/configuration-management.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>A way to run Ansible 2.19 on old operating systems like Ubuntu 18.04 with working Apt</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ansible_2.19_on_old_ubuntu_18.04_with_working_apt.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ansible_2.19_on_old_ubuntu_18.04_with_working_apt.html</guid>
                <description>Ansible recently stopped working on one of my older servers. The playbooks wouldn't execute anymore, with a cryptic python error. With Ansible 2.14 this server worked, after upgrading to 2.19 the playbooks failed.
It turned out that the Python version on the server was too old. This server runs Ubuntu 18.04, that ships with Python 3.6. That server still gets updates via Canonicals Ubuntu Pro program, but no more major python version upgrades.
I manually installed Python 3.12, after which the Ansible playbook started working again, only failing to do stuff via `apt`. For example the `package`, `apt_key` and `apt_repository` modules. I've found a workaround for package installation by using ansible's `raw` commands.
This post shows how to manually install newer Python and the trick I'm using to (idompotently) get package installation working again with a few `when` rules.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 23:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 23:08:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do action if on specific distribution (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS or RHEL) or distribution version (ubuntu precise, ubuntu trusty)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</guid>
                <description>This ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if you are on a certain distribution. You might have a mixed environment with CentOS and Debian, when using ansible to execute actions on different servers you don't need to run yum on debian, or apt on CentOS. Some package names are different and such, so this helps you with a when statement to select a specific distribution. As a bonus, you also get a when for specific distribution versions, like Ubuntu precise (12.04 LTS) or Ubuntu trusty (14.04 LTS).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do something if another action changed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how execute actions only if another action has changed. For example, a playbook which downloads a remote key for package signing but only executes the apt-add command if the key has changed. Or a playbook which clones a git repository and only restarts a service if the git repository has changed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>log_vcs - Ansible callback plugin that creates VCS (git) branches for every Ansible run</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/log_vcs_-_Ansible_Callback_plugin_that_creates_git_branches_for_every_ansible_run.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/log_vcs_-_Ansible_Callback_plugin_that_creates_git_branches_for_every_ansible_run.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible callback plugin creates a VCS branch every time you run Ansible. If you ever need to go back to a certain state or environment, check out that branch and be sure nothing has changed. This is useful when you have multiple environments or multiple people deploying and continually develop your Ansible. When you often deploy to test / acceptance and less often to production, you can checkout the last branch that deployed to production if a hotfix or other maintenance is required, without having to search back in your commits and logs. I would recommend to develop infrastructure features in feature branches and have the master branch always deployable to production. However, reality learns that that is not always the case and this is a nice automatic way to have a fallback.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if a file exists or does not exist</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_a_file_exists_or_does_not_exist.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_a_file_exists_or_does_not_exist.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if a file exists or does not exist. If you for example have a command you need to run to generate a certificate (or Diffie Hellman parameters for nginx) you only want to do that once. The command itself is not convergent so it will run with every ansible run. However, the command creates a file and Ansible is able to check if that file exists. If the file exists, it will not execute the action. The same goes for checking if a file does exist and only executing the action if it exists. (The action you want to do will remove that file).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if host is also in other hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet helps you execute actions only when a host is in another hostgroup in Ansible. For example, you might deploy munin-node via ansible, but you only want your apache and NGINX plugins deployed on your webservers, not on your database servers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Playbook Testing</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible article shows you how to run a basic test on your playbooks to check if their syntax is correct. It shows methods for both Ansible 1.3 and 1.4. When you get more complicated Ansible playbooks you sometimes have syntax (YAML) errors in them. It sometimes can take a while before those errors show up because they are lower in a playbook. By running the syntax check you make sure this won't happen.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Sudo sometimes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how run some actions via sudo and some not. It also shows you how to run an entire role via sudo or not.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - sudoers safety and sanity checking in playbook</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</guid>
                <description>Using Ansible to manage the /etc/sudoers file is fine, except when you have a syntax error in your template. This method helps you to only deploy a correct sudoers file.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - pure ssh based configuration management and deployment</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will get you started with Ansible. Ansible is a radically simple model-driven configuration management, deployment, and command execution framework. Other tools in this space have been too complicated for too long, require too much bootstrapping, and have too much learning curve. By comparison, Ansible is dead simple and painless to extend. Puppet and Chef have about 60k lines of code. Ansibles core is a little over 2000 lines.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    