<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag cookies on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/cookies.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag cookies on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/cookies.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>CookieNumberPrinter, incremental / idle game style numbers in C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/CookieNumberPrinter_incremental_game_style_numbers.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/CookieNumberPrinter_incremental_game_style_numbers.html</guid>
                <description>To level up my software development skills, I'm programming a command line game in my spare  time.  It is a clone of the famous cookieclicker game by ortiel. A clone of a game is simple enough to get up and running  fairly quickly, but also extensible enough when needed. How do you store huge score numbers  when they don't fit in a long long? How do you write a game loop, how to use threads to handle  user input? Saving a game (how to design a proper save format)? Also a great way to learn about project organization, software architecture and to try out design patterns. As the game is a clone of CookieCliker, which itself is an incremental game, I had to figure out how to work with large numbers. Since this is not a university math project, I allowed myself the luxury of using Boosts Multiprecision.  The library handles the large numbers, including caluclation and operations with such a number. I did want to print the numbers in Idle Style, where large numbers are displayed with a suffix, like '1 million' instead of '1000000' and so on. This 'C++' class can be used to print Boost's 'cpp_dec_float' numbers in incremental style. It's just one header.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: intercept all cookies and set secure attribute</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_intercept_all_cookies_and_set_secure_attribute.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_intercept_all_cookies_and_set_secure_attribute.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to use haproxy to set the secure attribute on cookies. You might have a backend application which is not able to set the secure attribute on cookies or for which haproxy does the ssl offloading. This simple frontend rspirep sets the secure attribute for all cookies.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    