<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag crl on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/crl.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag crl on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/crl.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL command line Root and Intermediate CA including OCSP, CRL and revocation</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL and_revocation.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL and_revocation.html</guid>
                <description>These are quick and dirty notes on generating a certificate authority (CA), intermediate certificate authorities and end certificates using the OpenSSL command line tools. It includes OCSP, CRL and CA Issuer information and specific issue and expiry dates. We'll set up our own root CA. We'll use the root CA to generate an example intermediate CA. We'll use the intermediate CA to sign end user certificates.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Manually verify a certificate against a CRL</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_manually_verify_a_certificate_against_a_CRL.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_manually_verify_a_certificate_against_a_CRL.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to manually verfify a certificate against a CRL. CRL stands for Certificate Revocation List and is one way to validate a certificate status. It is an alternative to the OCSP, Online Certificate Status Protocol.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Manually verify a certificate against an OCSP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_Manually_Verify_a_certificate_against_an_OCSP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_Manually_Verify_a_certificate_against_an_OCSP.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to manually verfify a certificate against an OCSP server. OCSP stands for the Online Certificate Status Protocol and is one way to validate a certificate status. It is an alternative to the CRL, certificate revocation list. This article shows you how to manually validate a certificate against an OCSP server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Get all certificates from a website in plain text</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to get all certificates of a website in plain text. With a few OpenSSL commands one can get the website certificate plus intermediate certificates, however, if you feed that output to OpenSSL it only works on the first certificate. Using a bit of sed and bash magic we can feed all certificates one by one to OpenSSL.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OCSP Stapling on Apache</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_Apache2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_Apache2.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up OCSP stapling on Apache. OCSP stapling is an enhancement to the standard OCSP protocol that delivers OCSP responses from the server with the certificate, eliminating the need for relying parties (web users) to check OCSP responses with the issuing CA. This has the effect of reducing bandwidth, improving perceived site performance, and increasing security for everyone involved in establishing the secure session.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OCSP Stapling on nginx</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_nginx.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_nginx.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up OCSP stapling on nginx. OCSP stapling is an enhancement to the standard OCSP protocol that delivers OCSP responses from the server with the certificate, eliminating the need for relying parties (web users) to check OCSP responses with the issuing CA. This has the effect of reducing bandwidth, improving perceived site performance, and increasing security for everyone involved in establishing the secure session.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check CRL expiry in minutes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_CRL_expiry.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_CRL_expiry.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin which you can use to check if a CRL (Certificate Revocation List, public list with revoked certificates) is still valid.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    