<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag cryptoki on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/cryptoki.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag cryptoki on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/cryptoki.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Nitrokey HSM/SmartCard-HSM and Raspberry Pi web cluster</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_HSM_web_cluster.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_HSM_web_cluster.html</guid>
                <description>This article sets up a Nitrokey HSM/SmartCard-HSM web cluster and has a lot of benchmarks. This specific HSM is not a fast HSM since it's very inexpensive and targeted at secure key storage, not performance. But, what if you do want more performance? Then you scale horizontally, just add some more HSM's and a loadbalancer in front. The cluster consists of Raspberry Pi's and Nitrokey HSM's and SmartCard-HSM's, softwarewise we use Apache, `mod_nss` and haproxy. We benchmark a small HTML file and a Wordpress site, with a regular 4096 bit RSA certificate without using the HSM's, a regular 2048 bit RSA certificate without using the HSM's, a 2048 bit RSA certificate in the HSM, a 1024 bit RSA certificate in the HSM and an EC prime256v1 key in the HSM. We do these benchmarks with the `OpenSC` module and with the `sc-hsm-embedded` module to see if that makes any difference.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Storing arbitraty data in the Nitrokey HSM/SmartCard-HSM with Elementary Files (EF)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Storing_arbitraty_data_in_the_Nitrokey_HSM.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Storing_arbitraty_data_in_the_Nitrokey_HSM.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide which shows you how to write small elementary files to a nitrokey HSM. This can be usefull if you want to securely store data protected by a user pin. You can enter the wrong pin only three times, so offline brute forcing is out of the picture.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Use the Nitrokey HSM or SmartCard-HSM with sc-hsm-embedded, mod_nss and Apache (read only module)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Use_the_Nitrokey_HSM_or_SmartCard-HSM_with_sc-hsm-embedded_mod_nss_and_Apache_read_only_module.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Use_the_Nitrokey_HSM_or_SmartCard-HSM_with_sc-hsm-embedded_mod_nss_and_Apache_read_only_module.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on using the Nitrokey HSM with sc-hsm-embedded module instead of the PC/SC daemon and OpenSC, mod_nss and the Apache webserver. This is an extension on the earlier guide, with new benchmarks. The sc-hsm-embedded module is not using a global lock like OpenSC, therefore providing better performance. The sc-hsm-embedded module is also a read only module, suitable for embedded systems or secure systems. The HSM allows you to store the private key for a SSL certificate inside the HSM (instead of on the filesystem), so that it can never leave the device and thus never be stolen. The guide covers the installation of the sc-hsm-embedded module, configuration of and benchmarks from Apache with the HSM and different key sizes.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Decrypt/Extract Nitrokey HSM/SmartCard-HSM RSA private keys</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Decrypt_NitroKey_HSM_or_SmartCard-HSM_private_keys.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Decrypt_NitroKey_HSM_or_SmartCard-HSM_private_keys.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide which shows you how to extract private RSA key material from the Nitrokey HSM / SmartCard-HSM using the DKEK. This way you can get the private key out of the HSM in an unencrypted form. It does require access to the HSM device, all the DKEK share and their passwords. Do note that doing this defeats the entire purpose of a HSM, namely that you never have access to the keys. In the article I'll go over some explanation why this might be a feature you need and why it might be a case of security over convinience.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Use the Nitrokey HSM or SmartCard-HSM with mod_nss and Apache</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_HSM_in_Apache_with_mod_nss.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_HSM_in_Apache_with_mod_nss.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on using the Nitrokey HSM with mod_nss and the Apache webserver. The HSM allows you to store the private key for a SSL certificate inside the HSM (instead of on the filesystem), so that it can never leave the device and thus never be stolen. The guide covers the installation and configuration of mod_nss, coupling the HSM to NSS, generating the keys and configuring Apache, and last but not least we also do some benchmarks on Apache with the HSM and different key sizes.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get started with the Nitrokey HSM or SmartCard-HSM</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Get_Started_With_The_Nitrokey_HSM.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Get_Started_With_The_Nitrokey_HSM.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide to get started with the Nitrokey HSM (or SmartCard-HSM). It covers what a HSM is and what it can be used for. It also goes over software installation and initializing the device, including backups of the device and the keys. Finally we do some actual crypto operatons via pkcs11, OpenSSL, Apache and OpenSSH. We also cover usage in Thunderbird (S/MIME), Elementary Files (EF), a Web cluster with Apache and mod_nss and the decryption of the keys.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    