<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag deb on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/deb.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag deb on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/deb.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>A way to run Ansible 2.19 on old operating systems like Ubuntu 18.04 with working Apt</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ansible_2.19_on_old_ubuntu_18.04_with_working_apt.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ansible_2.19_on_old_ubuntu_18.04_with_working_apt.html</guid>
                <description>Ansible recently stopped working on one of my older servers. The playbooks wouldn't execute anymore, with a cryptic python error. With Ansible 2.14 this server worked, after upgrading to 2.19 the playbooks failed.
It turned out that the Python version on the server was too old. This server runs Ubuntu 18.04, that ships with Python 3.6. That server still gets updates via Canonicals Ubuntu Pro program, but no more major python version upgrades.
I manually installed Python 3.12, after which the Ansible playbook started working again, only failing to do stuff via `apt`. For example the `package`, `apt_key` and `apt_repository` modules. I've found a workaround for package installation by using ansible's `raw` commands.
This post shows how to manually install newer Python and the trick I'm using to (idompotently) get package installation working again with a few `when` rules.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 23:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 23:08:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>All packages that were present in Ubuntu 18.04 but absent in Ubuntu 20.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/All_packages_that_were_present_in_Ubuntu_18.04_but_removed_in_20.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/All_packages_that_were_present_in_Ubuntu_18.04_but_removed_in_20.04.html</guid>
                <description>Otherwise titled `Figure out the differences between two apt repositories`. Recently I've had a few packages that I often use but were missing from Ubuntu 20.04 LTS. One is [ckermit](/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_CKermit_as_a_snap_for_Ubuntu_20.04.html) and the other is [gnash](/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html), both of which I 'converted' to a snap. (In air quotes because I just converted the 18.04 deb). This made me wonder if I could figure out a list of that are present in Ubuntu 18.04, but absent in Ubuntu 20.04. As `apt` and `dpkg` are standardized tools and and package formats, we can use a few shell tools to parse the package lists and compare them side by side.
This post shows you how to do the comparison yourself and I discuss the removed packages a bit. Some are version increments (like `gcc-6` in Ubuntu 18.04 but `gcc-7`in Ubuntu 20.04),  and some are packages that were combined into one instead of split up  (like `ltsp` in Ubuntu 20.04 but a bunch of seperate `ltsp-$postfix` packages instead  in Ubuntu 18.04). Many others are just replaced by newer versions (`python-ceph` vs `python3-ceph`). The list of differences is provided as a download, both ways.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I've packaged up CKermit as a snap, for Ubuntu 20.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_CKermit_as_a_snap_for_Ubuntu_20.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_CKermit_as_a_snap_for_Ubuntu_20.04.html</guid>
                <description>Last year I packaged up [gnash as a snap](/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html) because it was missing from the Ubuntu 20.04 apt repositories. Recently I found out that `ckermit` is also not in Ubuntu 20.04, as far as I can tell because it wasn't in the Debian repositories when the Ubuntu 20.04 initial sync happened. Which is very inconvenient for an LTS release.
I often use `ckermit` to connect to our hardware via a script, to automatically boot from NFS (via u-boot). I could do that manually via `screen` or `minicom`, but I have a `kermit` script that does it for me, which is very convenient. Since the snapping of `gnash` was so easy, I decided to do it for `ckermit` as well, since I now know how to convert deb packages to snaps. I also have a few colleagues who also use those kermit scripts and are going to update to 20.04 in the (near) future.
The snap packaging is based on work by Phil Roche, he wrote about re-packaging older debian packages with an Ubuntu 18.04/16.04 base layer as a snap. My `ckermit` package is confined (no `--classic` needed), the source code for the snap is on my github and on any snap-enabled distro you can now 'snap install ckermit-raymii' to enjoy CKermit.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I've packaged up Gnash as a snap, for modern linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html</guid>
                <description>I hate snaps just as much as the next guy but last week I did something unexpected. I packaged up Gnash as a snap.  Gnash is a GNU flash media player, not updated since 2011, and  thus removed from the Ubuntu 20.04 repositories. The snap packaging is based on work by phil roche, he wrote about re-packaging older debian packages with an Ubuntu 18.04/16.04 base layer as a snap. My gnash package is confined (no '--classic' needed), the source code for the snap is on my github and on any snap-enabled distro you can now 'snap install gnash-raymii' to enjoy Gnash again.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Building opkg .ipk packages by hand (for OpenEmbedded/Yocto/OpenWRT)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Building_IPK_packages_by_hand.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Building_IPK_packages_by_hand.html</guid>
                <description>.ipk packages are used by a variety of embedded linux systems, like routers running OpenWRT and appliances running on OpenEmbedded (Yocto). The opkg command installs these packages and OpenEmbedded comes with a set of tools to build .ipk packages. Recently I had to create ipk packages in a scripted fashion for a few hundred systems, all unique per system. The .ipk packages includes a few software changes for debugging, a systemd service and one precompiled binary. The yocto build tools were not available on the machine where these packages would be made so I had to figure out how to make them by hand, which means, automatically. The packages are actually just compressed files containing a few control files and the data to be extracted on the filesystem. This article will walk you through the steps of creating these packages by hand.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do action if on specific distribution (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS or RHEL) or distribution version (ubuntu precise, ubuntu trusty)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</guid>
                <description>This ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if you are on a certain distribution. You might have a mixed environment with CentOS and Debian, when using ansible to execute actions on different servers you don't need to run yum on debian, or apt on CentOS. Some package names are different and such, so this helps you with a when statement to select a specific distribution. As a bonus, you also get a when for specific distribution versions, like Ubuntu precise (12.04 LTS) or Ubuntu trusty (14.04 LTS).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Add an apt-repository on Debian and Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Add_an_apt-repository_on_Debian_and_Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Add_an_apt-repository_on_Debian_and_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide that shows you how to add an apt repository to Debian and Ubuntu using Ansible. It includes both the old way, when the apt modules only worked on Ubuntu, and the new way, now that the apt-modules also support Debian, plus some other tricks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Packages</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Software_packages.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Software_packages.html</guid>
                <description>Some software I encounter does not have a debian .deb package available. Via the ./configure, make, sudo checkinstall I compile them into a package and put it up here for download.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    