<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag directadmin on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/directadmin.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag directadmin on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/directadmin.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Let's Encrypt with DirectAdmin, now built in!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin_Now_Built_In.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin_Now_Built_In.html</guid>
                <description>Let's Encrypt is a new certificate authority, recognized by all major browsers. They make it a breeze to set up TLS certificates for your web server. And for free! Let's Encrypt is supported by major players like Mozilla, Akamai, Cisco, the EFF, the Internet Security Research Group and others. Let's Encrypt provides free, automatic and secure certificates so that every website can be secured with an SSL certificate. This article shows you how to setup Let's Encrypt with the DirectAdmin web control panel. DirectAdmin now supports Lets Encrypt natively since 1.50, so no more ssh fiddling, just via the control panel, for all the users on the server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Let's Encrypt with DirectAdmin or other Web Control Panels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Lets_Encrypt_Directadmin.html</guid>
                <description>Let's Encrypt is a new certificate authority, recognized by all major browsers. They make it a breeze to set up TLS certificates for your web server. And for free! Let's Encrypt is supported by major players like Mozilla, Akamai, Cisco, the EFF, the Internet Security Research Group and others. Let's Encrypt provides free, automatic and secure certificates so that every website can be secured with an SSL certificate. This article shows you how to setup Let's Encrypt with the DirectAdmin web control panel. The guide is generic, so it works for other controlpanels as well. For now it works with the beta, and required some linux knowledge and root access to the hosting server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove Installatron from a (Directadmin) server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Remove_Installatron_from_a_(Directadmin)_server.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Remove_Installatron_from_a_(Directadmin)_server.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short guide which shows you how to remove Installatron from a server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Configserver Firewall and Security (CSF and LFD)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Configserver_Firewall_and_Security_CSF_LFD.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Configserver_Firewall_and_Security_CSF_LFD.html</guid>
                <description>his page covers my notes about csf and lfd. csf is an easy SPI iptables firewall suite. lfd is the login failure daemon, which scans log files for failed authentication and blocks the IP's doing that. This page covers installation, populair command line options and popular config file options.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Owncloud, DirectAdmin, Apache 2.4 and Error AH01797: client denied by server configuration</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Owncloud_DirectAdmin,_Apache_2.4_and_Error_AH01797_client_denied_by_server_configuration.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Owncloud_DirectAdmin,_Apache_2.4_and_Error_AH01797_client_denied_by_server_configuration.html</guid>
                <description>I keep a few servers around for shared webhosting for friends, family and some other domains. Most of them run Directadmin, because it is easier to work with for the target audience. I'm very good with the command line, they've never heard of it. One of my friends runs Owncloud, a wonderfull piece of software to get cloud services under your control. He does not use the file part but rather the calendar and contacts a lot. A recent update of Apache to 2.4.10 broke that functionality on a Directadmin machine with the error AH01797: client denied by server configuration. After a bit of searching and debugging, here's how I fixed it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    