<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag dns on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/dns.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag dns on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/dns.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Migrating personal webapps and services</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</guid>
                <description></description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ dnsmasq set capabilities failed fix</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</guid>
                <description>When running dnsmasq under OpenVZ I sometimes get an error when restarting: set capabilities failed. This is because dnsmasq starts as root, then does privileged stuff and then drops to the configured run user. In OpenVZ these permissions are not passed to the VPS, sadly. These three commands fix the problem.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bind DNS Query Graph Charts with GNUPlot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bind-GNUPlot-DNS-Bar-Graph.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bind-GNUPlot-DNS-Bar-Graph.html</guid>
                <description>This is a very simple script which uses GNUplot to create graphs of Bind Query logs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ejabberd SSL Certificate</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_SSL_Certificate.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_SSL_Certificate.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up an SSL Certificate for use with Ejabberd. It covers both the creation of the Certificate Signing Request, the preparing of the certificate for use with Ejabberd and the installation of the certificate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ejabberd Active Directory LDAP Login</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_Active_Directory_LDAP_Login.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_Active_Directory_LDAP_Login.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up ejabberd to authenticate to an Active Directory LDAP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a federated XMPP Chat Network with ejabberd, your own Google Talk Hangouts alternative</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_federated_XMPP_Chat_Network_with_ejabberd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_federated_XMPP_Chat_Network_with_ejabberd.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up your own federated chat network using ejabberd. It covers a basic single node ejabberd server and also the setup of an ejabberd cluster, including errors and DNS SRV record examples. Last but not least federation is also covered.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Turn Bonjour off or on via the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet switches off Bonjour on OS X via the command line or Apple Remote Desktop. This is useful when you want to disable iChat or Messages chatting on the local network. Bonjour is Apple's implementation of Zero configuration networking (Zeroconf), a group of technologies that includes service discovery, address assignment, and hostname resolution. Bonjour locates devices such as printers, other computers, and the services that those devices offer on a local network using multicast Domain Name System (mDNS) service records.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2007 and 2010 Autodiscovery DNS SRV record for BIND</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</guid>
                <description>This is a BIND configuration example to set up Exchange Autodiscovery. Autodiscovery is the ability for Outlook to automatically configure itself to an Exchange 2007/2010 server. The main benefit is for remote users to use Outlook on the Internet as if it was connected on the LAN, this is called Outlook Anywhere or Outlook RPC over HTTP. This is very easily accomplished by having a specific DNS record available for the domain. However, the only examples Microsoft gives you are for their own software. This is the BIND version of the record.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Hide or determine BIND version number</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Get_DNS_server_version_and_hide_it_in_BIND.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Get_DNS_server_version_and_hide_it_in_BIND.html</guid>
                <description>The BIND nameserver (and many others) return their version number when queried a special DNS query. This tutorial shows you how to query the BIND version and how to stop your own BIND server sending its version out.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    