<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag dovecot on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/dovecot.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag dovecot on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/dovecot.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Forward or save outgoing email with Exim</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Forward_or_save_all_outgoing_email_with_exim.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Forward_or_save_all_outgoing_email_with_exim.html</guid>
                <description>I have a specific server where requirements state that all outgoing email should be saved for archival and auditing purposes. The server uses the Exim mail transfer agent, which makes this easy to configure. The outgoing email is also forwarded to an off-site mailbox, both for backup and easy consulting. This captures all outgoing email, sent by PHP scripts or cronjobs, or user accounts that send via exim. This tutorial also shows how to forward or save all outgoing email for a specific domain.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Filtering IMAP mail with imapfilter</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Filtering_IMAP_mail_with_imapfilter.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Filtering_IMAP_mail_with_imapfilter.html</guid>
                <description>I have several email accounts at different providers. Most of them don't offer filtering capabilites like Sieve, or only their own non exportable rule system (Google Apps). My mail client of choice, Thunderbird, has filtering capabilities but my phone has not and I don't want to leave my machine running Thunderbird all the time since it gets quite slow with huge mailboxes. Imapfilter is a mail filtering utility written in Lua which connects to one or more IMAP accounts and filters on the server using IMAP queries. It is a lightweight command line utility, the configuration can be versioned and is simple text and it is very fast.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Postfix snippets - not finished</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Set_up_an_IMAPS_and_SMTPS_mail_server_with_Postfix_and_Dovecot.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Set_up_an_IMAPS_and_SMTPS_mail_server_with_Postfix_and_Dovecot.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    