<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag duplicity on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/duplicity.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag duplicity on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/duplicity.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>MySQL restore after a crash and disk issues</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to restore a MySQL server. The hardware had issues with the storage and required some FSCK's, disk replacements and a lot of RAID and LVM love to get working again. Which was the easy part. MySQL was a bit harder to fix. This post describes the proces I used to get MySQL working again with a recent backup. In this case it was a replicated setup so the client had no actual downtime. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Basic website and database backups with Duplicity</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will help you backup your website and database with Duplicity. You can safely backup your MySQL, MongoDB, website and other data to an off-site location.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    