<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag email on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/email.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag email on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/email.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Forward or save outgoing email with Exim</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Forward_or_save_all_outgoing_email_with_exim.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Forward_or_save_all_outgoing_email_with_exim.html</guid>
                <description>I have a specific server where requirements state that all outgoing email should be saved for archival and auditing purposes. The server uses the Exim mail transfer agent, which makes this easy to configure. The outgoing email is also forwarded to an off-site mailbox, both for backup and easy consulting. This captures all outgoing email, sent by PHP scripts or cronjobs, or user accounts that send via exim. This tutorial also shows how to forward or save all outgoing email for a specific domain.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP Email Backup.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a bowsable HTML archive and a Maildir folder. Not one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view and no proprietary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password. This release has a few major new features, namely support to backup all available folders in one go and a conversion from HTML Kickstart to Bootstrap.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ruby script to upload or convert a Maildir Inbox to an IMAP server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ruby_script_to_upload_or_convert_a_Maildir_Inbox_to_an_IMAP_Server.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ruby_script_to_upload_or_convert_a_Maildir_Inbox_to_an_IMAP_Server.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of all the servers in the Sparkling Network, mostly as an overview for myself, but it might be interesting for others. It also has a status overview of the nodes...</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP email backup to HTML archive.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a HTML archive, nicely browsable, instead of weird folders (Maildir), one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view (thunderbird) and no propritary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Setting up Motion with FTP and Email! support</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Setting-up-motion-with-ftp-and-email-support.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Setting-up-motion-with-ftp-and-email-support.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    