<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag extension on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/extension.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag extension on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/extension.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>I had to jailbreak my iPhone to change the default browser...</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_had_to_jailbreak_my_iPhone_to_change_the_default_browser.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_had_to_jailbreak_my_iPhone_to_change_the_default_browser.html</guid>
                <description>The title of this article says enough. To change the default browser on an iOS device you need to jailbreak your device (root it). It's 2020 and Apple does not allow you to switch Safari with Firefox. Recently a new jailbreak for iOS was released which support the lastest firmware, 13.5. I currently have an iPhone SE 2020 running 13.5, the jailbreak was a welcome addition to fix some small and some big annoyances with iOS. Like switching to Firefox as default browser. This post contains both a small rant on the state of iOS as wel as links to the jailbreak and applications used to switch the default browser.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Dark Reader, dark mode for any website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Dark_Reader_dark_mode_for_any_website.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Dark_Reader_dark_mode_for_any_website.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I discovered a firefox extension that converts any website into a dark version. Works both on firefox for mobile and on the desktop (and all other major browsers), is open source, causes less strain on the eyes and improves battery life. Just as the earlier post on Blokada, I find this such a cool piece of software I wanted to share it with all my readers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    