<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag flash on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/flash.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag flash on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/flash.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>I've packaged up Gnash as a snap, for modern linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html</guid>
                <description>I hate snaps just as much as the next guy but last week I did something unexpected. I packaged up Gnash as a snap.  Gnash is a GNU flash media player, not updated since 2011, and  thus removed from the Ubuntu 20.04 repositories. The snap packaging is based on work by phil roche, he wrote about re-packaging older debian packages with an Ubuntu 18.04/16.04 base layer as a snap. My gnash package is confined (no '--classic' needed), the source code for the snap is on my github and on any snap-enabled distro you can now 'snap install gnash-raymii' to enjoy Gnash again.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Running gnash on Ubuntu 20.04 (in Docker with X11 forwarding)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Running_gnash_on_Ubuntu_20.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Running_gnash_on_Ubuntu_20.04.html</guid>
                <description>As you might have noticed, I'm slowly updating servers and workstations to Ubuntu 20.04, and as always with major upgrades, things break or are removed. Earlier this week I fixed up pygopherd and today I'll get gnash running again. Gnash is not updated since 2011 and therefore, finally, removed from the Ubuntu 20.04 repositories. Compiling it from source proved to be a lot of effort due to gstreamer dependencies and after a few hours I thought, why not just spin up a Ubuntu 18.04 Docker container, install gnash and forward X11. That took just about 10 minutes and now I'm happily running gnash again. In this tutorial I'll show you how to setup gnash in a docker container with x11 forwarding and host networking.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Create a VMWare ESXi 5  5.1 5.5 USB install disk</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare-ESXi-5-USB-installer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare-ESXi-5-USB-installer.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how you can convert a VMWare ESXi 5, 5.1 and 5.5 iso image to a USB install disk. You will learn how to create a USB drive from which you can install VMWare ESXi 5.1. This also works for the special HP version of ESXi with all the drivers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    