<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag freedombox on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/freedombox.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag freedombox on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/freedombox.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Personal Wireguard VPN on a Freedombox with Debian</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Wireguard_VPN_on_Freedombox.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Wireguard_VPN_on_Freedombox.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to set up a personal Wireguard VPN server on Debian or Ubuntu with Freedombox. Freedombox will be used to manage the VPN software, firewall and users. Wireguard is a relatively new VPN built in to the linux kernel. Freedombox is a long running project under the Debian umbrella providing a private server for non experts with focus on user freedom, ease of use and privacy. Combined, those two make a great pair. In the past I've written many articles on how to setup your own personal VPN server, but those all required manual setup and maintenance. With freedombox, the updates are automatic and the management is hidden away behind a convenient web interface. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing Freedombox on Armbian on the Olimex Pioneer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Installing_Freedombox_On_Armbian_On_The_Olimex_A20_Pioneer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Installing_Freedombox_On_Armbian_On_The_Olimex_A20_Pioneer.html</guid>
                <description>FreedomBox is a private server for non-experts: it lets you install and configure server applications with only a few clicks. It runs on cheap hardware of your choice, uses your internet connection and power, and is under your control. Last year the Pioneer became available, officially supported and sanctioned by the Freedombox Foundation. This is a home server you can buy from Olimex, comes in a nice metal case with a proper power supply, network cable, battery and SD card preloaded with Freedombox. Plug in and go. Perfect for users that don't want to tinker but do want their freedom and control. With the Pioneer, both the hardware and software are fully open source. In the default provided distribution for the Pioneer there are a few things I dislike. This guide covers the installation of Freedombox and Debian for the Olimex A20 Lime2 Pioneer with Armbian including reinstalling, Apache SSL certificate and LDAP issues.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    