<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag freebsd on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/freebsd.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag freebsd on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/freebsd.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 11.0-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_11.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_11.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 11.0-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance. A FreeBSD image with Cloud Init will automatically resize the disk to the size of the flavor and it will add your SSH key right at boot. You can use Cloud Config to execute a script at first boott, for example, to bootstrap your system into Puppet or Ansible. If you use Ansible to manage OpenStack instances you can integrate it without manually logging in or doing anything manually.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.3-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.3-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.3-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.3-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 02, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 02 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 01, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_01_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_01_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 01 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 52, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_52_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_52_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 52, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 51, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 51, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing Virtual Machines with virt-install, plus copy pastable distro install one-liners</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</guid>
                <description>virt-install is a command line tool for creating new KVM , Xen or Linux container guests using the libvirt hypervisor management library. It allows you to create a VM and start an installation from the command line. This article has a few copy pastable getting started examples for different distro's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>pfSense allow web interface access on WAN from specific IP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/pfSense_allow_web_interface_access_on_WAN_from_specific_IP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/pfSense_allow_web_interface_access_on_WAN_from_specific_IP.html</guid>
                <description>pfSense is a fast and simple FreeBSD based firewall appliance with a nice web managent interface and the power of the pf firewall underneath. Normally the web interface is only accessible from the management LAN (or LAN by default) interface. If you for whatever reason locked yourself out or need access from a different IP via the WAN interface you can use the easyrule command line to temporarly add a rule that allows your remote IP in. This simple snippet shows you how.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.1-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.1-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.0-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.0-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance. This tutorial is more a collection of notes than what you are used of me, it has less explanation and such, just right on steps to get started.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FreeBSD 10, Converting from RELEASE to STABLE </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_10_Converting_from_RELEASE_to_STABLE.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_10_Converting_from_RELEASE_to_STABLE.html</guid>
                <description>Because of a [bug in  mpd][1] which is fixed in 10-STABLE I wanted to move one of my FreeBSD machines from 10.0-RELEASE to 10.0-STABLE. The process to do so is fairly simple. Basically, you check out the new source code, build the world, build the kernel, install the kernel, install the world, merge some stuff and reboot. Read on to see the entire process</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FreeBSD Ports: remove config options</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_Ports_remove_config_options.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_Ports_remove_config_options.html</guid>
                <description>Today I wanted to upgrade a few packages on one of my FreeBSD servers. The vim port kept complaining: You must select one and only one option from the UI single. Read on to find out how I fixed this error.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    