<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag fst-01 on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/fst-01.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag fst-01 on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/fst-01.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Three new NitroKeys! Nitrokey Pro 2, Storage 2 and a FIDO-U2F Nitrokey</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Three_New_Nitrokeys_Pro_2_Storage_2_and_Fido_u2f.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Three_New_Nitrokeys_Pro_2_Storage_2_and_Fido_u2f.html</guid>
                <description>Last week I received several newsletters from Nitrokey. As you might know, I'm a fan of their (mostly open source) hardware security devices. Their newsletters introduced two new keys, the Nitrokey Pro 2 and the Nitrokey FIDO-U2F key. On their website I also saw the Nitrokey Storage Pro 2. This article is a summary of the newsletters and goes over the new features in the new hardware. It boils down to a new OpenPGP smartcard version (3.3, it was 2.1) in the Nitrokey Pro 2 and Storage 2. The FIDO-U2F device is an entirely new Nitrokey (with a button).</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nitrokey gnuk firmware update via DFU</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nitrokey_gnuk_firmware_update_via_DFU.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nitrokey_gnuk_firmware_update_via_DFU.html</guid>
                <description>The Nitrokey (start, all of them) can be upgraded to a newer GNUK firmware. However, this can only be done via ST Link or DFU, if you use the Gnuk USB firmware upgrade you will brick the device. This guide shows you how to attach a DFU adapter and how to flash firmware to a Nitrokey, both for upgrading or unbricking an USB upgraded one.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FST-01 gnuk firmware update via USB</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FST-01_firmware_upgrade_via_usb.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FST-01_firmware_upgrade_via_usb.html</guid>
                <description>The FST-01 (Flying Stone 1) is a small STM32F103TB based USB device designed to run gnuk and NeuG (gpg usb token or true random number generator). This guide shows you how to upgrade the firmware on the FST-01 so that you can enjoy newer gnuk features like 4096 bit RSA keys.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    