<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag gcc on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/gcc.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag gcc on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/gcc.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Logging all C++ destructors, poor mans run-time tracing</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Logging_all_Cpp_destructors_poor_mans_run-time_tracing.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Logging_all_Cpp_destructors_poor_mans_run-time_tracing.html</guid>
                <description>I recently faced a challenging issue with an application that wasn't shutting down correctly, either segfaulting or terminating without an active exception. Running the program via `valgrind` to check for memory leaks wasn't possible because the program couldn’t perform its cleanup if it didn't shut down correctly. This article covers adding runtime instrumentation provided by `gcc` to log destructors. This helped me figure out what was still left over from the closed-source framework in use preventing correct shutdowns or causing segfaults. It includes example code, setup instructions and insights into handling shutdown issues in large, multi-threaded codebases.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 23:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 23:59:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Statically (cross) compiled vim for x86, x86-64 and mipsel</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html</guid>
                <description>Sometimes I need to manage a few systems with either low resources or a very restricted set of packages. On those systems no compilers or development libraries are available, however it is allowed to bring binaries.A few of those systems are 32 bit x68 systems, some are MIPS systems, even worse. They serve a secure purpose, I cannot go in to much detail about them, except for they require a high level of security, they process certificates. I really like vim as my editor, the only editor available by default on those systems is ed. I have an ed cheatsheet for this purpose. The solution for this problem is to create a statically (cross) compiled version of vim. This article shows you how to create a statically compiled vim that runs everywhere.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    