<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag gdisk on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/gdisk.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag gdisk on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/gdisk.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Windows 7 installer on a KVM Linux VPS (Windows on Digital Ocean)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Windows_7_Installer_on_KVM_Linux_VPS_Digital_Ocean.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Windows_7_Installer_on_KVM_Linux_VPS_Digital_Ocean.html</guid>
                <description>For fun I wanted to install Windows 7 on a KVM Linux VPS (on [Digital Ocean) but it should work for any KVM or XEN-HVM VPS with console access). I was experimenting with Grub2 and ISO booting, since grub2 can natively boot a linux ISO. For Windows this is not possible, the installer needs to be extracted on a FAT32 partition from which you boot. On a normal system I would repartition the disk using a live CD, but on a VPS where an ISO cannot be booted this is troublesome. If I could boot from an ISO I would use that to install Windows, but where's the fun in that? I had to figure out how to shrink an EXT4 filesystem from a running Ubuntu VPS, which is possible, however very risky, with pivot_root. Next the partiton table can be converted to MBR, the partition can be resized, a FAT32 partiton and filesystem can be created, the Windows Installer files copied onto that, some Grub config and a reboot later, you're in the Windows 7 Installer.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    