<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag gnupg on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/gnupg.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag gnupg on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/gnupg.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>FST-01 gnuk firmware update via USB</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FST-01_firmware_upgrade_via_usb.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FST-01_firmware_upgrade_via_usb.html</guid>
                <description>The FST-01 (Flying Stone 1) is a small STM32F103TB based USB device designed to run gnuk and NeuG (gpg usb token or true random number generator). This guide shows you how to upgrade the firmware on the FST-01 so that you can enjoy newer gnuk features like 4096 bit RSA keys.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nitrokey Start: Getting started guide (gnuk openpgp token)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_Start_Getting_started_guide.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_Start_Getting_started_guide.html</guid>
                <description>The Nitrokey Start is an OpenPGP USB token. It supports three 2048 bit GPG keys and is based on gnuk. Gnuk is an implementation of USB cryptographic token for GPG. Cryptographic token is a store of private keys and it computes cryptographic functions on the device. The main difference with other GPG cards like the Nitrokey Pro or the OpenPGP card is that this device does not use a smartcard. Whereas the other devices are basically USB smartcard readers, the Nitrokey Start has everything in it's firmware. This article is a getting started guide where I talk about the initial setup of the device, setting up a user PIN, an admin PIN and a reset code, generating the key and subkeys on the device, or loading external keys into the device and usage examples with GPG, OpenSSH and Thunderbird.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    