<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag google on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/google.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag google on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/google.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Lets talk about changelogs, or, how I loathe 'bugfixes and performance improvements'</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Rant_Lets_talk_about_changelogs.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Rant_Lets_talk_about_changelogs.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short personal rant to start the new year off. When you're a multi billion dollar company with more software developers than you'd ever need, how on earth is it possible that your public changelog in an app store is just 'bugfixes and performance improvements'? If that is all you're going to put there, then just leave it blank. Or be honest and put 'We can't be arsed to fill this in' there. For me as a technical user it's not actionable, and your non technical users are not going to read that page anyway.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Local incremental backups of Google Photos on Ubuntu with gphotos-sync</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Local_incremental_Google_Photos_backup_on_Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Local_incremental_Google_Photos_backup_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>'Google Photos' no longer syncs with 'Google Drive' or with their 'Backup and Sync' desktop software. There used to be a checkbox to get your 'Google Photos' pictures in 'Google Drive' but that has been disabled. I used that feature together with their 'Backup and Sync' tool to sync all the photos in 'Google Photos' to my local Windows computer. From there I use 'DigiKam'  to manage the photos and backup them offline and offsite. Due to Google removing that feature, I had to go find another way to get the pictures out of 'Google Photos', which, after a few months of (automated) use, 'gphotos-sync' on Ubuntu seems to be the best, stable choice. In this guide I'll show you how to setup incremental backups from 'Google Photos' on Ubuntu. My 'DigiKam' database moved over without problems, and now I'm glad I don't have to use Windows for picture managemant anymore.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Chrome Extensions for Privacy, Adblocking and anti-tracking</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chrome-extensions-for-privacy.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Chrome-extensions-for-privacy.html</guid>
                <description>This is a list with extensions for google chrome which help you block tracking and ads, and help you protect your privacy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    