<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag gpg on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/gpg.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag gpg on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/gpg.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>The yearly backup restore test</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Yearly_Backup_Restore_test.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Yearly_Backup_Restore_test.html</guid>
                <description>In my calendar there is a yearly recurring item named 'backup restore test'. This is an article on my backup scheme and the yearly restore test, covering all aspects, such as data validation, backup scheme, time and cost involved.
I started doing personal restore tests each year around 2012, when I did them for my first job. At work back then, the restore test was monthly, for my own backups I decided that yearly was okay enough, since the backup scheme, software and provider do not change. I'm using Azure cold storage for my (locally encrypted) personal backups, since it's both cheap and supported by my local NAS.

Have you done your backup restore test recently?</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Three new NitroKeys! Nitrokey Pro 2, Storage 2 and a FIDO-U2F Nitrokey</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Three_New_Nitrokeys_Pro_2_Storage_2_and_Fido_u2f.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Three_New_Nitrokeys_Pro_2_Storage_2_and_Fido_u2f.html</guid>
                <description>Last week I received several newsletters from Nitrokey. As you might know, I'm a fan of their (mostly open source) hardware security devices. Their newsletters introduced two new keys, the Nitrokey Pro 2 and the Nitrokey FIDO-U2F key. On their website I also saw the Nitrokey Storage Pro 2. This article is a summary of the newsletters and goes over the new features in the new hardware. It boils down to a new OpenPGP smartcard version (3.3, it was 2.1) in the Nitrokey Pro 2 and Storage 2. The FIDO-U2F device is an entirely new Nitrokey (with a button).</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>GPG noninteractive batch sign, trust and send gnupg keys</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/GPG_noninteractive_batch_sign_trust_and_send_gnupg_keys.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/GPG_noninteractive_batch_sign_trust_and_send_gnupg_keys.html</guid>
                <description>Recently a team I consult for started using a shared password manager, pass. It uses GPG keys and presents itself as the standard unix password manager, but in essence it's nothing more than a wrapper around GPG encrypted files. We all had to generate new keys since the team is new and we were not allowed to use existing keys. Using a new, empty keyring, I generated my key and imported their keys. I wanted to trust, sign and publish all keys to a keyserver, this article shows how to do that noninteractively in batch form. Saves me doing the same thing four times, since now it's just four people, but next time it might be a hundred.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nitrokey gnuk firmware update via DFU</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nitrokey_gnuk_firmware_update_via_DFU.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nitrokey_gnuk_firmware_update_via_DFU.html</guid>
                <description>The Nitrokey (start, all of them) can be upgraded to a newer GNUK firmware. However, this can only be done via ST Link or DFU, if you use the Gnuk USB firmware upgrade you will brick the device. This guide shows you how to attach a DFU adapter and how to flash firmware to a Nitrokey, both for upgrading or unbricking an USB upgraded one.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FST-01 gnuk firmware update via USB</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FST-01_firmware_upgrade_via_usb.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FST-01_firmware_upgrade_via_usb.html</guid>
                <description>The FST-01 (Flying Stone 1) is a small STM32F103TB based USB device designed to run gnuk and NeuG (gpg usb token or true random number generator). This guide shows you how to upgrade the firmware on the FST-01 so that you can enjoy newer gnuk features like 4096 bit RSA keys.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nitrokey Start: Getting started guide (gnuk openpgp token)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_Start_Getting_started_guide.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_Start_Getting_started_guide.html</guid>
                <description>The Nitrokey Start is an OpenPGP USB token. It supports three 2048 bit GPG keys and is based on gnuk. Gnuk is an implementation of USB cryptographic token for GPG. Cryptographic token is a store of private keys and it computes cryptographic functions on the device. The main difference with other GPG cards like the Nitrokey Pro or the OpenPGP card is that this device does not use a smartcard. Whereas the other devices are basically USB smartcard readers, the Nitrokey Start has everything in it's firmware. This article is a getting started guide where I talk about the initial setup of the device, setting up a user PIN, an admin PIN and a reset code, generating the key and subkeys on the device, or loading external keys into the device and usage examples with GPG, OpenSSH and Thunderbird.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Keep messages secure with GPG</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Keeping_messages_secure_with_GPG.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Keeping_messages_secure_with_GPG.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to get started with GPG and Mailvelope. It discusses public/private key crypto and shows you how to use the Mailvelope software to encrypt and decrypt GPG messages on any webmail provider.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Horizon installation with SSL on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the Openstack Horizon (icehouse) dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04 or 14.04, including SSL setup. It features nice screenshots and even an Ansible playbook to automate it all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    