<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag gpl on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/gpl.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag gpl on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/gpl.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2024.01 released, better notifications and history</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include better alerting and history of events. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Fixing the hiss on my Atgames Legends Pinball Micro including root access</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Fixing_the_buzz_hiss_on_my_atgames_legends_pinball_micro.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Fixing_the_buzz_hiss_on_my_atgames_legends_pinball_micro.html</guid>
                <description>The [Atgames Legends Pinball Micro](https://web.archive.org/web/20240123213954/https://www.atgames.us/products/legends-pinball-micro) is a small virtual pinball cabinet for around USD 350. I imported one to the Netherlands, Atgames does not ship here. The built in tables are okay and more are for sale via Atgames' webshop. Overall for the price it is a nice device. Build quality is okay, software lacks a bit of quality. One really annoying issue which severely impacts gameplay is a buzz / hiss sound. This post goes over my attempts to fix this hiss and the one that worked was a ground loop isolator.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 22:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2023.01 released, major performance improvements, new layout and new checks!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2023.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2023.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include a responsive and adjustable layout, massive performance improvements and a new check type, allowing you to execute external processes, for example, the nagios/monitoring plugins. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Responsive Qt/QML layout coming to Leaf Node Monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Responsive_Qt_QML_Layout_coming_to_Leaf_Node_Monitoring.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Responsive_Qt_QML_Layout_coming_to_Leaf_Node_Monitoring.html</guid>
                <description>[Leaf Node Monitoring](https://leafnode.nl) is my own open source (GPLv3), paid, network monitoring program for Windows, Linux &amp; Android. Written in C++ &amp; Qt 5. Perfect to run on your desktop and monitor your servers. Simple setup, auto-detects running services, runs checks concurrently and alerting. This post shows another upcoming feature in the next version, responsive layouting to more effectively use screen real estate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>What's coming in the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Whats_coming_in_leaf_node_monitoring_v2022_02.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Whats_coming_in_leaf_node_monitoring_v2022_02.html</guid>
                <description>Leaf Node Monitoring is my own open source (GPLv3), paid, network monitoring program for Windows, Linux &amp; Android. Written in C++ &amp; Qt 5. Perfect to run on your desktop and monitor your servers. Simple setup, auto-detects running services, runs checks concurrently, open port scanning and alerting. I've recently released the first version, and this post goes over the features that will come in the next release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Selling my own GPL software part 3, prior art (existing GPL software for sale)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Existing_GPL_software_for_sale.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Existing_GPL_software_for_sale.html</guid>
                <description>In my earlier posts I described the hurdles I faced with my plan to [sell my own](/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html) GPL software and I described how to [embed the source code directly inside the app] (/s/articles/Embed_the_source_code_directly_in_your_Qt_app.html) (for mobile platforms). This post looks at a few other projects that sell GPL software and it's a bit of a progress update regarding my plans and software.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Qt 5.15.3 Open Source released</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15.3_OpenSource_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15.3_OpenSource_released.html</guid>
                <description>Qt is a nice C++ framework with a GUI toolkit on top, actually, 2 toolkit, Widgets and Qml. Qt is available under the GPL and LPGL, open source licenses and a closed source license. [Back in 2020](https://lwn.net/Articles/817129/), the Qt company decided to [start a war](https://ev.kde.org/2020/04/06/changes-in-qt-and-the-kde-free-qt-foundation/) against their own users and contributors by withholding the 5.15 code, only releasing them under a closed license, making the offline installers available to paid customers and requiring a Qt account for the online installer. Due to [an agreement](https://www.qt.io/faq/3.2.-why-do-you-have-an-agreement-with-kde-about-your-licensing-what-kde-is-and-whats-the-history-of-qt-and-kde) with the [KDE project](https://kde.org/community/whatiskde/kdefreeqtfoundation/) they are obliged to release the code after one year under an open source license, and that time has come for 5.15.3. For most LTS releases, the Qt company writes a blog post, but this open source release only gets a [mailing list post](https://lists.qt-project.org/pipermail/development/2022-March/042262.html) (One day and 4 blog posts later, [no mention of 5.15.3 on their blog](https://archive.ph/IvMSn)). This short post is intended to give a bit more publicity to that release and to tell you about the KDE Qt 5.15 LTS patch collection. Even if I might not agree with the business practices, the framework is nice to work with.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I enforced the AGPL on my code, here's how it went</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_enforced_the_AGPL_on_my_code_heres_how_it_went.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_enforced_the_AGPL_on_my_code_heres_how_it_went.html</guid>
                <description>Five years ago I made a website that allowed you to put in a few domains and get an email when the SSL certificate was about to expire. No ads, no fuss, just an easy way for people to keep tabs on their sites without setting up their own monitoring like Nagios. As with all of my software, I released it under the AGPL due to it being web based software.
Recently I found a company that hosted certificatemonitor, with some modifications (branding and a dutch tanslation), without any reference to its origin, no source code provided and no mention of the license.
In this article I'll talk about what I did to enforce the license and how it went. TL;DR, not as expected. The company responded timely and friendly, but did a half assed attempt (added a link to my site with 'Inspired By Remy' as the text), then after my complaints, took down the entire site.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Embed the source code directly in your Qt app with qmake and qrc, for GPL compliance</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Embed_the_source_code_directly_in_your_Qt_app.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Embed_the_source_code_directly_in_your_Qt_app.html</guid>
                <description>In my earlier [post on selling GPL software](/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html) I outlined a few points that make it hard to sell GPL software. One of them is the availability of the source code. You could put it online but then everyone has access without paying. Other options like putting it behind a login or sending a link after purchase require extra systems and saving more user information, lots of extra hassle for me and the users.
One of my ideas for 'solving' this issue is by shipping the actual source code directly inside the application. This article shows you how to do that, by creating an archive of the current source code on every build with `qmake` and embedding that inside the application using `qrc`, including a button to save the archive locally to disk. It works on the desktop as well as Android, including the required permissions.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    