<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag homelab on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/homelab.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag homelab on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/homelab.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Finally, run Docker containers natively in Proxmox 9.1 (OCI images)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Finally_run_Docker_containers_natively_in_Proxmox_9.1.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Finally_run_Docker_containers_natively_in_Proxmox_9.1.html</guid>
                <description>Proxmox VE is a virtualization platform, like VMWare, but open source, based on Debian. It can run KVM virtual machines and Linux Containers (LXC). I've been using it for over 10 years, the [first article I wrote mentioning it was in 2012](/s/tags/proxmox.html). At home I have a 2 node Proxmox VE cluster consisting of 2 HP EliteDesk Mini machines, both running with 16 GB RAM and both an NVMe and SATA SSD with ZFS on root (256 GB). It's small enough (physically) and is just enough for my homelab needs specs wise. Proxmox VE 9.1 was released [recently](https://www.proxmox.com/en/about/company-details/press-releases/proxmox-virtual-environment-9-1) and this new version is able to run Docker containers / OCI images natively, no more hacks or VM's required to run docker. This post shows you how to run a simple container from a docker image.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:34:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Proxmox VE 7 Corosync QDevice in a Docker container</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_7_Corosync_QDevice_in_Docker.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_7_Corosync_QDevice_in_Docker.html</guid>
                <description>At home I have a 2 node Proxmox VE cluster consisting of 2 HP EliteDesk Mini machines, both running with 16 GB RAM and both an NVMe and SATA SSD with ZFS on root (256 GB). It's small enough (physically) and is just enough for my homelab needs specs wise. Proxmox VE has support for clustering. For a cluster (in any sense of the word), you need at least 3 nodes, otherwise there is no quorum. Corosync, the cluster software used by Proxmox, supports an external Quorum device. This is a small piece of software running on a third node which provides an extra vote for the quorum. In my case I wanted to run this on my NAS, since (physical) space is a premium. The NAS supports Docker, this guide explains how to run the QDevice for Proxmox VE 7 in a Docker container. There is a qdevice Docker image on the Docker hub but that guide does not work for Proxmox VE 7 and requires a lot of manual setup. Using my method involves a lot less steps, since you're basically running an extra debian VPS (a container with systemd and openssh).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 04:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    