<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag icewm on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/icewm.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag icewm on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/icewm.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Using IceWM and a Raspberry Pi as my main PC, sharing my theme, config and some tips and tricks.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_IceWM_and_sharing_my_config_and_tips_tricks.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_IceWM_and_sharing_my_config_and_tips_tricks.html</guid>
                <description>KDE is my desktop environment of choice. KDE5 is rock-solid, configurable in any way possible and works great. It treats you like a responsible adult instead of a child like GNOME does these days, and after XFCE switched to GTK3, the RAM usage is on-par, more often than not a bare KDE install (Debian or Arch) uses around 300MB ram. This is with Baloo (search indexer) and Akonadi (PIM database backend) disabled. Great default behaviour, low resource usage and enourmous configurability, so why is this post then titled 'IceWM'? At home I'm using a small ARM device (Raspberry Pi 4 with an SSD) as my main computer, and there resources are limited. KDE runs fine, but you notice that it is a bit slower than on my work computer. IceWM on the other hand, uses less than 30 MB of RAM and even less CPU. The program that gives you a desktop background, icewmbg, uses double the RAM of IceWM itself! IceWM, next to Awesome, is one of my favorite window managers, very configurable and provides all I need. This PC doesn't have multiple screens, which would be a bit more of a hassle than with KDE. After switching, the machine feels a lot faster. It's the small details in which I notice it, like text input, a few seconds of lag here and there. This post shows my IceWM config including some options explained, my IceWM theme and a few tips and tricks to configure the rest of the desktop.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Run CLion native on Android, ditch your desktop!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Run_CLion_on_Android.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Run_CLion_on_Android.html</guid>
                <description>How often do you read articles that state that people have replaced their main computer with an iPad and are fully content? Now, how many of those articles just use a linux server (vps) somewhere with some native apps, but mostly SSH to that server? Well, what if I told you that you can run a full blown IDE, the best IDE for C++ there is, CLion by JetBrains, on Android? Including compiling, just native GCC, CMake, GDB and all the stuff you are used to? Just for fun I've installed CLion on an old Samsung Tab S2 I had lying around, using Ubuntu in a chroot. It works way better than I'd expected, with a Bluetooth keyboard and mouse it's almost as if your on a desktop. I wonder if you could run Android Studio and use the tablet to compile app's for itself. This article shows some photo's, including a mechanical keyboard, different window managers and had instructions to replicate this setup.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    