<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag intrusion-detection on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/intrusion-detection.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag intrusion-detection on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/intrusion-detection.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>OSSEC 2.8 Server, Client, Web UI and Analogi Dashboard Installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_2.8.0_Server_Client_and_Analogi_Dashboard_on_Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_2.8.0_Server_Client_and_Analogi_Dashboard_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>OSSEC is an Open Source Host-based Intrusion Detection System that performs log analysis, file integrity checking, policy monitoring, rootkit detection, real-time alerting and active response. It runs on most operating systems, including Linux, MacOS, Solaris, HP-UX, AIX and Windows. It also includes agentless monitoring for use with for example Cisco or Juniper hardware. This tutorial covers the installation of the OSSEC 2.8 server, the standard OSSEC Web UI and the Analogi dashboard on Ubuntu 14.04. It also covers OSSEC setup with MySQL support. Last but not least it shows you how to install the OSSEC agent on a *NIX system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Uninstall and Remove OSSEC</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial shows you how to remove an OSSEC installation. OSSEC is installed from source (via a script), so you have to remove all the things manually instead of with your package manager.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OSSEC Server, Client, Web UI and Analogi Dashboard Installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_and_webui_and_analogi_dashboard_installation_on_Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_and_webui_and_analogi_dashboard_installation_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>OSSEC is an Open Source Host-based Intrusion Detection System that performs log analysis, file integrity checking, policy monitoring, rootkit detection, real-time alerting and active response. It runs on most operating systems, including Linux, MacOS, Solaris, HP-UX, AIX and Windows. It also includes agentless monitoring for use with for example Cisco or Juniper hardware. This tutorial covers the installation of the OSSEC server, the standard OSSEC Web UI and the Analogi dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04. It also covers OSSEC setup with MySQL support, including a Makefile bugfix. Last but not least it shows you how to install the OSSEC agent on a *NIX system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python script to monitor a file for changes and then mail the report with the file attached.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script which checks a file's md5 hash, compares it to a previous (or given) hash and mails a report with the option of attaching the file with the email. I wrote it because I use AIDE on some systems, and I let it auto update the database. This script runs via cron before and after the AIDE run, so I have an archive of databases. But it can be used for all kind of files, not just for the AIDE database.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    