<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag kde on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/kde.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag kde on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/kde.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Qt 5.15.3 Open Source released</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15.3_OpenSource_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Qt_5.15.3_OpenSource_released.html</guid>
                <description>Qt is a nice C++ framework with a GUI toolkit on top, actually, 2 toolkit, Widgets and Qml. Qt is available under the GPL and LPGL, open source licenses and a closed source license. [Back in 2020](https://lwn.net/Articles/817129/), the Qt company decided to [start a war](https://ev.kde.org/2020/04/06/changes-in-qt-and-the-kde-free-qt-foundation/) against their own users and contributors by withholding the 5.15 code, only releasing them under a closed license, making the offline installers available to paid customers and requiring a Qt account for the online installer. Due to [an agreement](https://www.qt.io/faq/3.2.-why-do-you-have-an-agreement-with-kde-about-your-licensing-what-kde-is-and-whats-the-history-of-qt-and-kde) with the [KDE project](https://kde.org/community/whatiskde/kdefreeqtfoundation/) they are obliged to release the code after one year under an open source license, and that time has come for 5.15.3. For most LTS releases, the Qt company writes a blog post, but this open source release only gets a [mailing list post](https://lists.qt-project.org/pipermail/development/2022-March/042262.html) (One day and 4 blog posts later, [no mention of 5.15.3 on their blog](https://archive.ph/IvMSn)). This short post is intended to give a bit more publicity to that release and to tell you about the KDE Qt 5.15 LTS patch collection. Even if I might not agree with the business practices, the framework is nice to work with.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Expose any Qt5 program via VNC</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Expose_any_QT_program_via_VNC.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Expose_any_QT_program_via_VNC.html</guid>
                <description>A few months ago I wrote about [Microsoft Teams running on a coffee machine. That was a fun work experiment where I got a VNC client running on the Linux-based coffee machines that we produce at work. In the comments on hackernews Jean-Micha&amp;euml;l Celerier pointed me to the reverse, a way to expose any Qt application over VNC. This article shows you how I use this feature to work on our Qt 5 based coffee machine frontend as well as how you can use this on your machine, for example, to expose Dolphin, the KDE file manager, over VNC.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>The awesomely epic guide to KDE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/The_awesomely_epic_guide_to_KDE.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/The_awesomely_epic_guide_to_KDE.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows gives an overview of the major KDE features like font management, visual effects, file management, eye candy, the panels, the task switcer and more great KDE stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    