<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag keepalived on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/keepalived.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag keepalived on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/keepalived.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Adding IPv6 to a keepalived and haproxy cluster</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Adding_IPv6_to_a_keepalived_and_haproxy_cluster.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Adding_IPv6_to_a_keepalived_and_haproxy_cluster.html</guid>
                <description>At work I regularly build high-available clusters for customers, where the setup is distributed over multiple datacenters with failover software. If one component fails, the service doesn't experience issues or downtime due to the failure. Recently I was tasked with expanding a cluster setup to be also reachable via IPv6. This article goes over the settings and configuration required for haproxy and keepalived for IPv6. The internal cluster will only be IPv4, the loadbalancer terminates HTTP and HTTPS connections. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Keepalived notify script, execute action on failover</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived_notify_script_execute_action_on_failover.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived_notify_script_execute_action_on_failover.html</guid>
                <description>Keepalived supports running scripts on VRRP state change. This can come in handy when you need to execute an action when a failover occurs. In my case, I have a VPN running on a Virtual IP and want to make sure the VPN only runs on the node with the Virtual IP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Building HA Clusters with Ansible and Openstack</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</guid>
                <description>This is an extensive guide on building high available clusters with Ansible and Openstack. We'll build a Highly available cluster consisting out of two load balancers, two database servers and two application servers running a simple wordpress site. This is all done with Ansible, the cluster nodes are all on Openstack. Ansible is a super awesome orchestration tool and Openstack is a big buzzword filled software suite for datacenter virtualization.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Simple keepalived failover setup on Ubuntu 14.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived-Simple-IP-failover-on-Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived-Simple-IP-failover-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to set up very simple keepalived IP failover on Ubuntu 14.04. Keepalived is a piece of software which can be used to achieve high availability by assigning two or more nodes a virtual IP and monitoring those nodes, failing over when one goes down.  Keepalived can do more, like load balancing and monitoring, but this tutorial focusses on a very simple setup, just IP failover.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    