<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag kernel on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/kernel.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag kernel on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/kernel.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 50, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_50_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_50_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 50 of 2015, covering open source and sysadmin related stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Linux software raid, rebuilding broken raid 1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html</guid>
                <description>Last week Nagios alerted me about a broken disk in one of my clients testing servers. There is a best effort SLA on the thing, and there were spare drives of the same type and size in the datacenter. Lucky me. This particular data center is on biking distance, so I enjoyed a sunny ride there. Simply put, I needed to replace the disk and rebuild the raid 1 array. This server is a simple Ubuntu 12.04 LTS server with two disks running in raid 1, no spare. Client has a tight budget, and with a best effort SLA not in production, fine with me. Consultant tip, make sure you have those things signed. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused CentOS/Red Hat kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This small article will show you how to remove unused kernels in Red Hat or CentOS. This is sometimes necessary because the /boot partition can fill up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused Ubuntu kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This one liner will help you remove unused Ubuntu kernels. Ubuntu does not remove kernels when they install a new one, however the default /boot partition is relatively small, about 100MB. So after 10 kernels, you can get No Space Left On Device errors with apt-get upgrading. Then you can eitehr remove them manually, or use this one liner to automatically remove them all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ dnsmasq set capabilities failed fix</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</guid>
                <description>When running dnsmasq under OpenVZ I sometimes get an error when restarting: set capabilities failed. This is because dnsmasq starts as root, then does privileged stuff and then drops to the configured run user. In OpenVZ these permissions are not passed to the VPS, sadly. These three commands fix the problem.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exploring /proc/ - tips and tricks for the procfs</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Procfs_tips_and_tricks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Procfs_tips_and_tricks.html</guid>
                <description>This article has a lot of nice tips and trics on using the procfs linux virtual file system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    