<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag keystone on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/keystone.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag keystone on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/keystone.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Horizon installation with SSL on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the Openstack Horizon (icehouse) dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04 or 14.04, including SSL setup. It features nice screenshots and even an Ansible playbook to automate it all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Swift Objectstore Access via FTP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on accessing the Openstack Swift Object Storage system using an FTP client. Openstack Swift has a beautiful API which you can program to. However, sometimes it is handy to quickly be able to access your Swift/Objectstore data without programming around it. We will use ftp-cloudfs to do this. There is also Softlayers swftp, but that does not support Keystone Authentication (2.0). ftp-cloudfs does support this. The OS X Cyberduck FTP client also has Openstack Swift support, however that is a native implementation, not using FTP. With ftp-cloudfs we can use any ftp client, from Filezilla to midnight commander.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    