<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag leaf-node-monitoring on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/leaf-node-monitoring.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag leaf-node-monitoring on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/leaf-node-monitoring.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2025.01 released with Import/Export and Connectivity Check</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2025.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2025.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. This update adds two features users have requested, plus a couple of small but useful fixes. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 19:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 19:04:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2024.02 released, autostart, ssl certificate expiry and minimize to tray</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.02_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.02_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include minimizing to the tray, automatic startup on Windows and Linux and a new check, SSL Certificate Expiry. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2024.01 released, better notifications and history</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include better alerting and history of events. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2023.01 released, major performance improvements, new layout and new checks!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2023.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2023.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include a responsive and adjustable layout, massive performance improvements and a new check type, allowing you to execute external processes, for example, the nagios/monitoring plugins. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Responsive Qt/QML layout coming to Leaf Node Monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Responsive_Qt_QML_Layout_coming_to_Leaf_Node_Monitoring.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Responsive_Qt_QML_Layout_coming_to_Leaf_Node_Monitoring.html</guid>
                <description>[Leaf Node Monitoring](https://leafnode.nl) is my own open source (GPLv3), paid, network monitoring program for Windows, Linux &amp; Android. Written in C++ &amp; Qt 5. Perfect to run on your desktop and monitor your servers. Simple setup, auto-detects running services, runs checks concurrently and alerting. This post shows another upcoming feature in the next version, responsive layouting to more effectively use screen real estate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>What's coming in the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Whats_coming_in_leaf_node_monitoring_v2022_02.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Whats_coming_in_leaf_node_monitoring_v2022_02.html</guid>
                <description>Leaf Node Monitoring is my own open source (GPLv3), paid, network monitoring program for Windows, Linux &amp; Android. Written in C++ &amp; Qt 5. Perfect to run on your desktop and monitor your servers. Simple setup, auto-detects running services, runs checks concurrently, open port scanning and alerting. I've recently released the first version, and this post goes over the features that will come in the next release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Selling my own GPL software part 3, prior art (existing GPL software for sale)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Existing_GPL_software_for_sale.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Existing_GPL_software_for_sale.html</guid>
                <description>In my earlier posts I described the hurdles I faced with my plan to [sell my own](/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html) GPL software and I described how to [embed the source code directly inside the app] (/s/articles/Embed_the_source_code_directly_in_your_Qt_app.html) (for mobile platforms). This post looks at a few other projects that sell GPL software and it's a bit of a progress update regarding my plans and software.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Embed the source code directly in your Qt app with qmake and qrc, for GPL compliance</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Embed_the_source_code_directly_in_your_Qt_app.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Embed_the_source_code_directly_in_your_Qt_app.html</guid>
                <description>In my earlier [post on selling GPL software](/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html) I outlined a few points that make it hard to sell GPL software. One of them is the availability of the source code. You could put it online but then everyone has access without paying. Other options like putting it behind a login or sending a link after purchase require extra systems and saving more user information, lots of extra hassle for me and the users.
One of my ideas for 'solving' this issue is by shipping the actual source code directly inside the application. This article shows you how to do that, by creating an archive of the current source code on every build with `qmake` and embedding that inside the application using `qrc`, including a button to save the archive locally to disk. It works on the desktop as well as Android, including the required permissions.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Selling my own GPL software, part 1: a lot of hurdles</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Selling_GPL_Software_part_1_lots_of_hurdles.html</guid>
                <description>For as long as I can remember I've got this dream of a passive income software project. At first I thought of it as a hosted service, probably something monitoring related, or high-available cloud hosting-ish. That's the kind of stuff a sysadmin dreams of.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now that I'm a developer for a couple of years, exposed to a few different languages, design patterns and software architectures, that idea is still lingering around, but no longer focused on a hosted piece of software. The web is just too fast paced, bloated and way too much work compared to a piece of cross platform software.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In my spare time I've been chugging along on a piece of software, which I'm contemplating selling. In my case the commercial aspect is made more difficult because I also want to release the software with a GPL license.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This post describes the initial hurdles I'm encountering, next to just programming the software.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    