<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag matias-ergo-pro on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/matias-ergo-pro.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag matias-ergo-pro on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/matias-ergo-pro.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>SpaceCat Launchpad v2, an awesome cool little macropad</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/SpaceCat_Launchpad_v2_an_awesome_little_macropad.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/SpaceCat_Launchpad_v2_an_awesome_little_macropad.html</guid>
                <description>On Reddit, Josh (from SpaceCat) did a valentines day action, 10% off your entire order. I'm eyeing a LaunchPad for a while now, both to have a small macro pad and to experiment with QMK (firmware). So I ordered the LaunchPad full kit, an assortment of Gateron key switches and a VIM keycap. This article goes over the quality, the build process and my current setup of the Launchpad.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Split keyboards, a five year review including the ErgoDox EZ, Matias Ergo Pro and Kinesis Freestyle 2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Split_keyboards_a_five_year_review_including_the_ErgoDox_EZ_Matias_Ergo_Pro_and_Kinesis_Freestyle_2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Split_keyboards_a_five_year_review_including_the_ErgoDox_EZ_Matias_Ergo_Pro_and_Kinesis_Freestyle_2.html</guid>
                <description>A split keyboard is weird at first, but once you get used to it, you will never want anything else. The keyboard is made up from two halves allowing your arms and wrists to be in a natural (neutral, straight) position, instead of having an angle/twist in your wrist. I've been using split keyboards for about five years now. Over those years I've tried several different models from different manufacturers. In this article I'll talk about the three split keyboards I've used intensively and two I have only seen or tried shortly. We'll start with my current and favorite split keyboard, the ErgoDox EZ. The other two I've used are the Matias Ergo Pro and the Kinesis Freestyle 2. I discuss the UHK and Microsoft Natural Ergonomic Keyboard 4000 briefly.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    