<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag metadata on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/metadata.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag metadata on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/metadata.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenStack nova get-password, set-password and post encrypted password to metadata service</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenStack_nova_get_-_password_set_-_password_and_post_encrypted_password_to_metadata_service.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenStack_nova_get_-_password_set_-_password_and_post_encrypted_password_to_metadata_service.html</guid>
                <description>When you create images for an OpenStack Cloud you want to use 'cloud' features. Fancy term for automatic resizing of your instance disk, adding an SSH key, (re)setting passwords and executing scripts on first boot to configure your instance further. OpenStack provides the metadata service for instances, which supplies information for the instance, like its public IP, SSH public key that was provided and vendor or user provided data like scripts or information. The OpenStack metadata service allows an instance to post data to an endpoint wich can be retreived with the 'nova get-password' command. It is meant to be an encrypted password (with the public SSH key) but it can be any plain text as well and it doesn't have to be the root password. In this guide I'll go over the scripts I use inside linux images to post a password to the metadata service and the 'nova' commands such as 'set-password' and 'get-password'. That includes decrypting a password with an SSH key that is password-protected (Horizon and nova don't support that) and the 'nova set-password' command, which sets the root password inside an instance when it has the 'qemu-guest-agent' installed and running.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    