<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag migrate on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/migrate.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag migrate on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/migrate.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Migrating personal webapps and services</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I've migrated some of my personal servers and services to new machines and newer operating system versions. I prefer to migrate instead of upgrading the OS for a number of reasons. I'll also talk about the migration process and some stuff to remember when migrating web applications and services.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack - (Manually) migrating (KVM) Nova compute virtual machines</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_-_(Manually)_migrating_(KVM)_Nova_Compute_Virtual_Machines.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_-_(Manually)_migrating_(KVM)_Nova_Compute_Virtual_Machines.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to migrate KVM virtual machines with the  Openstack Nova compute service, either manually or with the Openstack tooling. Openstack provides a few different ways to migrate virtual machines from one compute node to another. Each option has different requirements and restrictions, for example, you can't live-migrate without shared storage. You can't live-migrate if you have a configdrive enabled. You can't select the target host if you use the nova migrate (non-live) command etc. This article describes the most common migration scenario's including live and manual migration using native linux tools.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    