<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag monitoring on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/monitoring.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag monitoring on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/monitoring.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2025.01 released with Import/Export and Connectivity Check</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2025.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2025.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. This update adds two features users have requested, plus a couple of small but useful fixes. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 19:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 19:04:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2024.02 released, autostart, ssl certificate expiry and minimize to tray</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.02_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.02_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include minimizing to the tray, automatic startup on Windows and Linux and a new check, SSL Certificate Expiry. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Leaf Node Monitoring v2024.01 released, better notifications and history</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.01_released.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Leaf_Node_Monitoring_v2024.01_released.html</guid>
                <description>I'm pleased to announce the next version of Leaf Node Monitoring, the simple and easy to use open source site and server monitoring tool. Major new features include better alerting and history of events. This post goes over everything that is new in this release.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash HTTP monitoring dashboard</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_HTTP_Monitoring_Dashboard.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_HTTP_Monitoring_Dashboard.html</guid>
                <description>This is a shell script that creates a webpage with the status of HTTP(s) sites. Parallel checking, thus very fast, only dependencies are curl and bash (version 4 or above). For all of you who want a simple script with a nice webpage to check a few websites. Perfect for a wall mounted monitoring display and a Raspberry Pi. Installation and configuration is easy to do inside the script. It scales well, both on the checking side as the information display page (dense on purpose). Failed checks appear right on top for you to act on. I had this script running at home for at least a year in that form, when I showed it to a friend he liked it,  asked me to make it public, but before I did that I polished it up a bit. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get number of incoming connections on specific port with ss</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_number_of_incoming_connections_on_specific_ports_with_ss.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_number_of_incoming_connections_on_specific_ports_with_ss.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to write a few monitoring plugins, one of which was a count of incoming connections to a specific network port. In the past I would have used netstat and a combination of grep and wc filter out only specific ports and established connections, but nowdays netstat is replaced by ss on ubuntu. ss has options to filter directly on all sorts of stuff, like state, ports, protocol, making the command I use more readable and use less pipes.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>GNUplot tips for nice looking charts from a CSV file</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/GNUplot_tips_for_nice_looking_charts_from_a_CSV_file.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/GNUplot_tips_for_nice_looking_charts_from_a_CSV_file.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to do some testing which resulted in a lot of log data. Looking at a bunch of text is not the same as seeing things graphically, this particular logdata was perfect to put in a graph. My goto favorite tool for graphs and charts is gnuplot. Not only is it very extensible, it is also reproducable. Give me a configfile and command over 'do this, then this and then such and such' in Excel to get a consistent result. In this article I'll give tips for using gnuplot, which include parsing a CSV file, a second axis, environment variables, A4 PDF's and a ton of styling options for a nice looking chart.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>totext.py - Convert URL or RSS feed to text with readability</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/totext.py-Convert_URL_or_RSS_feed_to_plaintext_with_readability.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/totext.py-Convert_URL_or_RSS_feed_to_plaintext_with_readability.html</guid>
                <description> Love plaintext? This script downloads an URL, parses it with readability and returns the plaintext (as markdown). It supports RSS feeds (will convert every article in the feed) and saves every article. My usecase is twofold. One is to convert RSS feeds to a gopher site, the second is to get full text in my RSS reader. The script contains a few workarounds for so-called cookiewalls. It also pauses between RSS feed articles to not do excessive requests. The readability part is handled by Python, no external services are used.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Simple pygopherd log analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Simple_pygopherd_log_analyzer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Simple_pygopherd_log_analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>Simple log analyzer for pygopherd. Fun if you have a gopherhole and want statistics. If you ever used Logwatch you'll feel at home.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Line total (up+down sum) in PHP Network Weathermap</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Line_total_up_down_sum_in_php_weathermap.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Line_total_up_down_sum_in_php_weathermap.html</guid>
                <description>With PHP Network Weathermap you can create a birds-eye view of network components from your monitoring system (like LibreNMS, Cacti or anything else with an RRD database). It can display simple maps with components and links between, showing up and down traffic, but also complex systems with custom components, like Nagios status, temperature or other information. For network and system administrators seeing the seperate in and out traffic of a link is fine, we can sum up two numbers. A co worker filling the role of service manager asked me if it was possible to sum up in and out and show that, including the scale (different colours depending on link usage). This co worker is not interested in the seperate up/down link speed but wants to know how much traffic a location is using in total. Using a clever workaround, you can display a line's total usage, including the scale. This article also gives some more tips on weathermap, colouring and scale.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Service checks in LibreNMS (http, all other Nagios plugins)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Service_checks_in_LibreNMS_nagios_plugins.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Service_checks_in_LibreNMS_nagios_plugins.html</guid>
                <description>LibreNMS is becoming one of my favorite monitoring tools. Setup and getting started is easy and it has enough advanced options and tunables. I recently discovered that LibreNMS is able to check services as well. Services, in this context, means, executing Nagios plugins (like check_http, check_ping, etc). This allows you to check services that SNMP does not cover by default, like HTTP(s) health checks, certificate expiry, tcp port checks (e.g. rdp) and anything for which you can write a Nagios plugin yourself. The performance data, if available, is graphed automatically. Alerting is done with the regular LibreNMS alerts. This guide covers the setup of services (it's not enabled by default) and a few basic checks, like an http health check, certificate expiry and SSH monitoring.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>tping - ping with a timestamp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/tping_ping_with_a_timestamp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/tping_ping_with_a_timestamp.html</guid>
                <description>tping is a bash alias I once got from an old co-worker. It's ping, but with a timestamp. Instead of looking at the increased icmp_seq number you now have a timestamp.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python script to talk to LibreNMS API and get alerts and hosts</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python_script_to_talk_to_LibreNMS_API_and_get_alerts_and_hosts.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python_script_to_talk_to_LibreNMS_API_and_get_alerts_and_hosts.html</guid>
                <description>This script talks to the LibreNMS API to receive a list of down devices and alerts. The LibreNMS dashboard provides widgets for alerts and host statusses, but there is no easy way to access that output via the API. Using Python I was able to get certain information and output it as HTML or text using PrettyTable. It can be included in other systems or be used in a chain of monitoring customizations. z</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Icinga2 / Nagios / Net::SNMP change the default timeout of 60 seconds</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Icinga2_Nagios_Net_SNMP_raise_default_timeout.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Icinga2_Nagios_Net_SNMP_raise_default_timeout.html</guid>
                <description>Recently a rather large amount of new infrastructure was added to one of my monitoring instances. Using SNMP exclusively, but not the fastest network or infrastructure. The SNMP checks in the Icinga2 instance started giving timeouts, which look like false positives and give unclean logs. Raising the SNMP timeout for the checks above 60 seconds was not that easy since the 60 second timeout is hardcoded in the underlying library (NET::SNMP). This article shows you how to raise that timeout on an Ubuntu 16.04 system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Essential Monitoring checks</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Essential_Monitoring_checks.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Essential_Monitoring_checks.html</guid>
                <description>In this article I'll provide a list of checks I consider essential for monitoring and why they are usefull. It's on different levels, ranging from your application (health checks), to operating system (disk usage, load) and hardware (iDrac, disks, power). Use it as a starting point when setting up your monitoring.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ncdu - for troubleshooting diskspace and inode issues</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/ncdu_-_for_troubleshooting_diskspace_and_inode_issues.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/ncdu_-_for_troubleshooting_diskspace_and_inode_issues.html</guid>
                <description>In my box of sysadmin tools there are multiple gems I use for troubleshooting servers. Since I work at a cloud provider sometimes I have to fix servers that are not mine. One of those tools is `ncdu`. It's a very usefull tool when a server has a full disk, both full of used space or full of used inodes. This article covers ncdu and shows the process of finding the culprit when you're out of disk space or inodes.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>atop is broken on Ubuntu 16.04 (version 1.26): trap divide error</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/atop_is_broken_on_Ubuntu_16.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/atop_is_broken_on_Ubuntu_16.04.html</guid>
                <description>Recently a few of my Ubuntu 16.04 machines had issues and I was troubleshooting them, noticing `atop` logs missing. atop is a very handy tool which can be setup to record system state every X minutes, and we set it up to run every 5 minutes. You can then at a later moment see what the server was doing, even sorting by disk, memory, cpu or network usage. This post discusses the error and a quick fix.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios 4 + Nagiosgraph (latest) installation on Ubuntu 12.04 &amp; 14.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_Core_4_Installation_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_Core_4_Installation_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the latest Nagios Core (4.2.1) on Ubuntu 12.04 and 14.04. Nagios is an open source computer system monitoring, network monitoring and infrastructure monitoring software application. Nagios offers monitoring and alerting services for servers, switches, applications, and services. It alerts the users when things go wrong and alerts them a second time when the problem has been resolved. The version in the Ubuntu 12.04 repositories is quite old, it is still the in the 3 branch. This guide helps to fix that by using the latest Nagios version. We also install Nagiosgraph, a plugin for Nagios which gives you graps of the metrics.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OSSEC 2.8 Server, Client, Web UI and Analogi Dashboard Installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_2.8.0_Server_Client_and_Analogi_Dashboard_on_Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_2.8.0_Server_Client_and_Analogi_Dashboard_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>OSSEC is an Open Source Host-based Intrusion Detection System that performs log analysis, file integrity checking, policy monitoring, rootkit detection, real-time alerting and active response. It runs on most operating systems, including Linux, MacOS, Solaris, HP-UX, AIX and Windows. It also includes agentless monitoring for use with for example Cisco or Juniper hardware. This tutorial covers the installation of the OSSEC 2.8 server, the standard OSSEC Web UI and the Analogi dashboard on Ubuntu 14.04. It also covers OSSEC setup with MySQL support. Last but not least it shows you how to install the OSSEC agent on a *NIX system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check if passwordless sudo can be used in a bash script or nagios check</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple trick to see if you can use passwordless sudo in a script. This for example can be usefull in a Nagios plugin which requires sudo. Instead of putting the sudo line in your README and otherwise having a NRPE Unable to parse result error, you could just give a nice warning message plus the right sudo configuration rule.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ntop-ng 1.1 installation on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ntop-ng-installation-on-Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ntop-ng-installation-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the latest ntop-ng (1.1) on Ubuntu 12.04. ntopng is the next generation version of the original ntop, a network traffic probe that shows the network usage, similar to what the popular top Unix command does. ntop is based on libpcap and it has been written in a portable way in order to virtually run on every Unix platform, MacOSX and on Win32 as well. ntopng users can use a a web browser to navigate through ntop (that acts as a web server) traffic information and get a dump of the network status. In the latter case, ntop can be seen as a simple RMON-like agent with an embedded web interface. This tutorial will walk you through the compilation and installation of ntopng from source.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Uninstall and Remove OSSEC</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Uninstall_OSSEC.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial shows you how to remove an OSSEC installation. OSSEC is installed from source (via a script), so you have to remove all the things manually instead of with your package manager.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OSSEC Server, Client, Web UI and Analogi Dashboard Installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_and_webui_and_analogi_dashboard_installation_on_Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OSSEC_and_webui_and_analogi_dashboard_installation_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>OSSEC is an Open Source Host-based Intrusion Detection System that performs log analysis, file integrity checking, policy monitoring, rootkit detection, real-time alerting and active response. It runs on most operating systems, including Linux, MacOS, Solaris, HP-UX, AIX and Windows. It also includes agentless monitoring for use with for example Cisco or Juniper hardware. This tutorial covers the installation of the OSSEC server, the standard OSSEC Web UI and the Analogi dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04. It also covers OSSEC setup with MySQL support, including a Makefile bugfix. Last but not least it shows you how to install the OSSEC agent on a *NIX system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bind DNS Query Graph Charts with GNUPlot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bind-GNUPlot-DNS-Bar-Graph.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bind-GNUPlot-DNS-Bar-Graph.html</guid>
                <description>This is a very simple script which uses GNUplot to create graphs of Bind Query logs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios - Hide all hosts in hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_-_Hide-entire-hostgroup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_-_Hide-entire-hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to hide all hosts from a hostgroup in Nagios, including the webinterface and email/sms notifications. It does however monitors and checks all the hosts in the hostgroup, so when there are problems you can view the hosts in Nagios. This is usefull for example when you have a staging, preproduction and production environment monitored by the same Nagios host, or by a Nagios cluster, and want to hide all of staging, but do want to quickly view the status when developers complain about a node.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check an OCSP server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_OCSP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_OCSP.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin to check an OCSP server. You can give it a hard coded certificate or your own one. This is sent to the OCSP server and the response is then parsed to give the correct nagios result. It is targeted at administrators who have their own OCSP and need to know when it is not working.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check Safenet HSM</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_Plugin_to_check_a_Safenet_HSM.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_Plugin_to_check_a_Safenet_HSM.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin which checks a Safenet Protectserver External HSM via the Safenet tools.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check CRL expiry in minutes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_CRL_expiry.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_plugin_to_check_CRL_expiry.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin which you can use to check if a CRL (Certificate Revocation List, public list with revoked certificates) is still valid.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin plugin to show Logstash/Kibana messages per hour</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Munin_plugin_Logstash_Kibana_messages_per_hour.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Munin_plugin_Logstash_Kibana_messages_per_hour.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple munin plugin which shows you the amount of log messages your logstash/kibana server receives per hour.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd client</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd client for use with a collectd server. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;).</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd server with web frontend</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd server. It also shows you how to set up the collectd-web frontend, an interactive gui for collectd, and has it all firewalled. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;). A collectd server is able to receive data from collectd clients.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Fix MySQL plugin on Ubuntu 12.04 and Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Debian 6 and Ubuntu 12.04 the Munin MySQL plugin does not work by default because of a missing package. Here is a little trick on fixing it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Set up the NGINX status plugin on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This post will show you how to set up the Munin plugin to monitor NGINX (nginx_request and nginx_status) and graph it. You need to change some URLs in the config because by default this is wrong.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python script to monitor a file for changes and then mail the report with the file attached.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script which checks a file's md5 hash, compares it to a previous (or given) hash and mails a report with the option of attaching the file with the email. I wrote it because I use AIDE on some systems, and I let it auto update the database. This script runs via cron before and after the AIDE run, so I have an archive of databases. But it can be used for all kind of files, not just for the AIDE database.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin optimization guide for Debian (rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice and nice)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to help you tune the performance of Munin using rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice, nice and a few other tricks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ray-Mon - PHP and Bash server status monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</guid>
                <description>Ray-Mon is a linux server monitoring script written in PHP and Bash, utilizing JSON as data storage. It requires only bash and a webserver on the client side, and only php on the server side. The client currently supports monitoring processes, uptime, updates, amount of users logged in, disk usage, RAM usage and network traffic.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios plugin to check certificates on local file system</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_check_local_certificate_files.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nagios_check_local_certificate_files.html</guid>
                <description>This is a nagios plugin to check local ssl certifcates for expiry.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Setting up Motion with FTP and Email! support</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Setting-up-motion-with-ftp-and-email-support.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Setting-up-motion-with-ftp-and-email-support.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    