<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag munin on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/munin.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag munin on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/munin.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if host is also in other hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet helps you execute actions only when a host is in another hostgroup in Ansible. For example, you might deploy munin-node via ansible, but you only want your apache and NGINX plugins deployed on your webservers, not on your database servers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin plugin to show Logstash/Kibana messages per hour</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Munin_plugin_Logstash_Kibana_messages_per_hour.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Munin_plugin_Logstash_Kibana_messages_per_hour.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple munin plugin which shows you the amount of log messages your logstash/kibana server receives per hour.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd client</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd client for use with a collectd server. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;).</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd server with web frontend</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd server. It also shows you how to set up the collectd-web frontend, an interactive gui for collectd, and has it all firewalled. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;). A collectd server is able to receive data from collectd clients.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Fix MySQL plugin on Ubuntu 12.04 and Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Debian 6 and Ubuntu 12.04 the Munin MySQL plugin does not work by default because of a missing package. Here is a little trick on fixing it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Set up the NGINX status plugin on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This little tutorial will show you how to set up the Munin plugin to monitor NGINX (nginx_request and nginx_status) and graph it. You need to change some URLs in the config because by default this is wrong.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin optimization guide for Debian (rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice and nice)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to help you tune the performance of Munin using rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice, nice and a few other tricks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    