<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag mysql on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/mysql.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag mysql on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/mysql.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>MySQL restore after a crash and disk issues</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to restore a MySQL server. The hardware had issues with the storage and required some FSCK's, disk replacements and a lot of RAID and LVM love to get working again. Which was the easy part. MySQL was a bit harder to fix. This post describes the proces I used to get MySQL working again with a recent backup. In this case it was a replicated setup so the client had no actual downtime. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Fix inconsistent Openstack volumes and instances from Cinder and Nova via the database</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Fix_inconsistent_Openstack_volumes_and_instances_from_Cinder_and_Nova_via_the_database.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Fix_inconsistent_Openstack_volumes_and_instances_from_Cinder_and_Nova_via_the_database.html</guid>
                <description>When running Openstack, sometimes the state of a volume  or an instance can be inconsistent on the cluster. Nova might find a volume attached while Cinder says the volume is detached or otherwise. Sometimes a volume deletion hangs, or a detach does not work. If you've found and fixed the underlying issue (lvm, iscsi, ceph, nfs etc...) you need to bring the database up to date with the new consistent state. Most of the time a reset-state works, sometimes you need to manually edit the database to correct the state. These snippets show you how.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Building HA Clusters with Ansible and Openstack</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</guid>
                <description>This is an extensive guide on building high available clusters with Ansible and Openstack. We'll build a Highly available cluster consisting out of two load balancers, two database servers and two application servers running a simple wordpress site. This is all done with Ansible, the cluster nodes are all on Openstack. Ansible is a super awesome orchestration tool and Openstack is a big buzzword filled software suite for datacenter virtualization.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Basic website and database backups with Duplicity</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will help you backup your website and database with Duplicity. You can safely backup your MySQL, MongoDB, website and other data to an off-site location.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Fix MySQL plugin on Ubuntu 12.04 and Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Debian 6 and Ubuntu 12.04 the Munin MySQL plugin does not work by default because of a missing package. Here is a little trick on fixing it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>RT (Request Tracker) - find and delete big attachments</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/RT_find__and_delete_big_attachments.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/RT_find__and_delete_big_attachments.html</guid>
                <description>RT (Request Tracker) can save attachments. It saves these in the database (mysql). I had an issue where my mysqldump used in backupping RT would fail due to an `mysqldump: Error 2020: Got packet bigger than 'max_allowed_packet' bytes when dumping table Attachments at row: xxxxx error. Adding the --max_allowed_packet=500M parameter to the mysqldump command didn't work, so here is how to search and find big attachments in RT using mysql.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    