<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag nrpe on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/nrpe.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag nrpe on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/nrpe.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios 4 + Nagiosgraph (latest) installation on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_Core_4_Installation_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_Core_4_Installation_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the latest Nagios Core (4.2.1) on Ubuntu 12.04 and 14.04. Nagios is an open source computer system monitoring, network monitoring and infrastructure monitoring software application. Nagios offers monitoring and alerting services for servers, switches, applications, and services. It alerts the users when things go wrong and alerts them a second time when the problem has been resolved. The version in the Ubuntu 12.04 repositories is quite old, it is still the in the 3 branch. This guide helps to fix that by using the latest Nagios version. We also install Nagiosgraph, a plugin for Nagios which gives you graps of the metrics.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install extra software in the VMWare vCenter Appliance (VCSA)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare_vCenter_Appliance_Install_Extra_Software.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare_vCenter_Appliance_Install_Extra_Software.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to install extra software in the VMWare vCenter appliance (VCSA). VMWare provides a vCenter appliance, which is a SUSE Linux Enterprise Server appliance with the VMWare vCenter server software installed. Because this is SUSE, we can add repositories and install software from there. By default it comes without repositories enabled. I needed to do this because I want to use NRPE on the vCenter appliance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check if passwordless sudo can be used in a bash script or nagios check</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_if_passwordless_sudo_can_be_used_in_a_bash_script_or_nagios_check.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple trick to see if you can use passwordless sudo in a script. This for example can be usefull in a Nagios plugin which requires sudo. Instead of putting the sudo line in your README and otherwise having a NRPE Unable to parse result error, you could just give a nice warning message plus the right sudo configuration rule.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    