<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag openssh on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/openssh.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag openssh on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/openssh.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Where is dropbearconvert on Ubuntu?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Where_is_dropbearconvert_on_ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Where_is_dropbearconvert_on_ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>Dropbear is a lightweight SSH server and client implementation, often used on embedded systems and routers. If you use the dropbear SSH client (dbclient) and want to use a private key, it needs to be in the dropbear format and cannot have a passphrase. Dropbear provides a conversion utility to convert openssh style keys to dropbear style keys, dropbearconvert, but on Ubuntu it's not in your $PATH. This means you have to provide the full path to execute it, which is cumbersome. There is a bug in Ubuntu that has been reported in 2012, but in Ubuntu 18.04 (2019) it's still not fixed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Disable motd news or (parts of) the dynamic motd on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Disable_dynamic_motd_and_motd_news_spam_on_Ubuntu_18.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Disable_dynamic_motd_and_motd_news_spam_on_Ubuntu_18.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Ubuntu 18.04 and up, when you login via SSH you are greeted with some news via motd (message of the day) that includes advertisements and messages from Canonical (via motd.ubuntu.com). This small guide shows you how to disable news, (parts of) the dynamic motd or just revert back to a plain old /etc/motd file.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSH on Windows Server 2019 (including how to sudo)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH_on_Windows_Server_2019.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH_on_Windows_Server_2019.html</guid>
                <description>On hackernews I saw a Microsoft blog post stating that Windows Server 2019 now includes OpenSSH. In this post I'll try out both the client and server on a Windows 2019 server, including how to login as a Active Directory Domain user and how to generate and place and SSH keypair. The bonus this time is how to elevate permissions via SSH on Windows, sudo but way more complicated. This guide is also applicable on Windows 10, build 1809 and up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nitrokey Start: Getting started guide (gnuk openpgp token)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_Start_Getting_started_guide.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_Start_Getting_started_guide.html</guid>
                <description>The Nitrokey Start is an OpenPGP USB token. It supports three 2048 bit GPG keys and is based on gnuk. Gnuk is an implementation of USB cryptographic token for GPG. Cryptographic token is a store of private keys and it computes cryptographic functions on the device. The main difference with other GPG cards like the Nitrokey Pro or the OpenPGP card is that this device does not use a smartcard. Whereas the other devices are basically USB smartcard readers, the Nitrokey Start has everything in it's firmware. This article is a getting started guide where I talk about the initial setup of the device, setting up a user PIN, an admin PIN and a reset code, generating the key and subkeys on the device, or loading external keys into the device and usage examples with GPG, OpenSSH and Thunderbird.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clear Uncluttered SSH client config with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>Openssh allows you to configure parameters like username, port, proxycommand, key and more in the ~/.ssh/config file. If you have many servers this file can become cluttered and maintaining it can become a not so nice task. This simple guide shows you how you can use a conf.d directory with seperate smaller files which gets converted to the big config file by Ansible</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Restrict SSH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html</guid>
                <description>restrict_ssh.sh is a bash script which restricts ssh for a user to a set of commands via .ssh/authorized_keys, and log it verbosely.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Limit access to openssh features with the Match option</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Limit_access_to_openssh_features_with_the_Match_keyword.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Limit_access_to_openssh_features_with_the_Match_keyword.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    