<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag openstack on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/openstack.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag openstack on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/openstack.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack - (Manually) migrating (KVM) Nova compute virtual machines</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_-_(Manually)_migrating_(KVM)_Nova_Compute_Virtual_Machines.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_-_(Manually)_migrating_(KVM)_Nova_Compute_Virtual_Machines.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to migrate KVM virtual machines with the  Openstack Nova compute service, either manually or with the Openstack tooling. Openstack provides a few different ways to migrate virtual machines from one compute node to another. Each option has different requirements and restrictions, for example, you can't live-migrate without shared storage. You can't live-migrate if you have a configdrive enabled. You can't select the target host if you use the nova migrate (non-live) command etc. This article describes the most common migration scenario's including live and manual migration using native linux tools.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Automating Openstack with cloud init run a script on VM's first boot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to create a VM in Openstack and execute a script at the first boot using cloud-init's user-data feature. This way you can eliminate some more manual labor and keep a small base image, instead of requiring all kinds of specific images for specific tasks. This tutorial will also give you a few example scripts to use with cloud-init and to create Openstack virtual machines from the command line. </description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Glance Image Download, download Openstack images</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack_Glance_Image_Download.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack_Glance_Image_Download.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how download Openstack Images to your local machine using the command line Glance client. You can use this, for example, to download a copy of an image created from a VM, or to download the images your Openstack provider provides and adapt those.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing Virtual Machines with virt-install, plus copy pastable distro install one-liners</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</guid>
                <description>virt-install is a command line tool for creating new KVM , Xen or Linux container guests using the libvirt hypervisor management library. It allows you to create a VM and start an installation from the command line. This article has a few copy pastable getting started examples for different distro's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Fix inconsistent Openstack volumes and instances from Cinder and Nova via the database</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Fix_inconsistent_Openstack_volumes_and_instances_from_Cinder_and_Nova_via_the_database.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Fix_inconsistent_Openstack_volumes_and_instances_from_Cinder_and_Nova_via_the_database.html</guid>
                <description>When running Openstack, sometimes the state of a volume  or an instance can be inconsistent on the cluster. Nova might find a volume attached while Cinder says the volume is detached or otherwise. Sometimes a volume deletion hangs, or a detach does not work. If you've found and fixed the underlying issue (lvm, iscsi, ceph, nfs etc...) you need to bring the database up to date with the new consistent state. Most of the time a reset-state works, sometimes you need to manually edit the database to correct the state. These snippets show you how.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Affinity Groups, make sure instances are on the same or different compute hypervisor hosts</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_Affinity_Groups-make-sure-instances-are-on-the-same-or-a-different-hypervisor-host.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Openstack_Affinity_Groups-make-sure-instances-are-on-the-same-or-a-different-hypervisor-host.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to use Openstack Affinity groups. Affinity or Anti-Affinity groups allow you to make sure instances (VM/VPS) are on the same hypervisor host or on a different one. There are cases when you want two instances on different compute nodes, for example, when they are clustered servers like a load balancer or a database master-master setup. All VMs in each Affinity group are hosted in the same hypervisor, while no two VMs of a same Anti-Affinity group are hosted in the same hypervisor.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.1-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.1-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Building HA Clusters with Ansible and Openstack</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</guid>
                <description>This is an extensive guide on building high available clusters with Ansible and Openstack. We'll build a Highly available cluster consisting out of two load balancers, two database servers and two application servers running a simple wordpress site. This is all done with Ansible, the cluster nodes are all on Openstack. Ansible is a super awesome orchestration tool and Openstack is a big buzzword filled software suite for datacenter virtualization.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.0-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.0-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance. This tutorial is more a collection of notes than what you are used of me, it has less explanation and such, just right on steps to get started.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Horizon installation with SSL on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the Openstack Horizon (icehouse) dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04 or 14.04, including SSL setup. It features nice screenshots and even an Ansible playbook to automate it all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Swift Objectstore Access via FTP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on accessing the Openstack Swift Object Storage system using an FTP client. Openstack Swift has a beautiful API which you can program to. However, sometimes it is handy to quickly be able to access your Swift/Objectstore data without programming around it. We will use ftp-cloudfs to do this. There is also Softlayers swftp, but that does not support Keystone Authentication (2.0). ftp-cloudfs does support this. The OS X Cyberduck FTP client also has Openstack Swift support, however that is a native implementation, not using FTP. With ftp-cloudfs we can use any ftp client, from Filezilla to midnight commander.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    