<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag owa on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/owa.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag owa on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/owa.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Active Directory and Exchange Command Line Powershell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Active_Directory_Exchange_Powershell_Snippets.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Active_Directory_Exchange_Powershell_Snippets.html</guid>
                <description>This is a collection of Powershell snippets to install Active Directory, create a new Active Directory Domain, join an existing Active Directory domain and to install Microsoft Exchange 2013. The snippets were tested on Windows Server 2012 R2.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Microsoft Exchange / Active Directory Powershell script to notify users of expiring Passwords</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Microsoft_Exchange_Powershell_Script_User_Password_Expiry.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Microsoft_Exchange_Powershell_Script_User_Password_Expiry.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small PowerShell script which emails your users that their password is going to expire in X days. This is needed when you have an Active Directory and Exchange Environment, but your users do not log in to a Windows machine bound to the Active Directory, but for example a Mac OS X or Linux machine with Full Disk Encryption enabled. Then they are not notified that their password is about to expire. This script can run as a scheduled task and scan and email your users that their password is about to expire.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2007 and 2010 Autodiscovery DNS SRV record for BIND</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</guid>
                <description>This is a BIND configuration example to set up Exchange Autodiscovery. Autodiscovery is the ability for Outlook to automatically configure itself to an Exchange 2007/2010 server. The main benefit is for remote users to use Outlook on the Internet as if it was connected on the LAN, this is called Outlook Anywhere or Outlook RPC over HTTP. This is very easily accomplished by having a specific DNS record available for the domain. However, the only examples Microsoft gives you are for their own software. This is the BIND version of the record.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2010 - OWA - Lock user after x amount of failed logins</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to set up automatic user lockout in Exchange 2010 - Outlook Web Acces (OWA). When a user does 5 wrong login attempts, he/she is locked out from the webinterface. After for example 5 minutes he or she is unlocked again automatically. This helps you mitigate brute force attacks, since an attacker can only try 1 password/minute, but the user will not be blocked for to long. Exchange 2010 has some special register settings to make IIS stop caching, otherwise it would not work. As a bonus you get an LDAP saved search query to view locked out users</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    