<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag owncloud on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/owncloud.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag owncloud on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/owncloud.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 02, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 02 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 51, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 51, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Owncloud, DirectAdmin, Apache 2.4 and Error AH01797: client denied by server configuration</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Owncloud_DirectAdmin,_Apache_2.4_and_Error_AH01797_client_denied_by_server_configuration.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Owncloud_DirectAdmin,_Apache_2.4_and_Error_AH01797_client_denied_by_server_configuration.html</guid>
                <description>I keep a few servers around for shared webhosting for friends, family and some other domains. Most of them run Directadmin, because it is easier to work with for the target audience. I'm very good with the command line, they've never heard of it. One of my friends runs Owncloud, a wonderfull piece of software to get cloud services under your control. He does not use the file part but rather the calendar and contacts a lot. A recent update of Apache to 2.4.10 broke that functionality on a Directadmin machine with the error AH01797: client denied by server configuration. After a bit of searching and debugging, here's how I fixed it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    