<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag pda on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/pda.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag pda on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/pda.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Bringing a Decade Old Bicycle Navigator Back to Life with Open Source Software (and DOOM)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Bringing_a_Decade_Old_Bicycle_Navigator_Back_to_Life_with_Open_Source_Software_and_DOOM.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Bringing_a_Decade_Old_Bicycle_Navigator_Back_to_Life_with_Open_Source_Software_and_DOOM.html</guid>
                <description>I recently found a Navman Bike 1000 in a thrift store for EUR 10. This is a bike computer, a navigation device for cyclists, made by MiTaC, the same company that makes the Mio bike computers. This Navman Bike 1000 is a rebadged `Mio Cyclo 200`. It's from 2015 and as you might have guessed, no more map updates.
This article shows how I dabbled a bit in reverse engineering, figuring out the device runs Windows CE 6.0 and using Total Commander and [NaVeGIS](https://sourceforge.net/projects/navegis/) together with Open Street Map to get up to date maps from the OpenFietsMap project, allowing me to use this device for navigation with the most up to date maps. Since it is all open source, even if the current map provider would stop, I can always make my own maps.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 23:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 21:31:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My 24 year old HP Jornada can do things your modern iPhone still can't do!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_24_year_old_HP_Jornada_can_do_things_your_modern_iPhone_still_cant_do.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_24_year_old_HP_Jornada_can_do_things_your_modern_iPhone_still_cant_do.html</guid>
                <description>I like to tinker with old hardware. The [DEC](https://raymii.org/s/tags/dec.html) PDP-8 is my favorite [retro computer](/s/tags/pdp-8.html) and [Office 2003](/s/blog/Using_a_Windows_Mobile_2003_PDA_hp_ipaq_in_2022_including_whatsapp.html) is the best version ever released IMHO.  One of my other favorite retro devices is the HP Jornada 720. A small `handheld PC` (smaller than a netbook) running Windows CE or in my case, Linux. It has a decent keyboard, CFL backlit screen, **32 MB of RAM(!)**, a compact Flash card for storage and a stylus for the resistive touchscreen. Oh and I got a 10Mbit PCMCIA network card, but wireless cards are also still available. It might be old, released in 1999, but can do one thing your modern iPhone can't. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 01:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Using a Windows Mobile 2003 PDA (HP iPAQ h4350) in 2022, including WhatsApp!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_a_Windows_Mobile_2003_PDA_hp_ipaq_in_2022_including_whatsapp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_a_Windows_Mobile_2003_PDA_hp_ipaq_in_2022_including_whatsapp.html</guid>
                <description>While cleaning out my collection of electronics, I found a PDA. Not the modern kind (voice assistant), but the old school precursor to the smartphone. It's a HP iPAQ h4350, it was a model used by the Dutch Railways. I picked it up in working condition years ago and was wondering, how does a mobile device from 2003 stack up to a modern smartphone? The first thing I did was run linux on it which worked surprisingly well, it however was noticeably slower than Windows Mobile. This post shows you how well the device still works in 2022, including using WhatsApp to chat. Almost all things I use my smartphone for, I can do with this PDA!</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 01:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    