<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag php on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/php.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag php on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/php.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>I enforced the AGPL on my code, here's how it went</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_enforced_the_AGPL_on_my_code_heres_how_it_went.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/I_enforced_the_AGPL_on_my_code_heres_how_it_went.html</guid>
                <description>Five years ago I made a website that allowed you to put in a few domains and get an email when the SSL certificate was about to expire. No ads, no fuss, just an easy way for people to keep tabs on their sites without setting up their own monitoring like Nagios. As with all of my software, I released it under the AGPL due to it being web based software.
Recently I found a company that hosted certificatemonitor, with some modifications (branding and a dutch tanslation), without any reference to its origin, no source code provided and no mention of the license.
In this article I'll talk about what I did to enforce the license and how it went. TL;DR, not as expected. The company responded timely and friendly, but did a half assed attempt (added a link to my site with 'Inspired By Remy' as the text), then after my complaints, took down the entire site.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Tiny Tiny RSS vs Miniflux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny_Tiny_RSS_vs_Miniflux.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny_Tiny_RSS_vs_Miniflux.html</guid>
                <description>I'm an heavy user of RSS feeds, having over 1500 feeds I follow. Without a decent feed reader that setup wouldn't work. For over eight years now I've been an happy user of Tiny Tiny RSS, a web based feed reader. But, recently I found out about 'miniflux', also a web based RSS reader. In this article I'll compare the two for my use cases, mostly mobile usage. TD;DR, I've switched to Miniflux, due to it being more suited for mobile usage, less ajax heavy, easier to subscribe to feeds and a more pleasant reading layout.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Tiny Tiny RSS + Readability == The best way to read RSS feeds</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS-Readability-plaintext.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS-Readability-plaintext.html</guid>
                <description>Back in 2012, I already wrote about Tiny Tiny RSS. We're now almost eight years later and I still use TT-RSS as my main RSS reader. I'm following almost a thousand feeds (944) and it is my main way of reading and discovering stuff online. All those personal blogs that post once half a year, mainline tech news sites and a bunch more sites. Back in 2012 I had 300 feeds, used the Android app. Nowdays, more feeds, still use the android app, used an iPhone app for a while and the server that it runs on has been migrated and upgraded a few times. I want to share my Tiny Tiny RSS setup with you, which uses the af_readability plugin. Combined with the Android app, I've got an ideal setup to read just content without distractions. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Migrating personal webapps and services</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I've migrated some of my personal servers and services to new machines and newer operating system versions. I prefer to migrate instead of upgrading the OS for a number of reasons. I'll also talk about the migration process and some stuff to remember when migrating web applications and services.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL Decoder Script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenSSL_Decoder.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenSSL_Decoder.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple PHP script which decodes a certificate, csr or connection and displays the information it finds.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ray-Mon - PHP and Bash server status monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</guid>
                <description>Ray-Mon is a linux server monitoring script written in PHP and Bash, utilizing JSON as data storage. It requires only bash and a webserver on the client side, and only php on the server side. The client currently supports monitoring processes, uptime, updates, amount of users logged in, disk usage, RAM usage and network traffic.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Codename Geld</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Codename_Geld.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Codename_Geld.html</guid>
                <description>Codename Geld is a finance manager written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the values and the visual side is created with the excellent HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke. It is not as fancy as mint.com or gnucash, so if you need advanced features (multiple accounts for example) you might want to use another piece of software. Also, the code is quite messy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NutsManager</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/NutsManager.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/NutsManager.html</guid>
                <description>NutsManager is a power/gas/water usage tracker written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the values and the visual side is created with the excellent HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke. The graphs are made with the flot framework. It helps me to keep track of my power usage, and shows me on which days I use a lot, and on which days I do not. That way, I know that a LAN party costs me a lot. Also, the code is quite messy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>PHP Task/Todo list</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/PHP-task-list-v2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/PHP-task-list-v2.html</guid>
                <description>This is a task/todo list written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the tasks, and the visual side is created with the HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Tiny Tiny RSS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS.html</guid>
                <description>Tiny Tiny RSS is an open source web-based news feed (RSS/Atom) reader and aggregator, designed to allow you to read news from any location, while feeling as close to a real desktop application as possible. I will go over the features of TIny Tiny RSS, compare it to Google Reader and write some things I like about it, and things I miss about it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Introduction to DokuWiki</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dokuwiki_Overview.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dokuwiki_Overview.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    