<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag php on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/php.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag php on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/php.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Migrating personal webapps and services</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I've migrated some of my personal servers and services to new machines and newer operating system versions. I prefer to migrate instead of upgrading the OS for a number of reasons. I'll also talk about the migration process and some stuff to remember when migrating web applications and services.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL Decoder Script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenSSL_Decoder.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenSSL_Decoder.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple PHP script which decodes a certificate, csr or connection and displays the information it finds.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ray-Mon - PHP and Bash server status monitoring</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_PHP_Server_Status_Monitor.html</guid>
                <description>Ray-Mon is a linux server monitoring script written in PHP and Bash, utilizing JSON as data storage. It requires only bash and a webserver on the client side, and only php on the server side. The client currently supports monitoring processes, uptime, updates, amount of users logged in, disk usage, RAM usage and network traffic.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Codename Geld</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Codename_Geld.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Codename_Geld.html</guid>
                <description>Codename Geld is a finance manager written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the values and the visual side is created with the excellent HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke. It is not as fancy as mint.com or gnucash, so if you need advanced features (multiple accounts for example) you might want to use another piece of software. Also, the code is quite messy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NutsManager</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/NutsManager.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/NutsManager.html</guid>
                <description>NutsManager is a power/gas/water usage tracker written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the values and the visual side is created with the excellent HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke. The graphs are made with the flot framework. It helps me to keep track of my power usage, and shows me on which days I use a lot, and on which days I do not. That way, I know that a LAN party costs me a lot. Also, the code is quite messy.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>PHP Task/Todo list</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/PHP-task-list-v2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/PHP-task-list-v2.html</guid>
                <description>This is a task/todo list written in PHP. It uses a JSON text file for the tasks, and the visual side is created with the HTML5 Kickstart framework by Joshua Gatcke.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Tiny Tiny RSS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Tiny-Tiny-RSS.html</guid>
                <description>Tiny Tiny RSS is an open source web-based news feed (RSS/Atom) reader and aggregator, designed to allow you to read news from any location, while feeling as close to a real desktop application as possible. I will go over the features of TIny Tiny RSS, compare it to Google Reader and write some things I like about it, and things I miss about it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Introduction to DokuWiki</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dokuwiki_Overview.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dokuwiki_Overview.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    