<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag pki on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/pki.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag pki on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/pki.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Deborphan cleanup until no more orphaned packages left</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html</guid>
                <description>Deborphan removes packages it thinks your system doesn't need anymore. It is a great tool for package cleanup and maintenance. Sometimes, after cleaning up the packages, it will find new packages that are orphaned (because you just cleaned up). This is a small script that cleans up with deborphan until there is nothing more to cleanup.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypt and decrypt files to public keys via the OpenSSL Command Line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypt_and_decrypt_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypt_and_decrypt_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</guid>
                <description>This small tutorial will show you how to use the openssl command line to encrypt and decrypt a file using a public key. We will first generate a random key, encrypt that random key against the public key of the other person and use that random key to encrypt the actual file with using symmetric encryption.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Sign and verify text/files to public keys via the OpenSSL Command Line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Sign_and_verify_text_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Sign_and_verify_text_files_to_public_keys_via_the_OpenSSL_Command_Line.html</guid>
                <description>This small guide will shows you how to use the OpenSSL Command Line to sign a file, and how to verify the signing of this file. You can do this to prove ownership of a key, or to prove that a file hasn't been modified since you signed it. This works both with small text files as well as huge photo's, documents or PDF files.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Find all services using libssl to restart after an OpenSSL update</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html</guid>
                <description>When you update OpenSSL, the software that currently has the ssl libraries loaded in memory do not automatically load the updated libraries. A full system reboot resolves that problem, but sometimes that is not possible. This command shows you all the software that has loaded the libraries, allowing you to restart only those services. If you don't restart or reload after an update, the software might still be vulnerable to issues that the update fixed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL command line Root and Intermediate CA including OCSP, CRL and revocation</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL and_revocation.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenSSL_command_line_Root_and_Intermediate_CA_including_OCSP_CRL and_revocation.html</guid>
                <description>These are quick and dirty notes on generating a certificate authority (CA), intermediate certificate authorities and end certificates using the OpenSSL command line tools. It includes OCSP, CRL and CA Issuer information and specific issue and expiry dates. We'll set up our own root CA. We'll use the root CA to generate an example intermediate CA. We'll use the intermediate CA to sign end user certificates.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL One liner to create self signed certificate</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_One_line_to_create_self_signed_certificate.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_One_line_to_create_self_signed_certificate.html</guid>
                <description>This is a one-liner for OpenSSL to generate a self signed certificate and private key.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Dogtag / Red Hat Certificate System reset admin pkiconsole password</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dogtag_Red_Hat_Certificate_System_Reset_Admin_pkiconsole_Password.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Dogtag_Red_Hat_Certificate_System_Reset_Admin_pkiconsole_Password.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to reset the password for the PKI Console within the Red Hat Certificate System (Dogtag).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL Generate CSR non-interactive</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_generate_CSR_non-interactivemd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_generate_CSR_non-interactivemd.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short command to generate a CSR (certificate signing request) with openssl without being prompted for the values which go in the certificate's Subject field.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL match certificate and private key</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_match_certificate_with_private_key.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_match_certificate_with_private_key.html</guid>
                <description>This check lets you know if a certificate matches a private key. Today I had to set up something but I kept getting ssl errors. Turns out, the certificate did not match the private key, because the private key file was damaged. This is how I found out.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL one liner to get expiry date from SSL Certificate of any website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Get_Certificate_Expiry_Date_and_Other_Info.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Get_Certificate_Expiry_Date_and_Other_Info.html</guid>
                <description>This little openssl one liner gets the expiry date from a website's ssl certificate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    