<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag proxmox-ve on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/proxmox-ve.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag proxmox-ve on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/proxmox-ve.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - pre-backup all container dump script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</guid>
                <description>This simple script creates a vzdump of all the OpenVZ containers on a machine. It can be used before an actual backup, in my case the actual backup excludes the container path /var/lib/vz/private. This because a dump is easier to backup because it has much less files in it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - Container to Template</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to convert an OpenVZ (Proxmox) container to a template. You can then use this template on any other OpenVZ (or proxmox) host. This can be used either to migrate containers or to create a kind of master image to deploy new hosts from.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Proxmox VE - One Public IP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to set up Proxmox with only one public IP. We will configure an extra interface bridge and make sure VM traffic is NATed. I have a few dedicated servers, some run Proxmox. Most of them however have only a few IP's. Therefore the VM's in proxmox cannot all have a public IP. For most of them that is not a problem. If needed I run a proxy or set up iptables to forward ports to the VM's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ProxBash - a bash script to manage Proxmox VE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</guid>
                <description>ProxMox VE is a very nice piece of software to setup a VM host very fast, which also is easy manageable via a webinterface. It supports both OpenVZ and KVM. I use it to manage a few VM's to test stuff on and it works really great. However, I'm a command line lover, and I thought it would be nice to be able to 'Manage' Proxmox VE from a bash shell. And I've written a script to do just that. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    