<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag python on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/python.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag python on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/python.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.3-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.3-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.3-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.3-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible playbook for GoAccess Log Analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible_role_for_GoAccess_Log_Analyzer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible_role_for_GoAccess_Log_Analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small Ansible playbook to deploy the GoAccess log analyzer on Debian based systems. Next to Piwik, I use goaccess myself to get better insights in who and what visits my servers. This role is ment to be included in your webserver playbooks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 01, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_01_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_01_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 01 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 51, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 51, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do action if on specific distribution (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS or RHEL) or distribution version (ubuntu precise, ubuntu trusty)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if you are on a certain distribution. You might have a mixed environment with CentOS and Debian and when using Ansible to execute actions on nodes you don't need to run Yum on Debian, or Apt on CentOS. Some package names are different and such, so this helps you with an only if statement to select a specific distribution. As a bonus, you also get an only_if for specific distribution versions, like Ubuntu precise (12.04 LTS) or Ubuntu trusty (14.04 LTS).</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Automating Openstack with cloud init run a script on VM's first boot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to create a VM in Openstack and execute a script at the first boot using cloud-init's user-data feature. This way you can eliminate some more manual labor and keep a small base image, instead of requiring all kinds of specific images for specific tasks. This tutorial will also give you a few example scripts to use with cloud-init and to create Openstack virtual machines from the command line. </description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python: build dynamic web pages</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Python_build_dynamic_web_pages.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Python_build_dynamic_web_pages.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you various ways of creating a dynamic webpage. It covers iframes, widgets and a few Python modules including Tornado, feedparser and JSON. We'll build a page which has RSS feeds, the weather and the current exchange rates.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Euclid's algorithm: recursion and python</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Euclids_algorithm_recursion_and_python.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Euclids_algorithm_recursion_and_python.html</guid>
                <description>This article talks about Euclids Algorithm. The problem that Euclid's algorithm solves is easy enough to understand: what is the largest common divisor of two integers? Take the numbers 100 and 80, for example: what's the largest number that divides into both? It walks us through Python example code explaining the function.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if host is also in other hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet helps you execute actions only when a host is in another hostgroup in Ansible. For example, you might deploy munin-node via ansible, but you only want your apache and NGINX plugins deployed on your webservers, not on your database servers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.1-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.1-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get the current or all Firefox tab urls in Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This snippets gets the current firefox tab url or all the firefox tab url's. It uses the sessionstore.js file in your profile folder.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Building HA Clusters with Ansible and Openstack</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</guid>
                <description>This is an extensive guide on building high available clusters with Ansible and Openstack. We'll build a Highly available cluster consisting out of two load balancers, two database servers and two application servers running a simple wordpress site. This is all done with Ansible, the cluster nodes are all on Openstack. Ansible is a super awesome orchestration tool and Openstack is a big buzzword filled software suite for datacenter virtualization.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.0-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.0-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance. This tutorial is more a collection of notes than what you are used of me, it has less explanation and such, just right on steps to get started.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Horizon installation with SSL on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the Openstack Horizon (icehouse) dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04 or 14.04, including SSL setup. It features nice screenshots and even an Ansible playbook to automate it all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Swift Objectstore Access via FTP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on accessing the Openstack Swift Object Storage system using an FTP client. Openstack Swift has a beautiful API which you can program to. However, sometimes it is handy to quickly be able to access your Swift/Objectstore data without programming around it. We will use ftp-cloudfs to do this. There is also Softlayers swftp, but that does not support Keystone Authentication (2.0). ftp-cloudfs does support this. The OS X Cyberduck FTP client also has Openstack Swift support, however that is a native implementation, not using FTP. With ftp-cloudfs we can use any ftp client, from Filezilla to midnight commander.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible Inventory from VMWare</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible__Dynamic_Inventory_From_VMware_vCenter.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible__Dynamic_Inventory_From_VMware_vCenter.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple script which lets you use VMWare vCenter as a dynamic inventory for Ansible.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Playbook Testing</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible article shows you how to run a basic test on your playbooks to check if their syntax is correct. It shows methods for both Ansible 1.3 and 1.4. When you get more complicated Ansible playbooks you sometimes have syntax (YAML) errors in them. It sometimes can take a while before those errors show up because they are lower in a playbook. By running the syntax check you make sure this won't happen.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do something if another action changed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how execute actions only if another action has changed. For example, a playbook which downloads a remote key for package signing but only executes the apt-add command if the key has changed. Or a playbook which clones a git repository and only restarts a service if the git repository has changed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Sudo sometimes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how run some actions via sudo and some not. It also shows you how to run an entire role via sudo or not.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP Email Backup.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a bowsable HTML archive and a Maildir folder. Not one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view and no proprietary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password. This release has a few major new features, namely support to backup all available folders in one go and a conversion from HTML Kickstart to Bootstrap.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>bdsh - Whitelist Restricted Shell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</guid>
                <description>A shell where you whitelist commands and only those commands can be executed. Either via ssh, as an interactive shell or launched with commands. Logs everything and escapes dangerous characters. bdsh stands for Boa Diminish SHell. You can probably guess why. It might have to to with snakes and restricting users, no pun intended.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - sudoers safety and sanity checking in playbook</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</guid>
                <description>Using Ansible to manage the /etc/sudoers file is fine, except when you have a syntax error in your template. This method helps you to only deploy a correct sudoers file.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - pure ssh based configuration management and deployment</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will get you started with Ansible. Ansible is a radically simple model-driven configuration management, deployment, and command execution framework. Other tools in this space have been too complicated for too long, require too much bootstrapping, and have too much learning curve. By comparison, Ansible is dead simple and painless to extend. Puppet and Chef have about 60k lines of code. Ansibles core is a little over 2000 lines.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install python 2.7 or 3 under Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_Python_2.7_or_3_on_debian_6.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_Python_2.7_or_3_on_debian_6.html</guid>
                <description>Debian 6 by default ships with python 2.6.6. If for some reason need a newer version of python you can either mess with repo's, compile from source or use pythonbrew. This tutorial will show you how to install python 2.7 or 3 under debian 6 using pythonbrew.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python script to monitor a file for changes and then mail the report with the file attached.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script which checks a file's md5 hash, compares it to a previous (or given) hash and mails a report with the option of attaching the file with the email. I wrote it because I use AIDE on some systems, and I let it auto update the database. This script runs via cron before and after the AIDE run, so I have an archive of databases. But it can be used for all kind of files, not just for the AIDE database.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Terrible Start</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Terrible-start.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Terrible-start.html</guid>
                <description>This is a python based Linux start/welcome screen written for Terrible Linux</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>MagicProg: Magic the Gathering (RPG/TGC) Life Program </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Magicprog.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Magicprog.html</guid>
                <description>I'm a fervent [Magic the Gathering][7] player. If you do not know what magic is, scroll down for an explanation. I play it a lot in my free time, and I participate in bootserdrafts and casual tournaments here locally. I've developed a program to keep the life in a 2 player game. It's called MagicProg. It will also work for TGC's like pokemon, yu-gi-oh, WoW TCG or any other TGC. And it has a note area.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Stopping fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication error and other errors in fail2ban on ubuntu 9.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to stop fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication errors on Ubuntu 9.04.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP email backup to HTML archive.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a HTML archive, nicely browsable, instead of weird folders (Maildir), one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view (thunderbird) and no propritary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    