<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag python on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/python.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag python on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/python.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Site update, self-hosted search via pagefind</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_self_hosted_search_via_pagefind.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_self_hosted_search_via_pagefind.html</guid>
                <description>This is a static site, meaning that no server-side processing occurs. All HTML is generated out of a few folders full of markdown source and then uploaded to the cluster. Searching on this site was always provided by a text-box form that sent you to google with 'site:raymii.org' appended to it. Works fine, but it sends all data to Google. With my recent removal of all Google Ads on this site, as well as tracking via Google Analytics, sending searches via Google seems wrong. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I recently found the `pagefind` program which I now use on here, it is a self hosted static site search engine of sorts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 21:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 21:32:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site update, cookie consent popup (for a static site)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_cookie_consent_popup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_cookie_consent_popup.html</guid>
                <description>A small site update this time, just to let you know that I've added a cookie consent popup to this static site. If you reject all cookies, you should not see any advertisements and aren't tracked by Google Analytics. It's open source, cookieconsent by Orest Bida.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 19:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, new font for better contrast and other small CSS fixes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_font_for_better_contrast.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_font_for_better_contrast.html</guid>
                <description>New year, time for some site updates. This site is generated with my self-written open source static site generator named ingsoc (named after 1984) and this update is a collection of  small improvements. A new font, internal code updates to the generator and a few CSS fixes here and there. This article goes over all of them including screenshots before and after!</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>What does raymii.org cost to run?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Costs_to_run_raymii.org.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Costs_to_run_raymii.org.html</guid>
                <description>Inspired by recent articles from Kev Quirk, Horst Gutmann and Jan-Lukas where they do a cost breakdown of their sites, I decided to do one as well. Kev is around USD 30, Horst is around USD 13 and Jan-Lukas is around 5 USD. Their breakdowns are interesting, from specific wordpress plugins to CDN or DNS costs. I don't have those, but I do have a multitude of small servers running this site, which add up to around USD 20, adding up two domain names gives me around USD 22 per month. It could be a lot cheaper, I only need one server for the gigantuous amounts of static HTML this site consists of, but I do have around 10.000 unique visitors each day, so having redundancy is nice. If I would go all cheap, this site would cost me no more than 2 USD a month including the domain name, but that would take the fun out of it. This article features a list of similar, how much does my site cost articles and a cost breakdown of this site.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Store multiple types in a single std::map in C++ with std::any, just like a python dict</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Store_multiple_types_in_a_single_stdmap_in_cpp_just_like_a_python_dict.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Store_multiple_types_in_a_single_stdmap_in_cpp_just_like_a_python_dict.html</guid>
                <description>In C++, everything has a type. When declaring a function you specify the return type and for each parameter you specify what type it is, just as for regular variables. Templates aside (those still have a type), you almost always know what type of data you're working with. There is the 'auto' keyword, which can save you a lot of typing and duplicate code, but fundamentally you're still working with types. Since C++ 17 you can use 'std::any' to store anything, without knowing the type. This is awesome for some tasks, and horrific for most use cases. In this article I'll show an example of a 'std::map' with 'std::any', that behaves like a python 'dict', it's able to store multiple different types in the same container.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Local incremental backups of Google Photos on Ubuntu with gphotos-sync</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Local_incremental_Google_Photos_backup_on_Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Local_incremental_Google_Photos_backup_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>'Google Photos' no longer syncs with 'Google Drive' or with their 'Backup and Sync' desktop software. There used to be a checkbox to get your 'Google Photos' pictures in 'Google Drive' but that has been disabled. I used that feature together with their 'Backup and Sync' tool to sync all the photos in 'Google Photos' to my local Windows computer. From there I use 'DigiKam'  to manage the photos and backup them offline and offsite. Due to Google removing that feature, I had to go find another way to get the pictures out of 'Google Photos', which, after a few months of (automated) use, 'gphotos-sync' on Ubuntu seems to be the best, stable choice. In this guide I'll show you how to setup incremental backups from 'Google Photos' on Ubuntu. My 'DigiKam' database moved over without problems, and now I'm glad I don't have to use Windows for picture managemant anymore.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>C++ create and write to a CSV file with a variadic template</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_create_and_write_to_a_CSV_file_with_a_variadic_template.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_create_and_write_to_a_CSV_file_with_a_variadic_template.html</guid>
                <description>In this snippet I'll show you a variadic template to write to a file. In line with my other experiments to get a better grasp at templates, this example improves on my earlier attempt by using a variadic template, thus allowing you to provide an infinite number of columns to the csv file of any type that has the overloaded &lt;&lt; operator.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>C++ variadic template recursive example</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_variadic_template_recursive_example.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_variadic_template_recursive_example.html</guid>
                <description>In this article I'll show you how to use a variadic template in C++. Variadic templates allow you to have a template with a variable number of arguments, also called a parameter pack. Unpacking that pack is more difficult than it should be, so we use a recursive template to iterate over all the parameters one by one. I've also included an example in Python to compare to.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, new layout</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updated_new_2019_layout.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updated_new_2019_layout.html</guid>
                <description>This site is generated with my self-written open source static site generator named ingsoc (named after 1984). I've updated the layout of the website to be less cluttered, allowing you to get to the content much faster. Inspired by my recent gopher adventures I decided to do away with the 2 column layout (drop the sidebar with menu) and have a smaller header with essential links. On mobile this makes a huge difference in scrolling, on the desktop it looks less cluttered. This article details all the changes with side by side images showing differences.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>totext.py - Convert URL or RSS feed to text with readability</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/totext.py-Convert_URL_or_RSS_feed_to_plaintext_with_readability.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/totext.py-Convert_URL_or_RSS_feed_to_plaintext_with_readability.html</guid>
                <description> Love plaintext? This script downloads an URL, parses it with readability and returns the plaintext (as markdown). It supports RSS feeds (will convert every article in the feed) and saves every article. My usecase is twofold. One is to convert RSS feeds to a gopher site, the second is to get full text in my RSS reader. The script contains a few workarounds for so-called cookiewalls. It also pauses between RSS feed articles to not do excessive requests. The readability part is handled by Python, no external services are used.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Simple pygopherd log analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Simple_pygopherd_log_analyzer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Simple_pygopherd_log_analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>Simple log analyzer for pygopherd. Fun if you have a gopherhole and want statistics. If you ever used Logwatch you'll feel at home.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, raymii.org now also available on Gopher</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_raymii.org_now_on_gopher.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_raymii.org_now_on_gopher.html</guid>
                <description>I've made some new improvements to this website, you can now view raymii.org on Gopher! Building on the last site improvement, every article being available as plain text, it was easy to generate a gophermap file and bind it all together with pygopherd.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get a JSON value with bash and sed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_json_value_with_sed.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_json_value_with_sed.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I was asked to get one value from a json object using only shell tools. The json in question is from a dutch radio station and it lists the current song that is played. Using this together with a few shell commands and notify-send we can show the current song when it changes as a desktop notification. I'd rather use Python or jq if it has to be shell. In this case the co-worker asked to just use simple shell tools and no external dependencies.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do action if on specific distribution (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS or RHEL) or distribution version (ubuntu precise, ubuntu trusty)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</guid>
                <description>This ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if you are on a certain distribution. You might have a mixed environment with CentOS and Debian, when using ansible to execute actions on different servers you don't need to run yum on debian, or apt on CentOS. Some package names are different and such, so this helps you with a when statement to select a specific distribution. As a bonus, you also get a when for specific distribution versions, like Ubuntu precise (12.04 LTS) or Ubuntu trusty (14.04 LTS).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do something if another action changed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how execute actions only if another action has changed. For example, a playbook which downloads a remote key for package signing but only executes the apt-add command if the key has changed. Or a playbook which clones a git repository and only restarts a service if the git repository has changed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Add an apt-repository on Debian and Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Add_an_apt-repository_on_Debian_and_Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Add_an_apt-repository_on_Debian_and_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide that shows you how to add an apt repository to Debian and Ubuntu using Ansible. It includes both the old way, when the apt modules only worked on Ubuntu, and the new way, now that the apt-modules also support Debian, plus some other tricks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Line total (up+down sum) in PHP Network Weathermap</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Line_total_up_down_sum_in_php_weathermap.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Line_total_up_down_sum_in_php_weathermap.html</guid>
                <description>With PHP Network Weathermap you can create a birds-eye view of network components from your monitoring system (like LibreNMS, Cacti or anything else with an RRD database). It can display simple maps with components and links between, showing up and down traffic, but also complex systems with custom components, like Nagios status, temperature or other information. For network and system administrators seeing the seperate in and out traffic of a link is fine, we can sum up two numbers. A co worker filling the role of service manager asked me if it was possible to sum up in and out and show that, including the scale (different colours depending on link usage). This co worker is not interested in the seperate up/down link speed but wants to know how much traffic a location is using in total. Using a clever workaround, you can display a line's total usage, including the scale. This article also gives some more tips on weathermap, colouring and scale.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Service checks in LibreNMS (http, all other Nagios plugins)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Service_checks_in_LibreNMS_nagios_plugins.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Service_checks_in_LibreNMS_nagios_plugins.html</guid>
                <description>LibreNMS is becoming one of my favorite monitoring tools. Setup and getting started is easy and it has enough advanced options and tunables. I recently discovered that LibreNMS is able to check services as well. Services, in this context, means, executing Nagios plugins (like check_http, check_ping, etc). This allows you to check services that SNMP does not cover by default, like HTTP(s) health checks, certificate expiry, tcp port checks (e.g. rdp) and anything for which you can write a Nagios plugin yourself. The performance data, if available, is graphed automatically. Alerting is done with the regular LibreNMS alerts. This guide covers the setup of services (it's not enabled by default) and a few basic checks, like an http health check, certificate expiry and SSH monitoring.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python script to talk to LibreNMS API and get alerts and hosts</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python_script_to_talk_to_LibreNMS_API_and_get_alerts_and_hosts.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python_script_to_talk_to_LibreNMS_API_and_get_alerts_and_hosts.html</guid>
                <description>This script talks to the LibreNMS API to receive a list of down devices and alerts. The LibreNMS dashboard provides widgets for alerts and host statusses, but there is no easy way to access that output via the API. Using Python I was able to get certain information and output it as HTML or text using PrettyTable. It can be included in other systems or be used in a chain of monitoring customizations. z</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates for accessibility, text only pages and skip to main content</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_Improvements_for_accessibility.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_Improvements_for_accessibility.html</guid>
                <description>I've made some new improvements to this website. Raymii.org is generated using my self-written static site generator named ingsoc, the new features are focussed on accessibility. If you are using a screen reader or command-line browser this will benefit you. Or if you like to archive stuff offline. The two main improvements are a text-only version of every content page (article/tutorial etc) and a 'Skip to main content' link.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>log_vcs - Ansible callback plugin that creates VCS (git) branches for every Ansible run</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/log_vcs_-_Ansible_Callback_plugin_that_creates_git_branches_for_every_ansible_run.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/log_vcs_-_Ansible_Callback_plugin_that_creates_git_branches_for_every_ansible_run.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible callback plugin creates a VCS branch every time you run Ansible. If you ever need to go back to a certain state or environment, check out that branch and be sure nothing has changed. This is useful when you have multiple environments or multiple people deploying and continually develop your Ansible. When you often deploy to test / acceptance and less often to production, you can checkout the last branch that deployed to production if a hotfix or other maintenance is required, without having to search back in your commits and logs. I would recommend to develop infrastructure features in feature branches and have the master branch always deployable to production. However, reality learns that that is not always the case and this is a nice automatic way to have a fallback.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, new layout for overview pages</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_layout_for_overview_pages.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_layout_for_overview_pages.html</guid>
                <description>This site is generated with my self-written open source static site generator named ingsoc (named after 1984). I've updated the overview pages with a new layout so that items are sorted by their publishing date instead of alphabetically. I've also rewritten some internal logic regarding tags and categories. This article shows the difference before and after and includes some old screenshots of raymii.org.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - add apt_key inline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ansible_-_add_apt_key_inline.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ansible_-_add_apt_key_inline.html</guid>
                <description>Using the apt_key module one can add an APT key with ansible. You can get the key from a remote server or from a file, or just a key ID. I got the request to do some stuff on a machine which was quite rescricted (so no HKP protocol) and I was asked not to place to many files on the machine. The apt_key was needed but it could not be a file, so using a YAML Literal Block Scalar I was able to add the key inline in the playbook. Not the best way to do it, but one of the many ways Ansible allows it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenStack: Quick and automatic instance snapshot backup and restore (and before an apt upgrade) with nova backup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenStack_Quick_and_automatic_instance_snapshot_backups.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenStack_Quick_and_automatic_instance_snapshot_backups.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide that shows you how to create OpenStack instance snapshots automatically, quick and easy. This allows you to create a full backup of the entire instance. This guide has a script that makes creating snapshots from an OpenStack VM automatic via cron. The script uses the `nova backup` function, therefore it also has retention and rotation of the backups. It also features an option to create a snapshot before every apt action, upgrade/install/remove. This way, you can easily restore from the snapshot when something goes wrong after an upgrade. Snapshots are very usefull to restore the entire instance to an earlier state. Do note that this is not the same as a file based backup, you can't select a few files to restore, it's all or nothing.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Overflow the Investigatory Powers Bill!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Overflow_the_Investigatory_Powers_Bill.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Overflow_the_Investigatory_Powers_Bill.html</guid>
                <description>I read an article on The Register regarding the Investigatory Powers Bill. The part were ISP's are forced to save their customers browsing history for a year is the most horryfing part, just as that whole bill. Let's hope the political process and organizations like the Open Rights Group and the EFF have enough lobbying power to change people's minds.	If that fails, then we can all try to overflow the logging. Just as some people put keywords in their mail signatures to trigger automatic filters and generate noise, we should all generate as much data and noise as possible. This way the information they do gather will not be usefull, it will take too much time, storage and effort to process it and thus the project will fail. 2 years ago I wrote a small Python script which browser the web for you, all the time. Running that on one or two Raspberry Pi's or other small low power computers 24/7 will generate a lot of noise in the logging and filtering.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 11.0-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_11.0-release_Openstack_Image.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_11.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 11.0-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance. A FreeBSD image with Cloud Init will automatically resize the disk to the size of the flavor and it will add your SSH key right at boot. You can use Cloud Config to execute a script at first boott, for example, to bootstrap your system into Puppet or Ansible. If you use Ansible to manage OpenStack instances you can integrate it without manually logging in or doing anything manually.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Create OpenStack servers with Ansible 2.0 and the os_server module and a dynamic inventory</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_create_OpenStack_servers_with_os_server.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_create_OpenStack_servers_with_os_server.html</guid>
                <description>I regularly deploy clusters and single servers on OpenStack with Ansible. However, Ansible 2.0 comes with new OpenStack modules my playbooks still used the old ones. I reserved some time to convert these playbooks to the new modules and ansible 2. This article shows a very simple example, it creates three servers in OpenStack and adds them to different hostgroups based on variables. For example, to create one loadbalancer and two appservers and run specific playbooks on those hosts based on their role.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - create playbooks and role file and folder structure</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ansible_-_create_playbooks_and_role_file_and_folder_structure.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ansible_-_create_playbooks_and_role_file_and_folder_structure.html</guid>
                <description>Because I always forget which folders and files go into a playbook folder.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.3-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.3-release_Openstack_Image.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.3-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.3-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible playbook for GoAccess Log Analyzer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible_role_for_GoAccess_Log_Analyzer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible_role_for_GoAccess_Log_Analyzer.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small Ansible playbook to deploy the GoAccess log analyzer on Debian based systems. Next to Piwik, I use goaccess myself to get better insights in who and what visits my servers. This role is ment to be included in your webserver playbooks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Automating Openstack with cloud init run a script on VM's first boot</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Automating_Openstack_with_Cloud_init_run_a_script_on_VMs_first_boot.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to create a VM in Openstack and execute a script at the first boot using cloud-init's user-data feature. This way you can eliminate some more manual labor and keep a small base image, instead of requiring all kinds of specific images for specific tasks. This tutorial will also give you a few example scripts to use with cloud-init and to create Openstack virtual machines from the command line. </description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Euclid's algorithm: recursion and python</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Euclids_algorithm_recursion_and_python.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Euclids_algorithm_recursion_and_python.html</guid>
                <description>This article talks about Euclids Algorithm. The problem that Euclid's algorithm solves is easy enough to understand: what is the largest common divisor of two integers? Take the numbers 100 and 80, for example: what's the largest number that divides into both? It walks us through Python example code explaining the function.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only if host is also in other hostgroup</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_host_is_also_in_other_hostgroup.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet helps you execute actions only when a host is in another hostgroup in Ansible. For example, you might deploy munin-node via ansible, but you only want your apache and NGINX plugins deployed on your webservers, not on your database servers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.1-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.1-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.1-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get the current or all Firefox tab urls in Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This snippets gets the current firefox tab url or all the firefox tab url's. It uses the sessionstore.js file in your profile folder.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Building HA Clusters with Ansible and Openstack</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</guid>
                <description>This is an extensive guide on building high available clusters with Ansible and Openstack. We'll build a Highly available cluster consisting out of two load balancers, two database servers and two application servers running a simple wordpress site. This is all done with Ansible, the cluster nodes are all on Openstack. Ansible is a super awesome orchestration tool and Openstack is a big buzzword filled software suite for datacenter virtualization.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a FreeBSD 10.0-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.0-release_Openstack_Image.html</guid>
                <description>We are going to prepare a FreeBSD image for Openstack deployment. We do this by creating a FreeBSD 10.0-RELEASE instance, installing it and converting it using bsd-cloudinit. We'll use the CloudVPS public Openstack cloud for this. We'll be using the Openstack command line tools, like nova, cinder and glance. This tutorial is more a collection of notes than what you are used of me, it has less explanation and such, just right on steps to get started.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Horizon installation with SSL on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the Openstack Horizon (icehouse) dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04 or 14.04, including SSL setup. It features nice screenshots and even an Ansible playbook to automate it all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Swift Objectstore Access via FTP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on accessing the Openstack Swift Object Storage system using an FTP client. Openstack Swift has a beautiful API which you can program to. However, sometimes it is handy to quickly be able to access your Swift/Objectstore data without programming around it. We will use ftp-cloudfs to do this. There is also Softlayers swftp, but that does not support Keystone Authentication (2.0). ftp-cloudfs does support this. The OS X Cyberduck FTP client also has Openstack Swift support, however that is a native implementation, not using FTP. With ftp-cloudfs we can use any ftp client, from Filezilla to midnight commander.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible Inventory from VMWare</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible__Dynamic_Inventory_From_VMware_vCenter.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ansible__Dynamic_Inventory_From_VMware_vCenter.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple script which lets you use VMWare vCenter as a dynamic inventory for Ansible.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Playbook Testing</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Playbook_Testing.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible article shows you how to run a basic test on your playbooks to check if their syntax is correct. It shows methods for both Ansible 1.3 and 1.4. When you get more complicated Ansible playbooks you sometimes have syntax (YAML) errors in them. It sometimes can take a while before those errors show up because they are lower in a playbook. By running the syntax check you make sure this won't happen.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Sudo sometimes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how run some actions via sudo and some not. It also shows you how to run an entire role via sudo or not.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP Email Backup.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv-IMAP-backup.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a bowsable HTML archive and a Maildir folder. Not one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view and no proprietary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password. This release has a few major new features, namely support to backup all available folders in one go and a conversion from HTML Kickstart to Bootstrap.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>bdsh - Whitelist Restricted Shell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</guid>
                <description>A shell where you whitelist commands and only those commands can be executed. Either via ssh, as an interactive shell or launched with commands. Logs everything and escapes dangerous characters. bdsh stands for Boa Diminish SHell. You can probably guess why. It might have to to with snakes and restricting users, no pun intended.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - sudoers safety and sanity checking in playbook</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Sudo_Safety_and_Sanity_Checks.html</guid>
                <description>Using Ansible to manage the /etc/sudoers file is fine, except when you have a syntax error in your template. This method helps you to only deploy a correct sudoers file.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - pure ssh based configuration management and deployment</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_Deployment_Framework.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will get you started with Ansible. Ansible is a radically simple model-driven configuration management, deployment, and command execution framework. Other tools in this space have been too complicated for too long, require too much bootstrapping, and have too much learning curve. By comparison, Ansible is dead simple and painless to extend. Puppet and Chef have about 60k lines of code. Ansibles core is a little over 2000 lines.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install python 2.7 or 3 under Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_Python_2.7_or_3_on_debian_6.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_Python_2.7_or_3_on_debian_6.html</guid>
                <description>Debian 6 by default ships with python 2.6.6. If for some reason need a newer version of python you can either mess with repo's, compile from source or use pythonbrew. This tutorial will show you how to install python 2.7 or 3 under debian 6 using pythonbrew.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Python script to monitor a file for changes and then mail the report with the file attached.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Python-script-to-monitor-a-file-for-changes-and-then-mail-the-report-with-the-file-attached.html</guid>
                <description>This is a script which checks a file's md5 hash, compares it to a previous (or given) hash and mails a report with the option of attaching the file with the email. I wrote it because I use AIDE on some systems, and I let it auto update the database. This script runs via cron before and after the AIDE run, so I have an archive of databases. But it can be used for all kind of files, not just for the AIDE database.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Terrible Start</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Terrible-start.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Terrible-start.html</guid>
                <description>This is a python based Linux start/welcome screen written for Terrible Linux</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>MagicProg: Magic the Gathering (RPG/TGC) Life Program </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Magicprog.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Magicprog.html</guid>
                <description>I'm a fervent [Magic the Gathering][7] player. If you do not know what magic is, scroll down for an explanation. I play it a lot in my free time, and I participate in bootserdrafts and casual tournaments here locally. I've developed a program to keep the life in a 2 player game. It's called MagicProg. It will also work for TGC's like pokemon, yu-gi-oh, WoW TCG or any other TGC. And it has a note area.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Stopping fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication error and other errors in fail2ban on ubuntu 9.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to stop fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication errors on Ubuntu 9.04.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NoPriv.py - Easy IMAP email backup to HTML archive.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Nopriv.py.html</guid>
                <description>NoPriv.py is a python script to backup any IMAP capable email account to a HTML archive, nicely browsable, instead of weird folders (Maildir), one huge file (mbox), only needing a web browser to view (thunderbird) and no propritary code, so you can make sure I won't steal your password.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    