<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag qmk on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/qmk.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag qmk on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/qmk.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Relegendable keycaps for your macropad, the best thing ever for developer productivity</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Relegendable_keycaps_for_your_macropad.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Relegendable_keycaps_for_your_macropad.html</guid>
                <description>As you might know, I've got a weird keyboard. It is an Ergodox EZ, it's split up in two halves and for me it's the best thing ever to combat RSI. I've also got a weird mouse, a left handed vertical mouse, for the same reason. Even 15 minutes on a regular setup and my wrists and shoulders hurt. The next best thing is my standing desk and number three is having regular breaks with small exercises. One downside to the Ergodox is that you have less keys than on a regular keyboard. This is solved with layers, just like when holding SHIFT or CTRL, a key does something different. SHIFT is the layer for capital letters and symbols, with the Ergodox you can define your own layers. I however cannot get used to layers, not even after 7 years of using the Ergodox. Not a problem, I've got an extra keyboard in the middle, next to my mouse, with 8 or 9 keys just for my most often used shortcuts. It's called a macropad, one I've soldered myself and one I've bought on a well-known chinese webstore. One at work and one at home, both run QMK, firmware that allows me to program the macropad with my own shortcuts. Recently a video from Atomic Shrimp (awesome channel) showed off relegendable keycaps. Those are transparent keycaps with an insert for your own label. Before I had relegendable keycaps, I had regular keycaps for the macropad, for example, the `L` key sends `CTRL+ALT+L` to lock the desktop. Now, with these awesome keycaps, I have a dedicated `LOCK` key. This is such a big quality of life improvement, especially when using the CLion debugger shortcuts. This post covers my usage of the macropads, the re-legendable keycaps and shows you a few pictures of the macropads, both before and after.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Gherkin 30% keyboard build log and review</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Gherkin_30_key_keyboard_build_log_and_review.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Gherkin_30_key_keyboard_build_log_and_review.html</guid>
                <description>The Gherkin keyboard is a 30% (actually a 30 key) keyboard kit. I've built one and used it for a while, this article covers the build and my experiences with such a small board.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SpaceCat Launchpad v2, an awesome cool little macropad</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/SpaceCat_Launchpad_v2_an_awesome_little_macropad.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/SpaceCat_Launchpad_v2_an_awesome_little_macropad.html</guid>
                <description>On Reddit, Josh (from SpaceCat) did a valentines day action, 10% off your entire order. I'm eyeing a LaunchPad for a while now, both to have a small macro pad and to experiment with QMK (firmware). So I ordered the LaunchPad full kit, an assortment of Gateron key switches and a VIM keycap. This article goes over the quality, the build process and my current setup of the Launchpad.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Split keyboards, a five year review including the ErgoDox EZ, Matias Ergo Pro and Kinesis Freestyle 2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Split_keyboards_a_five_year_review_including_the_ErgoDox_EZ_Matias_Ergo_Pro_and_Kinesis_Freestyle_2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Split_keyboards_a_five_year_review_including_the_ErgoDox_EZ_Matias_Ergo_Pro_and_Kinesis_Freestyle_2.html</guid>
                <description>A split keyboard is weird at first, but once you get used to it, you will never want anything else. The keyboard is made up from two halves allowing your arms and wrists to be in a natural (neutral, straight) position, instead of having an angle/twist in your wrist. I've been using split keyboards for about five years now. Over those years I've tried several different models from different manufacturers. In this article I'll talk about the three split keyboards I've used intensively and two I have only seen or tried shortly. We'll start with my current and favorite split keyboard, the ErgoDox EZ. The other two I've used are the Matias Ergo Pro and the Kinesis Freestyle 2. I discuss the UHK and Microsoft Natural Ergonomic Keyboard 4000 briefly.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    