<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag raid on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/raid.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag raid on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/raid.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>That time when one of my HP-UX servers lost half of it's RAM (and how to connect to an HP iLO 2 with modern OpenSSH (7.6+))</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/That_time_one_of_my_HP-UX_machines_lost_half_its_ram_openssh_7.3_ilo_2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/That_time_one_of_my_HP-UX_machines_lost_half_its_ram_openssh_7.3_ilo_2.html</guid>
                <description>One of my favorite sayings is: 'Hardware is stupid, move everything to the cloud!'. The cloud is just someone elses computer, but at least I'm not responsible for the hardware anymore, since hardware breaks. When a VM breaks, because you use configuration management and version control, just roll out a new one. We all know that's not true, but still, the thought of it is nice. Last week one of the HP-UX machines had a failing disk and this week it's back with a whole new issue. After it was rebooted (due to issues with the services running on it), the Event Monitoring Service (EMS) sent an email regarding RAM issues and after manual checking it seems the machine lost half of it's RAM. It should have 16 GB and now it only has 8 GB. You might imagine my suprise. This post goes into my troubleshooting, since I was not able to go to the machine, shut it down and check if the RAM was still there. I'll cover the use of cstm (Support Tool Manager), how to connect to the HP iLO (out of band access) with modern OpenSSH (7.2) and the steps I took to gather information on what might have happened. </description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>HP-UX 11.31 System information and find out part number of a failed disk with sasmgr</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Find_part_number_of_failed_disk_on_HP-UX_with_sasmgr.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Find_part_number_of_failed_disk_on_HP-UX_with_sasmgr.html</guid>
                <description>On one of my regular scheduled datacenter visits one of the older HP-UX Itanium machines had an orange light on the front. These systems are not (yet) monitored, but still in use so the disk had to be replaced. Not knowing anything about this system or which parts were used, I managed to find the exact part number and device type so we could order a spare. This small guide uses sasmgr to get the data on HP-UX 11.31.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Linux software raid, rebuilding broken raid 1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html</guid>
                <description>Last week Nagios alerted me about a broken disk in one of my clients testing servers. There is a best effort SLA on the thing, and there were spare drives of the same type and size in the datacenter. Lucky me. This particular data center is on biking distance, so I enjoyed a sunny ride there. Simply put, I needed to replace the disk and rebuild the raid 1 array. This server is a simple Ubuntu 12.04 LTS server with two disks running in raid 1, no spare. Client has a tight budget, and with a best effort SLA not in production, fine with me. Consultant tip, make sure you have those things signed. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up your own distributed, redundant, and encrypted storage grid with Tahoe-LAFS</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tahoe_LAFS_Storage_Grid.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Tahoe_LAFS_Storage_Grid.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers the installation and configuration of Tahoe/LAFS, a distributed, encrypted and redundant storage clustering grid.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    