<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag raspberry-pi on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/raspberry-pi.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag raspberry-pi on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/raspberry-pi.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi unattended upgrade Raspbian to Debian Testing</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Raspberry_Pi_Raspbian_Unattended_Upgrade_Jessie_to_Testing.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Raspberry_Pi_Raspbian_Unattended_Upgrade_Jessie_to_Testing.html</guid>
                <description>I'm working on a Nitrokey/SmartCard-HSM cluster article and therefore I needed three identical computers. The current version of Raspbian (2016-05-27) is based on Debian Jessie and comes with a version of OpenSC that is too old (0.14) to work with the Nitrokey/SmartCard-HSM. Since there is no Ubuntu 16.04 official image yet I decided to upgrade Raspbian to Debian Testing. Since I don't want to answer yes to any config file changes or service restarts I figured out how to do an unattended dist-upgrade.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 02, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 02 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 53, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_53_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_53_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 53 of 2015, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 52, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_52_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_52_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 52, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 51, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 51, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Make OpenELEC/Kodi work with the Sitecom CN-524/ Cambridge Silicon Radio (CSR) 8510 A10 Bluetooth USB adapter on the Raspberry Pi.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Make_Openelec_Kodi_work_with_the_Sitecom_CN-524_Cambridge_Silicon_Radio_CSR_8510_A10_Bluetooth_USB_adapter_on_the_Raspberry_Pi.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Make_Openelec_Kodi_work_with_the_Sitecom_CN-524_Cambridge_Silicon_Radio_CSR_8510_A10_Bluetooth_USB_adapter_on_the_Raspberry_Pi.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I set up a Kodi (XMBC) media center on a Raspberry Pi.  The setup is mounted on a flatscreen TV and uses a small Wifi dongle for network access and a small Bluetooth dongle for a Rapoo E6700 wireless bluetooth keyboard/touchpad. This is a nice bluetooth keyboard/mouse combo for a media center, it charges via micro USB. That saves a lot of battery hassle. The bluetooth adapter is a Sitecom CN-524, which was the only one my local electronic store had available. It however does not work with linux/Kodi by default. This is because the device boots in a wrong mode. This guide shows you how this can be fixed and the necessary software changes for OpenELEC.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi Arcade Machine</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_Arcade_Machine.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_Arcade_Machine.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to build your own full size arcade machine using a Raspberry Pi. It involves a real, full size arcade cabinet, a converter device called a J-Pac and the MAME emulator software.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 mainline 4.0.0 kernel, u-boot and debian rootfs image building tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_A20_Lime2_Kernel_3.19_uBoot_Debian_7_image_building.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino_A20_Lime2_Kernel_3.19_uBoot_Debian_7_image_building.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 45, and has 160 GPIO pins. This is a guide to build a linux image with Debian and the mainline 4.0.0 kernel for the Olimex A20-Lime2 board, from scratch. By default it comes with an 3.4 kernel with binary blobs and patches from Allwinner. Recently the mainline kernel has gained support for these boards, you can now run and use the mainline kernel without these awfull non-free binary blobs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Raspberry Pi FM radio transmitter with Buttons</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_FM_Radio_With_Buttons.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Raspberry_Pi_FM_Radio_With_Buttons.html</guid>
                <description>The PiFM project allows you to use a Raspberry Pi to send out a WAV file on the FM band. This is awesome because every normal radio then can receive your music/podcast without expensive (sonos) equipment. I've used a lasercutter to craft a new top plate for my Pi which has room for three buttons. These are hooked up to a python script which allows me to start and stop the transmission, and skip or go back songs. It also allows me to shut down the Pi instead of just pulling the power cable.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 Minimal Debian 7 Image</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A20-OLinuXino-LIME2_minimal_debian_7_image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A20-OLinuXino-LIME2_minimal_debian_7_image.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A20 LIME2 is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 45, and has 160 GPIO pins. The default Debian image from OlimeX is quite huge and bloated, over 2,5 GB, with X and all. I do not want a huge image, so I stripped it down to a 200 MB image with only dhcp and ssh and a few basic tools. It uses about 15 MB of RAM. This image allows you to start with almost nothing and build up only what you need.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Broken Corrupted Raspberry Pi SD Card</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Broken_Corrupted_Raspberry_Pi_SD_Card.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Broken_Corrupted_Raspberry_Pi_SD_Card.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's would not boot up after a reboot. The SD card was corrupted, sadly beyond repair. This article walks you through the steps I took to try to fix the SD card, including fsck, badblocks and other filesystem utilities. It also has tips to reduce the writing on the Raspberry Pi, this to save SD cards from some amount of wear and thus possible corruption.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino a10 Lime uBoot, Kernel and root image guide</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino _10 Lime_uBoot_Kernel.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_OlinuXino _10 Lime_uBoot_Kernel.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A10 LIME is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 30, and has 160 GPIO. This guide is a cleaned up version of theirs with instructions to build your own kernel and u-boot image on Ubuntu 14.04.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Arch Linux on a Raspberry Pi with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_a_Raspberry_Pi_with_Arch_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_a_Raspberry_Pi_with_Arch_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Arch Linux on a Raspberry Pi using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Olimex OlinuXino a10 Lime Minimal Debian 7 Image</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A10-OLinuXino-LIME_minimal_debian_7_image.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Olimex_A10-OLinuXino-LIME_minimal_debian_7_image.html</guid>
                <description>The Olimex OlinuXino A10 LIME is an amazing, powerfull and cheap open source ARM development board. It costs EUR 30, and has 160 GPIO. The default Debian image from OlimeX is quite huge and bloated, over 2 GB, with X and all. I do not want a huge image, so I stripped it down to a 200 MB image with only dhcp and ssh and a few basic tools. It uses about 20 MB of RAM. This image allows you to start with almost nothing and build up only what you need.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Build a $35 Time Capsule - Raspberry Pi Time Machine Backup Server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Build_a_35_dollar_Time_Capsule_-_Raspberry_Pi_Time_Machine.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple guide on building a $35 Time Capsule with a Raspberry Pi. A Time Capsule is a network attached storage device from Apple for use with their Time Machine. Time Machine gives users a very easy and userfriendly way to automatically create and restore (encrypted) backups. A Time Capsule is basically an expensive NAS that only talks the AFP/netatalk protocol. The 2 TB version costs $299 at this time, a Raspberry Pi only $35. </description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Transmission Web on a Raspberry Pi with Arch Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's was running a test setup of the Citadel groupware service. The test was sucessfull, so I set up a real world setup. The Raspberry Pi would serve another purpose, namely, a Linux Torrent seedbox. As in, to seed Linux torrents from linuxtracker.org. I choose Transmission for this, because it is simple, fast and stable. Transmission has a good webinterface, plus it allows access from remote clients with the transmission-remote gui packages. This article shows you how to set it up on a Raspberry Pi running Arch Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up your own truly secure, encrypted and shared file synchronization, aka Dropbox clone</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html</guid>
                <description>This article describes my truly secure, encrypted file synchronization service. It used EncFS and dvcs-autosync which lets me share only the encrypted data and mount that locally to get the plaintext. It works on OS X, Linux and ARM linux. This article has setup instructions for all those platforms.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Small low cost linux pc's, an overview from 11-2012</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_PCs.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Small_Linux_PCs.html</guid>
                <description>This is an overview of small linux computers, mostly ARM based.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    