<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag raymiiorg on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/raymiiorg.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag raymiiorg on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/raymiiorg.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Site update, cookie consent popup (for a static site)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_cookie_consent_popup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_cookie_consent_popup.html</guid>
                <description>A small site update this time, just to let you know that I've added a cookie consent popup to this static site. If you reject all cookies, you should not see any advertisements and aren't tracked by Google Analytics. It's open source, cookieconsent by Orest Bida.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, new font for better contrast and other small CSS fixes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_font_for_better_contrast.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_font_for_better_contrast.html</guid>
                <description>New year, time for some site updates. This site is generated with my self-written open source static site generator named ingsoc (named after 1984) and this update is a collection of  small improvements. A new font, internal code updates to the generator and a few CSS fixes here and there. This article goes over all of them including screenshots before and after!</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>What does raymii.org cost to run?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Costs_to_run_raymii.org.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Costs_to_run_raymii.org.html</guid>
                <description>Inspired by recent articles from Kev Quirk, Horst Gutmann and Jan-Lukas where they do a cost breakdown of their sites, I decided to do one as well. Kev is around USD 30, Horst is around USD 13 and Jan-Lukas is around 5 USD. Their breakdowns are interesting, from specific wordpress plugins to CDN or DNS costs. I don't have those, but I do have a multitude of small servers running this site, which add up to around USD 20, adding up two domain names gives me around USD 22 per month. It could be a lot cheaper, I only need one server for the gigantuous amounts of static HTML this site consists of, but I do have around 10.000 unique visitors each day, so having redundancy is nice. If I would go all cheap, this site would cost me no more than 2 USD a month including the domain name, but that would take the fun out of it. This article features a list of similar, how much does my site cost articles and a cost breakdown of this site.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, new layout</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updated_new_2019_layout.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updated_new_2019_layout.html</guid>
                <description>This site is generated with my self-written open source static site generator named ingsoc (named after 1984). I've updated the layout of the website to be less cluttered, allowing you to get to the content much faster. Inspired by my recent gopher adventures I decided to do away with the 2 column layout (drop the sidebar with menu) and have a smaller header with essential links. On mobile this makes a huge difference in scrolling, on the desktop it looks less cluttered. This article details all the changes with side by side images showing differences.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Convert markdown inline links to reference style links with Pandoc</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Convert_markdown_inline_links_to_reference_style_links_with_Pandoc.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Convert_markdown_inline_links_to_reference_style_links_with_Pandoc.html</guid>
                <description>Markdown has two options to create a link. A link is the piece of text you click to go to another webpage. Actually, three ways, since you can just embed HTML code in Markdown. I write all the content for this site in Markdown files, which are then converted by my static site generator to HTML, text and a gopher version. I'm used to using the inline link style, which is  where you paste the link right in the text. Since I've enabled the Gopher  version of raymii.org, I noticed that there was no line wrapping. The HTML  website all arranges that via CSS, but the text-only Gopher does not. Sometimes  Gopher clients wrap text, but most don't. I'm re-wrapping all articles to make them fit, but the wrapping is way off with inline style markdown links. By  converting them to reference style markdown links, the wrapping looks way better, and as an added bonus, reference style links give a better overview. There are a few scripts floating around to convert these links, but either  Ruby or NodeJS. It turns out after a bit of research that Pandoc, the anything-to-anything text conversion tool, has an option to use reference style links. With this option, I converted all the articles here (almost 400) to the reference style Markdown links.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, raymii.org now also available on Gopher</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_raymii.org_now_on_gopher.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_raymii.org_now_on_gopher.html</guid>
                <description>I've made some new improvements to this website, you can now view raymii.org on Gopher! Building on the last site improvement, every article being available as plain text, it was easy to generate a gophermap file and bind it all together with pygopherd.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates for accessibility, text only pages and skip to main content</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_Improvements_for_accessibility.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_Improvements_for_accessibility.html</guid>
                <description>I've made some new improvements to this website. Raymii.org is generated using my self-written static site generator named ingsoc, the new features are focussed on accessibility. If you are using a screen reader or command-line browser this will benefit you. Or if you like to archive stuff offline. The two main improvements are a text-only version of every content page (article/tutorial etc) and a 'Skip to main content' link.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, new layout for overview pages</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_layout_for_overview_pages.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_new_layout_for_overview_pages.html</guid>
                <description>This site is generated with my self-written open source static site generator named ingsoc (named after 1984). I've updated the overview pages with a new layout so that items are sorted by their publishing date instead of alphabetically. I've also rewritten some internal logic regarding tags and categories. This article shows the difference before and after and includes some old screenshots of raymii.org.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    