<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag rrd on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/rrd.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag rrd on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/rrd.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Line total (up+down sum) in PHP Network Weathermap</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Line_total_up_down_sum_in_php_weathermap.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Line_total_up_down_sum_in_php_weathermap.html</guid>
                <description>With PHP Network Weathermap you can create a birds-eye view of network components from your monitoring system (like LibreNMS, Cacti or anything else with an RRD database). It can display simple maps with components and links between, showing up and down traffic, but also complex systems with custom components, like Nagios status, temperature or other information. For network and system administrators seeing the seperate in and out traffic of a link is fine, we can sum up two numbers. A co worker filling the role of service manager asked me if it was possible to sum up in and out and show that, including the scale (different colours depending on link usage). This co worker is not interested in the seperate up/down link speed but wants to know how much traffic a location is using in total. Using a clever workaround, you can display a line's total usage, including the scale. This article also gives some more tips on weathermap, colouring and scale.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd client</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_client_setup_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd client for use with a collectd server. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;).</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a Collectd server with web frontend</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Collectd_server_setup_tutorial_with_web_frontend.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a collectd server. It also shows you how to set up the collectd-web frontend, an interactive gui for collectd, and has it all firewalled. What is collectd? collectd gathers statistics about the system it is running on and stores this information. Those statistics can then be used to find current performance bottlenecks (i.e. performance analysis) and predict future system load (i.e. capacity planning). Or if you just want pretty graphs of your private server and are fed up with some homegrown solution you're at the right place, too ;). A collectd server is able to receive data from collectd clients.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    