<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag rust on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/rust.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag rust on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/rust.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Compiling TETRIS from 1992 on OpenVMS x86 in 2024!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Tetris_from_1992_on_OpenVMS_x86_in_2024.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Tetris_from_1992_on_OpenVMS_x86_in_2024.html</guid>
                <description>Since [DECWindows / CDE](/s/blog/OpenVMS_x86_E9.2-3_fixes_CDE_and_adds_Guest_Console.html) now works on OpenVMS x86 (from 9.2-3 onwards) there is much fun stuff to do. Back in 2021 I wrote an article on the [CDE desktop on Alpha / AXPbox](/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html) and also an article on how to run [CDE on modern linux, since it's still developed](/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html#toc_6). Both articles included a game, **GENERIC-TETRIS** from 1992, [written by Qiang Alex Zhao](https://web.archive.org/web/20240815073318/https://sites.cc.gatech.edu/gvu/people/qiang.a.zhao/Games.html).
After getting the (remote) desktop working I wanted to compile and run Tetris to continue this lineage, from VAX, to Alpha, to Linux/CDE, to x86 VMS. I haven't got an Itanium to run it on, but if anyone has one left willing to send this way, feel free to contact me. This article includes the precompiled tetris binary for OpenVMS x86 and instructions to compile the source. The code required some minor modifications which I'll also cover, but that's not surprising for code that hasn't changed much since 1992 to be compiled in 2024. This article also shows you how to install curl on OpenVMS.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 14:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 14:33:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site update, self-hosted search via pagefind</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_self_hosted_search_via_pagefind.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_update_self_hosted_search_via_pagefind.html</guid>
                <description>This is a static site, meaning that no server-side processing occurs. All HTML is generated out of a few folders full of markdown source and then uploaded to the cluster. Searching on this site was always provided by a text-box form that sent you to google with 'site:raymii.org' appended to it. Works fine, but it sends all data to Google. With my recent removal of all Google Ads on this site, as well as tracking via Google Analytics, sending searches via Google seems wrong. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I recently found the `pagefind` program which I now use on here, it is a self hosted static site search engine of sorts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 21:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 21:32:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    