<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag s3 on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/s3.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag s3 on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/s3.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>The yearly backup restore test</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Yearly_Backup_Restore_test.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Yearly_Backup_Restore_test.html</guid>
                <description>In my calendar there is a yearly recurring item named 'backup restore test'. This is an article on my backup scheme and the yearly restore test, covering all aspects, such as data validation, backup scheme, time and cost involved.
I started doing personal restore tests each year around 2012, when I did them for my first job. At work back then, the restore test was monthly, for my own backups I decided that yearly was okay enough, since the backup scheme, software and provider do not change. I'm using Azure cold storage for my (locally encrypted) personal backups, since it's both cheap and supported by my local NAS.

Have you done your backup restore test recently?</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Backup OpenStack object store or S3 with rclone</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Backup_or_Sync_OpenStack_object_store_or_other_cloud_storage_with_rclone.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Backup_or_Sync_OpenStack_object_store_or_other_cloud_storage_with_rclone.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide that shows you how to make backups of an object storage service like OpenStack swift or S3. Most object store services save data on multiple servers, but deleting a file also deletes it from all servers. Tools like rsync or scp are not compatible most of the time with these services, unless there is a proxy that translates the object store protocol to something like SFTP. rclone is an rsync-like, command line tool that syncs files and directories from cloud storage services like OpenStack swift, Amazon S3, Google cloud/drive, dropbox and more. By having a local backup of the contents of your cloud object store you can restore from accidental deletion or easily migrate between cloud providers. Syncing between cloud providers is also possible. It can also help to lower the RTO (recovery time objective) and backups are just always a good thing to have and test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    