<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag shell on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/shell.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag shell on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/shell.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Record your Linux Desktop with ffmpeg and slop to any format</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Record_your_Linux_Desktop_with_ffmpeg_and_slop.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Record_your_Linux_Desktop_with_ffmpeg_and_slop.html</guid>
                <description>This two-line shell script allows you to record a region of your linux desktop to a video file, or a `.gif`, using `slop` and `ffmpeg`. I use it often when a screenshot is not enough, or when you need to explain a sequence of events to someone.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash HTTP monitoring dashboard</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_HTTP_Monitoring_Dashboard.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Bash_HTTP_Monitoring_Dashboard.html</guid>
                <description>This is a shell script that creates a webpage with the status of HTTP(s) sites. Parallel checking, thus very fast, only dependencies are curl and bash (version 4 or above). For all of you who want a simple script with a nice webpage to check a few websites. Perfect for a wall mounted monitoring display and a Raspberry Pi. Installation and configuration is easy to do inside the script. It scales well, both on the checking side as the information display page (dense on purpose). Failed checks appear right on top for you to act on. I had this script running at home for at least a year in that form, when I showed it to a friend he liked it,  asked me to make it public, but before I did that I polished it up a bit. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get number of incoming connections on specific port with ss</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_number_of_incoming_connections_on_specific_ports_with_ss.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_number_of_incoming_connections_on_specific_ports_with_ss.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to write a few monitoring plugins, one of which was a count of incoming connections to a specific network port. In the past I would have used netstat and a combination of grep and wc filter out only specific ports and established connections, but nowdays netstat is replaced by ss on ubuntu. ss has options to filter directly on all sorts of stuff, like state, ports, protocol, making the command I use more readable and use less pipes.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get all SSH public keys from gitlab</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_SSH_public_keys_from_gitlab.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_SSH_public_keys_from_gitlab.html</guid>
                <description>This small snippet gets all the SSH keys from a gitlab instance. You need to be an administrator, then you can query all keys at once using the API. On the web frontend you can only see the keys per user, not all at once in an overview.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Send commands or input to a detached screen session</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Sending_commands_or_input_to_a_screen_session.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Sending_commands_or_input_to_a_screen_session.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet will show you how to send commands to a running screen session. This includes actual shell commands or keyboard input, as well as screen commands, for example to set a logfile.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash bits: split a file in blocks and do something with each block</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Bash_bits_split_a_file_in_blocks_and_do_something_with_each_block.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Bash_bits_split_a_file_in_blocks_and_do_something_with_each_block.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for the bash shell. This bash bit shows you how to split a file into blocks (multiline) and do something with each block. This can be used for certificate chains or other files which have multiline blocks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash bits: find has a -delete flag</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_bits_find_has_a_delete_option.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_bits_find_has_a_delete_option.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for the bash shell. This bash bit shows you that find has a -delete option. I recently found this out, before I would always use -exec rm {} ;. The delete flag is shorter, performs better and is  easier to remember.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Match dig 127.0.0.53 server with systemd-resolvd server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Match_dig_127.0.0.53_server_with_systemd-resolved_server.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Match_dig_127.0.0.53_server_with_systemd-resolved_server.html</guid>
                <description>On systems that use systemd-resolved for DNS you will see the 127.0.0.53 IP address in dig output. dig is a tool to do DNS lookups, and for troubleshooting it's usefull to see which server is being queried. With systemd-resolved, you need to issue another command to view the actual server that is being queried, since systemd-resolvd also acts as a local caching server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Find all files containing specific text (and remove them)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Find_all_files_containing_specific_text.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Find_all_files_containing_specific_text.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to find all files containing specific text, and how to remove them.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Randomize a cronjob to run between 00:00 and 06:00 hours</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Randomize_cronjob_time.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Randomize_cronjob_time.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to randomize the time a cronjob runs in /etc/cron.d/</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Check if a program is installed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_if_command_is_available.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_if_command_is_available.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to check if a piece of software is installed on a machine. It's a function you can use in your shell scripts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get a JSON value with bash and sed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_json_value_with_sed.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_json_value_with_sed.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I was asked to get one value from a json object using only shell tools. The json in question is from a dutch radio station and it lists the current song that is played. Using this together with a few shell commands and notify-send we can show the current song when it changes as a desktop notification. I'd rather use Python or jq if it has to be shell. In this case the co-worker asked to just use simple shell tools and no external dependencies.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Find files in tar archives and extract specific files from tar archives</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_files_in_tar_archives_and_extract_them.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_files_in_tar_archives_and_extract_them.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small tip, to find specific files in tar archives and how to extract those specific files from said archive.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>tping - ping with a timestamp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/tping_ping_with_a_timestamp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/tping_ping_with_a_timestamp.html</guid>
                <description>tping is a bash alias I once got from an old co-worker. It's ping, but with a timestamp. Instead of looking at the increased icmp_seq number you now have a timestamp.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Send email with multiple inline images via bash with a loop</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Send_email_with_multiple_inline_images_via_bash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Send_email_with_multiple_inline_images_via_bash.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had a request from a user that whished to receive a scheduled email with two screenshots. The screenshots were automated via AutoIt on a network share, the user manually logged in every evening to check the pictures. With bash and postfix/sendmail we can automate this process, the user now doesn't have to login but can just check their email. There are a lot of snippets and guides to attach emails via the shell, but displaying multiple images inline as an HTML mail was something I had to figure out. You cannot embed the image in base64 HTML because Outlook doesn't show that, you must use the Content-ID style embed. Like UUENCODE, but more complicated. (The next step in this process with the user is to automate the reason why they have to check those screenshots every night, that is something for another article)</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Manually verify a certificate against a CRL</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_manually_verify_a_certificate_against_a_CRL.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_manually_verify_a_certificate_against_a_CRL.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to manually verfify a certificate against a CRL. CRL stands for Certificate Revocation List and is one way to validate a certificate status. It is an alternative to the OCSP, Online Certificate Status Protocol.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Manually verify a certificate against an OCSP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_Manually_Verify_a_certificate_against_an_OCSP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_Manually_Verify_a_certificate_against_an_OCSP.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to manually verfify a certificate against an OCSP server. OCSP stands for the Online Certificate Status Protocol and is one way to validate a certificate status. It is an alternative to the CRL, certificate revocation list. This article shows you how to manually validate a certificate against an OCSP server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL: Get all certificates from a website in plain text</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/OpenSSL_-_Get_all_certificates_from_a_website_in_plain_text.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to get all certificates of a website in plain text. With a few OpenSSL commands one can get the website certificate plus intermediate certificates, however, if you feed that output to OpenSSL it only works on the first certificate. Using a bit of sed and bash magic we can feed all certificates one by one to OpenSSL.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Simple command line arguments</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add command line arguments to your script. It is very simple, non-positional and does not use getopts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Check if item is in array</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how find out if an array has an item.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Add colour output to your script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to add coloured output to your scripts</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Debug Logging</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add debug logging to a bash script.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Trap Control C (SIGTERM)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to capture a Control C signal in a bash script, for example, to clean up any temp or pid files when your script is killed or closed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>bdsh - Whitelist Restricted Shell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/bdsh.html</guid>
                <description>A shell where you whitelist commands and only those commands can be executed. Either via ssh, as an interactive shell or launched with commands. Logs everything and escapes dangerous characters. bdsh stands for Boa Diminish SHell. You can probably guess why. It might have to to with snakes and restricting users, no pun intended.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Incremental History Search / Autocomplete </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet for your .bashrc or your .inputrc changes the Up/Down arrow behavior to autocomplete what is already typed instead of just go back in history.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Screenfetch installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install screenfetch, a bash information tool. It displays handy system information at login, including distro name, kernel, uptime, cpu, ram and nice distro-based artwork. The tutorial includes support for bash and zsh, for every supported linux OS (ubuntu, centos, arch, redhat, solusOS, linux mint and more.)</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Better Cron env and shell control with the SHELL variable</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Better_cron_env_and_shell_control_with_the_SHELL_variale.html</guid>
                <description>Have better control over env variables and shell settings in cron via the SHELL variable and a few scripts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    