<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag snap on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/snap.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag snap on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/snap.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>All packages that were present in Ubuntu 18.04 but absent in Ubuntu 20.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/All_packages_that_were_present_in_Ubuntu_18.04_but_removed_in_20.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/All_packages_that_were_present_in_Ubuntu_18.04_but_removed_in_20.04.html</guid>
                <description>Otherwise titled `Figure out the differences between two apt repositories`. Recently I've had a few packages that I often use but were missing from Ubuntu 20.04 LTS. One is [ckermit](/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_CKermit_as_a_snap_for_Ubuntu_20.04.html) and the other is [gnash](/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html), both of which I 'converted' to a snap. (In air quotes because I just converted the 18.04 deb). This made me wonder if I could figure out a list of that are present in Ubuntu 18.04, but absent in Ubuntu 20.04. As `apt` and `dpkg` are standardized tools and and package formats, we can use a few shell tools to parse the package lists and compare them side by side.
This post shows you how to do the comparison yourself and I discuss the removed packages a bit. Some are version increments (like `gcc-6` in Ubuntu 18.04 but `gcc-7`in Ubuntu 20.04),  and some are packages that were combined into one instead of split up  (like `ltsp` in Ubuntu 20.04 but a bunch of seperate `ltsp-$postfix` packages instead  in Ubuntu 18.04). Many others are just replaced by newer versions (`python-ceph` vs `python3-ceph`). The list of differences is provided as a download, both ways.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I've packaged up CKermit as a snap, for Ubuntu 20.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_CKermit_as_a_snap_for_Ubuntu_20.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_CKermit_as_a_snap_for_Ubuntu_20.04.html</guid>
                <description>Last year I packaged up [gnash as a snap](/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html) because it was missing from the Ubuntu 20.04 apt repositories. Recently I found out that `ckermit` is also not in Ubuntu 20.04, as far as I can tell because it wasn't in the Debian repositories when the Ubuntu 20.04 initial sync happened. Which is very inconvenient for an LTS release.
I often use `ckermit` to connect to our hardware via a script, to automatically boot from NFS (via u-boot). I could do that manually via `screen` or `minicom`, but I have a `kermit` script that does it for me, which is very convenient. Since the snapping of `gnash` was so easy, I decided to do it for `ckermit` as well, since I now know how to convert deb packages to snaps. I also have a few colleagues who also use those kermit scripts and are going to update to 20.04 in the (near) future.
The snap packaging is based on work by Phil Roche, he wrote about re-packaging older debian packages with an Ubuntu 18.04/16.04 base layer as a snap. My `ckermit` package is confined (no `--classic` needed), the source code for the snap is on my github and on any snap-enabled distro you can now 'snap install ckermit-raymii' to enjoy CKermit.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>I've packaged up Gnash as a snap, for modern linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ive_packaged_up_Gnash_as_a_Snap_for_modern_linux.html</guid>
                <description>I hate snaps just as much as the next guy but last week I did something unexpected. I packaged up Gnash as a snap.  Gnash is a GNU flash media player, not updated since 2011, and  thus removed from the Ubuntu 20.04 repositories. The snap packaging is based on work by phil roche, he wrote about re-packaging older debian packages with an Ubuntu 18.04/16.04 base layer as a snap. My gnash package is confined (no '--classic' needed), the source code for the snap is on my github and on any snap-enabled distro you can now 'snap install gnash-raymii' to enjoy Gnash again.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ubuntu Snap auto updates broke my development setup and there is no way to turn them off</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ubuntu_Snap_auto_updates_broke_my_development_setup.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Ubuntu_Snap_auto_updates_broke_my_development_setup.html</guid>
                <description>After updating-by-reinstall to Ubuntu 20.04, I installed CLion via snap since that  seemed more convinient than manually downloading a java installation. CLion is the best thing since sliced bread, or I mean a C/C++ IDE by JetBrains. Ubuntu snap is  a packaging system made by Canonical and pushed hard in Ubuntu. Today I found out the hard way that snap auto-updates and that there is no way to turn that off permanently. CLion was updated, which I noticed because the process was killed. The update broke several key plugins for my workflow  and the theme was weird. In this article I'll discuss my disgust, I as the owner of the computer want to be in full control, not some developer that decides I need auto updates. I ended up removing snap completely, and my next install will not be Ubuntu due to this.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>snap install mosaic, the first graphical webbrowser on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/snap_install_mosaic_the_first_graphical_webbrowser_on_Ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/snap_install_mosaic_the_first_graphical_webbrowser_on_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>On one of my favorite podcasts from Jupiter Broadcasting, either Linux Action News or Linux unplugged (252 I think, not sure), Allan Pope was talking about Snap packages and how there are now WinePacks, a snap with Wine and a single (Windows) application packaged. During the discussion he dropped that Mosaic, the first graphical web browser, is available as a snap package, for modern distributions. I installed it, after huge download (1.5 MB), playing around with it is quite fun. In this post I'll discuss how to install it, what works and what doens't in the modern age on Ubuntu 18.04</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    