<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag snippets on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/snippets.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag snippets on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/snippets.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Execute a script in a Yocto package on every image build</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Execute_a_script_in_a_Yocto_package_on_every_image_build.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Execute_a_script_in_a_Yocto_package_on_every_image_build.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small snippet showing a Yocto recipe that executes a script on every build of an image that includes that recipe. I use it to write the build hosts date/time to a file on the image, but you could do anything you want inside the script.
It's not recommended to do this, for example, if you want to place a binary on your image you should version it correctly. Yocto can build from a git repo, no need to copy binaries. If you include the `buildinfo` class your image or the `os-release` recipe, build info is also written to your image. </description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Log all Item properties and functions in Qml</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Log_all_Item_properties_and_functions_in_Qml.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Log_all_Item_properties_and_functions_in_Qml.html</guid>
                <description>This small snippet of Javascript logs all properties and functions of a Qml Item. This is useful when you're knees-deep in a dynamic control that has a model and you're wondering why your code does not work. Probably because you're not using the correct property name. Or at least, that is something I often have. Logging all properties or functions helps to figure out that issue.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Loop over all Repeater items or Delegate's in Qml</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Loop_over_all_Repeater_items_or_Delegates_in_Qml.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Loop_over_all_Repeater_items_or_Delegates_in_Qml.html</guid>
                <description>This small snippet shows how to loop over all Repeater items in Qml and also over all Delegate items in Qml. There are sublte differences between the two.
I'm using this to update visual all items in a control, before syncing state to a networked backend, and if the backend actions fails, I undo the visual state change. The network backend could be slow, by keeping state locally and syncing in the background, the user can continue working.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Render markdown in a Qt QML Text or TextEdit control</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/QML_Render_Markdown_in_Text.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/QML_Render_Markdown_in_Text.html</guid>
                <description>I recently discovered that Qt QML can render Markdown in `Text{}` controls. This snippet shows you how to do that including a screenshot and demo QML app.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exclude lines in less (or journalctl)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Exclude_lines_in_less_or_journalctl.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Exclude_lines_in_less_or_journalctl.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small tip I want to give you when using a `less` based pager, for example in `journalctl` or when viewing a file interactively with `less` or `more`. You can exclude certain lines that match one or multiple words (or a regex) with a few keystrokes, once `less` is open. This is one of those tips you never knew you needed, but when you know it, you'll use it frequently. Like in my case today when searching through some logfiles to find out why my database stopped working.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Run one specific clang-tidy check on your entire codebase</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Run_one_specific_clang-tidy_check_on_your_codebase.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Run_one_specific_clang-tidy_check_on_your_codebase.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I did a major refactor on a piece of code that involved thousands of lines of code which were in one  way or another related to string handling. All of the code handled `char*` (C style character pointer arrays) and the concept of `const` or ownership was literally unknown in that part of the codebase. The refactored code uses `std::string`'s, but due to the legacy nature, a large number of methods returned `nullptr`'s instead of empty strings. I understand why this was done, but finding all those instances and the fact it only gives a runtime error was a bit of a bummer.
Luckily `clang-tidy` is here to save the day. In my IDE, CLion, it gives a warning when you return a `nullptr`. It however does that only in the file you're currently editing, and since we're talking millions of files, I wasn't going to open them by hand. You can run `clang-tidy` easily on one file, and it's not hard to run it on an entire codebase as well, using  the script `run-clang-tidy.py`, provided in their packages.
This snippet shows you how to run one specific `clang-tidy` check, in my case, `bugprone-string-constructor`, on a (cmake and C++) codebase.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Record your Linux Desktop with ffmpeg and slop to any format</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Record_your_Linux_Desktop_with_ffmpeg_and_slop.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Record_your_Linux_Desktop_with_ffmpeg_and_slop.html</guid>
                <description>This two-line shell script allows you to record a region of your linux desktop to a video file, or a `.gif`, using `slop` and `ffmpeg`. I use it often when a screenshot is not enough, or when you need to explain a sequence of events to someone.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>QT / QML Signals and Slots with C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_QT_QML_Signals_and_Slots.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_QT_QML_Signals_and_Slots.html</guid>
                <description>QT has an Observer mechanism built in, which they call '[Signals and Slots](https://web.archive.org/web/20210210180603/https://doc.qt.io/qt-5/signalsandslots.html)'. It allows objects to communicate with each other without having to have knowledge of either ones internals. By inheriting from `QObject` and defining a few `Q_PROPERTY` macro's, the QT Meta Object Compiler (`moc`) does all the hard work for you.
Inside a C++ class this all works handy dandy and is reasonable easy to follow, but when using QML it requires a bit more work. This small example shows you how to bind QML and C++ together using signals and slots, in QT 5.12.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>std::accumulate in C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_std_accumulate.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_std_accumulate.html</guid>
                <description>I'm using codewars to practice my development skills. Today I found out about the std::accumulate method in C++ while doing an exercise there. I'm sharing it here because I never heard of it before. It is the numeric header, and it also accepts a custom binary function to apply instead of operator+. This snippet shows some examples including a lambda operator and the for loop you would use otherwise.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get number of incoming connections on specific port with ss</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_number_of_incoming_connections_on_specific_ports_with_ss.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_number_of_incoming_connections_on_specific_ports_with_ss.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to write a few monitoring plugins, one of which was a count of incoming connections to a specific network port. In the past I would have used netstat and a combination of grep and wc filter out only specific ports and established connections, but nowdays netstat is replaced by ss on ubuntu. ss has options to filter directly on all sorts of stuff, like state, ports, protocol, making the command I use more readable and use less pipes.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get all SSH public keys from gitlab</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_SSH_public_keys_from_gitlab.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_SSH_public_keys_from_gitlab.html</guid>
                <description>This small snippet gets all the SSH keys from a gitlab instance. You need to be an administrator, then you can query all keys at once using the API. On the web frontend you can only see the keys per user, not all at once in an overview.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>C++ Remove leading or trailing characters from std::string</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_Remove_leading_or_trailing_characters_from_string.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_Remove_leading_or_trailing_characters_from_string.html</guid>
                <description>Here's a small snippet to remove leading or trailing characters from a std::string in C++. I use it to strip leading and trailing zeroes in a game score display function.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>std::string to lowercase or uppercase in C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/std_string_to_lowercase_or_uppercase_in_cpp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/std_string_to_lowercase_or_uppercase_in_cpp.html</guid>
                <description>I'm using codewars to practice my development skills. Today I learned a method to transform a std::string's casing, either to uppercase or lowercase. Researching it further, I also found out how to do unicode strings with boost. This article also includes a mini howto on installing Boost on Windows 10 via mingw for use with CLion.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Send commands or input to a detached screen session</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Sending_commands_or_input_to_a_screen_session.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Sending_commands_or_input_to_a_screen_session.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet will show you how to send commands to a running screen session. This includes actual shell commands or keyboard input, as well as screen commands, for example to set a logfile.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash bits: find has a -delete flag</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_bits_find_has_a_delete_option.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_bits_find_has_a_delete_option.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for the bash shell. This bash bit shows you that find has a -delete option. I recently found this out, before I would always use -exec rm {} ;. The delete flag is shorter, performs better and is  easier to remember.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Only zero is false, everything else is true in C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_Only_zero_is_false.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_Only_zero_is_false.html</guid>
                <description>When using numbers in a boolean (implicit conversion), remember that only zero evaluates to false. Anything else, including negative numbers, will evaluate to true. This snippet talks about the rules for implicit conversion in C++ when using booleans. For seasoned programmers it's nothing new, but I found it interesting.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>connman operstate list</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/connman_operstate_list.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/connman_operstate_list.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I was debugging connection issues with a system that uses connman as it's network management software. In the log it was visible that the connection went away and came back, logged with 'operstate' $number $state. I couldn't easily find an overview of all the possible states, but since it's open source we can take a look at the code to find out. Publishing it here for future reference.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>C++ template definitions in a .cpp file (instead of a header file)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_template_definitions_in_a_cpp_file_instead_of_header.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_template_definitions_in_a_cpp_file_instead_of_header.html</guid>
                <description>In this snippet I'll show you how to place your C++ template definitions in a seperate .cpp file. I'd recommend you to just put template definitions in your header file, or a .hpp file, but if you really want to there is a trick to get them in a seperate .cpp file. The trick is to explicitly instanciate every template you're going to use at the end of the .cpp file. With many different templates and types this becomes cumbersome, but for certain usecases it could be useful. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>C++ create and write to a CSV file with a variadic template</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_create_and_write_to_a_CSV_file_with_a_variadic_template.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_create_and_write_to_a_CSV_file_with_a_variadic_template.html</guid>
                <description>In this snippet I'll show you a variadic template to write to a file. In line with my other experiments to get a better grasp at templates, this example improves on my earlier attempt by using a variadic template, thus allowing you to provide an infinite number of columns to the csv file of any type that has the overloaded &lt;&lt; operator.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>C++ create and write to a CSV file</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_create_and_write_to_a_csv_file.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_create_and_write_to_a_csv_file.html</guid>
                <description>In this quick snippet I'll show you how to create and write to a csv file. It includes checking if the file is writable, and if it's not there, creates it with a different first row as header. It's a quick example, I've used it to log some test data. It can probably be improved.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>C++ variadic template recursive example</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_variadic_template_recursive_example.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Cpp_variadic_template_recursive_example.html</guid>
                <description>In this article I'll show you how to use a variadic template in C++. Variadic templates allow you to have a template with a variable number of arguments, also called a parameter pack. Unpacking that pack is more difficult than it should be, so we use a recursive template to iterate over all the parameters one by one. I've also included an example in Python to compare to.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Match dig 127.0.0.53 server with systemd-resolvd server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Match_dig_127.0.0.53_server_with_systemd-resolved_server.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Match_dig_127.0.0.53_server_with_systemd-resolved_server.html</guid>
                <description>On systems that use systemd-resolved for DNS you will see the 127.0.0.53 IP address in dig output. dig is a tool to do DNS lookups, and for troubleshooting it's usefull to see which server is being queried. With systemd-resolved, you need to issue another command to view the actual server that is being queried, since systemd-resolvd also acts as a local caching server.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Find all files containing specific text (and remove them)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Find_all_files_containing_specific_text.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Find_all_files_containing_specific_text.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to find all files containing specific text, and how to remove them.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Randomize a cronjob to run between 00:00 and 06:00 hours</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Randomize_cronjob_time.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Randomize_cronjob_time.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to randomize the time a cronjob runs in /etc/cron.d/</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Check if a program is installed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_if_command_is_available.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_if_command_is_available.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to check if a piece of software is installed on a machine. It's a function you can use in your shell scripts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Where is dropbearconvert on Ubuntu?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Where_is_dropbearconvert_on_ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Where_is_dropbearconvert_on_ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>Dropbear is a lightweight SSH server and client implementation, often used on embedded systems and routers. If you use the dropbear SSH client (dbclient) and want to use a private key, it needs to be in the dropbear format and cannot have a passphrase. Dropbear provides a conversion utility to convert openssh style keys to dropbear style keys, dropbearconvert, but on Ubuntu it's not in your $PATH. This means you have to provide the full path to execute it, which is cumbersome. There is a bug in Ubuntu that has been reported in 2012, but in Ubuntu 18.04 (2019) it's still not fixed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get a JSON value with bash and sed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_json_value_with_sed.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_json_value_with_sed.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I was asked to get one value from a json object using only shell tools. The json in question is from a dutch radio station and it lists the current song that is played. Using this together with a few shell commands and notify-send we can show the current song when it changes as a desktop notification. I'd rather use Python or jq if it has to be shell. In this case the co-worker asked to just use simple shell tools and no external dependencies.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Find files in tar archives and extract specific files from tar archives</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_files_in_tar_archives_and_extract_them.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_files_in_tar_archives_and_extract_them.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small tip, to find specific files in tar archives and how to extract those specific files from said archive.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>tping - ping with a timestamp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/tping_ping_with_a_timestamp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/tping_ping_with_a_timestamp.html</guid>
                <description>tping is a bash alias I once got from an old co-worker. It's ping, but with a timestamp. Instead of looking at the increased icmp_seq number you now have a timestamp.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Send email with multiple inline images via bash with a loop</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Send_email_with_multiple_inline_images_via_bash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Send_email_with_multiple_inline_images_via_bash.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had a request from a user that whished to receive a scheduled email with two screenshots. The screenshots were automated via AutoIt on a network share, the user manually logged in every evening to check the pictures. With bash and postfix/sendmail we can automate this process, the user now doesn't have to login but can just check their email. There are a lot of snippets and guides to attach emails via the shell, but displaying multiple images inline as an HTML mail was something I had to figure out. You cannot embed the image in base64 HTML because Outlook doesn't show that, you must use the Content-ID style embed. Like UUENCODE, but more complicated. (The next step in this process with the user is to automate the reason why they have to check those screenshots every night, that is something for another article)</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - add apt_key inline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ansible_-_add_apt_key_inline.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ansible_-_add_apt_key_inline.html</guid>
                <description>Using the apt_key module one can add an APT key with ansible. You can get the key from a remote server or from a file, or just a key ID. I got the request to do some stuff on a machine which was quite rescricted (so no HKP protocol) and I was asked not to place to many files on the machine. The apt_key was needed but it could not be a file, so using a YAML Literal Block Scalar I was able to add the key inline in the playbook. Not the best way to do it, but one of the many ways Ansible allows it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Synergy, no mouse cursor on Ubuntu 17.10</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Synergy_no_mouse_cursor_on_Ubuntu_17.10.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Synergy_no_mouse_cursor_on_Ubuntu_17.10.html</guid>
                <description>Synergy is an application to control remote screens with your local mouse and keyboard over the network, cross platform. You could use Linux as your main OS and have a seperate box with Windows next to it, and use your Linux mouse to control windows. On Ubuntu 17.10 the mouse cursor is not visible, but does work. This snippet provides a fix. Hint, wayland is in the way.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FreeIPA DNS workaround for DNS zone [...]. already exists in DNS and is handled by server(s):</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/FreeIPA_DNS_workaround_for_DNS_zone_already_exists_in_DNS_and_is_handled_by_servers.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/FreeIPA_DNS_workaround_for_DNS_zone_already_exists_in_DNS_and_is_handled_by_servers.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I ran into an issue with FreeIPA when trying to add an existing DNS zone. The zone already exists on the internet so, logically, FreeIPA wouldn't allow me to hijack this domain locally. My usecase is special, so I wanted to forcefully add this zone as a forward zone.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: restrict specific URLs to specific IP addresses</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_restrict_specific_urls_to_specific_ip_addresses.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_restrict_specific_urls_to_specific_ip_addresses.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to use haproxy to restrict certain URLs to certain IP addresses. For example, to make sure your admin interface can only be accessed from your company IP address. It also includes an example to prompt for a password if the visitor is from a different network.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check HTTP status code for a page on all DNS records</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Check_HTTP_status_code_for_a_page_on_all_DNS_records.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Check_HTTP_status_code_for_a_page_on_all_DNS_records.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small snippet using curl to check the status code of a given URL on all DNS records for a given domain. This site has a few A records in round robin mode, and sometimes the automatic deployment fails. Using this query I can check which server is the culprit and fix it manually.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Traceroute IPv6 to Smokeping Target config</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/IPv6_Traceroute_to_Smokeping_Target_Config.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/IPv6_Traceroute_to_Smokeping_Target_Config.html</guid>
                <description>This little one-liner converts the output of traceroute for IPv6 to Smokeping Target output. I had only setup my smokepings for IPv4. Recently we had an issue were network config was borked and the whole IPv4 network was not announced via BGP anymore. I was at home troubleshooting, but finding nothing since I have native IPv6 and that part still worked. My Smokeping did show loss, and that explicitly uses IPv4. That helped with the debugging a lot. I have a [IPv4][4] version of this article as well.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Firefox History stats with Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small script to gather some statistics from your Firefox history. First we use sqlite3 to parse the Firefox history database and get the last three months, then we remove all the IP addresses and port numbers and finally we sort and count it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Create /etc/shadow crypted password entries</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Create_etc_shadow_crypted_password_entries.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Create_etc_shadow_crypted_password_entries.html</guid>
                <description>These small snippets create password strings you can put in /etc/shadow when you need to reset a password on a system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - create playbooks and role file and folder structure</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ansible_-_create_playbooks_and_role_file_and_folder_structure.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ansible_-_create_playbooks_and_role_file_and_folder_structure.html</guid>
                <description>Because I always forget which folders and files go into a playbook folder.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Deborphan cleanup until no more orphaned packages left</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html</guid>
                <description>Deborphan removes packages it thinks your system doesn't need anymore. It is a great tool for package cleanup and maintenance. Sometimes, after cleaning up the packages, it will find new packages that are orphaned (because you just cleaned up). This is a small script that cleans up with deborphan until there is nothing more to cleanup.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Find all services using libssl to restart after an OpenSSL update</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html</guid>
                <description>When you update OpenSSL, the software that currently has the ssl libraries loaded in memory do not automatically load the updated libraries. A full system reboot resolves that problem, but sometimes that is not possible. This command shows you all the software that has loaded the libraries, allowing you to restart only those services. If you don't restart or reload after an update, the software might still be vulnerable to issues that the update fixed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get all IP ranges from an AS number</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_IP_ranges_from_an_AS_number.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_IP_ranges_from_an_AS_number.html</guid>
                <description>One of my clients wanted to block a few social networking websites. Since they have no IPv6 (yet) I figured the simplest way was to block access to the entire IP range. This won't work for all the CDN networks they use, but it does get you started. To find all the ranges beloning to an AS number you can query the whois.radb.net server with the AS number.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>pfSense allow web interface access on WAN from specific IP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/pfSense_allow_web_interface_access_on_WAN_from_specific_IP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/pfSense_allow_web_interface_access_on_WAN_from_specific_IP.html</guid>
                <description>pfSense is a fast and simple FreeBSD based firewall appliance with a nice web managent interface and the power of the pf firewall underneath. Normally the web interface is only accessible from the management LAN (or LAN by default) interface. If you for whatever reason locked yourself out or need access from a different IP via the WAN interface you can use the easyrule command line to temporarly add a rule that allows your remote IP in. This simple snippet shows you how.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Arch Linux AUR PKGBUILD generate new checksums</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch_Linux_AUR_PKGBUILD_generate_new_checksums.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch_Linux_AUR_PKGBUILD_generate_new_checksums.html</guid>
                <description>The AUR is a nice feature from Arch Linux, it allows anyone to create and upload a simple package build script, PKGBUILD, for a piece of software which is not in the repositories. Sometimes however, the PKGBUILD is outdated. You then need to manually fix it, by changing the download link or version. With a new version you get new checksums, and the makepkg command has a neat feature which generates the checksums for you.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Get the current or all Firefox tab urls in Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_the_current_or_all_Firefox_tab_urls_in_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This snippets gets the current firefox tab url or all the firefox tab url's. It uses the sessionstore.js file in your profile folder.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>CentOS 5 CA Certificate Bundle Update</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_5_CA_Certificate_Bundle_Update.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_5_CA_Certificate_Bundle_Update.html</guid>
                <description>This simple snippet shows you how to update the root ca certificate bundle on CentOS 5. Some websites have certificates signed by authorities not in the default bundle and those websites will not work with tools like git, curl, wget or anything else that uses https.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Traceroute to Smokeping Target config</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Traceroute_to_Smokeping_Target_Config.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Traceroute_to_Smokeping_Target_Config.html</guid>
                <description>This little one-liner converts the output of traceroute to Smokeping Target output. This way you can build your smokeping config faster.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Remove all Apple Remote Dekstop settings</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Remove_all_Apple_Remote_Desktop_settings.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Remove_all_Apple_Remote_Desktop_settings.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to remove all Apple Remote Desktop settings. My ARD installation recently stopped working correctly, having problems discovering new machines and connecting to already set up machines. These commands wipe all settings and the ARD installation is clean again. This solved my problem.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused CentOS/Red Hat kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This small article will show you how to remove unused kernels in Red Hat or CentOS. This is sometimes necessary because the /boot partition can fill up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Simple command line arguments</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Simple_Command_Line_Arguments.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add command line arguments to your script. It is very simple, non-positional and does not use getopts.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Apache access/error log to syslog</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Apache_access_and_error_log_to_syslog.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Apache_access_and_error_log_to_syslog.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to redirect the Apache access log to syslog using the Customlog statement, and the Error log to syslog via the ErrorLog statement.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: set specific ssl ciphers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_set_specific_ssl_ciphers.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_set_specific_ssl_ciphers.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to set specific ciphers for haproxy when using an ssl frontend.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: add strict transport security or any other http header</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_add_strict_transport_security_or_any_other_http_header.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_add_strict_transport_security_or_any_other_http_header.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to add a header to a haproxy response, for example, the HSTS header (http strict transport security).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: ssl backends</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_ssl_backends.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_ssl_backends.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to configure an ssl backend on haproxy 1.5 or higher.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: redirect to ssl or other website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_redirect_to_ssl_or_any_other_website.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_redirect_to_ssl_or_any_other_website.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to use haproxy to redirect http traffic to https or any other website</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Corosync Notes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Corosync_Notes.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Corosync_Notes.html</guid>
                <description>These are my notes and command snippets for usage with Corosync.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused Ubuntu kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This one liner will help you remove unused Ubuntu kernels. Ubuntu does not remove kernels when they install a new one, however the default /boot partition is relatively small, about 100MB. So after 10 kernels, you can get No Space Left On Device errors with apt-get upgrading. Then you can eitehr remove them manually, or use this one liner to automatically remove them all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL One liner to create self signed certificate</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_One_line_to_create_self_signed_certificate.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_One_line_to_create_self_signed_certificate.html</guid>
                <description>This is a one-liner for OpenSSL to generate a self signed certificate and private key.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Check if item is in array</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Check_If_Item_Is_In_Array.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how find out if an array has an item.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Add colour output to your script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Add_Color_Output_To_Your_Scripts.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples, tips and tutorials for Bash (Scripts). This bash bit shows you how to add coloured output to your scripts</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Debug Logging</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Debug_Logging.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to add debug logging to a bash script.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Bits: Trap Control C (SIGTERM)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_Bits_Trap_Control_C_SIGTERM.html</guid>
                <description>Bash Bits are small examples and tips for Bash Scripts. This bash bit shows you how to capture a Control C signal in a bash script, for example, to clean up any temp or pid files when your script is killed or closed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Enable access for assistive devices via the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Enable-Access-for-assistive-devices-via-command-line.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Enable-Access-for-assistive-devices-via-command-line.html</guid>
                <description>This command enables access for assistive devices on Apple OS X machines via the command line. This is needed for software like SpectacleApp or SizeUp. This article has methods for OS X Mavericks 10.9 as for 10.8 and 10.7</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ dnsmasq set capabilities failed fix</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</guid>
                <description>When running dnsmasq under OpenVZ I sometimes get an error when restarting: set capabilities failed. This is because dnsmasq starts as root, then does privileged stuff and then drops to the configured run user. In OpenVZ these permissions are not passed to the VPS, sadly. These three commands fix the problem.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL - Generate Psuedo Random Passwords</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Password_Generator.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Password_Generator.html</guid>
                <description>This a snippet to generate a psuedo random password fast via the command line with OpenSSL. It generates a number of random bytes, which can either be output raw, as Base64 or as HEX. The Base64 output is a good password most of the time.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Disable Notification Center</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Disable_Notification_Centre.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X-Disable_Notification_Centre.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to disable the OS X Notification Center completely, the menu item and the sidebar. It also gives you the command to enable it again.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Strip all non-ascii characters from a file</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Strip_all_non-ascii_characters_from_a_file.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Strip_all_non-ascii_characters_from_a_file.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet strips all non-ascii characters from a file. It backs up the original file. This is handy if you have input for programs that bork on non-ascii input like older mainframes and such.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash Incremental History Search / Autocomplete </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Incremental_History_Search_Autocomplete.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet for your .bashrc or your .inputrc changes the Up/Down arrow behavior to autocomplete what is already typed instead of just go back in history.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Turn Bonjour off or on via the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_Bonjour_off_or_on_via_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet switches off Bonjour on OS X via the command line or Apple Remote Desktop. This is useful when you want to disable iChat or Messages chatting on the local network. Bonjour is Apple's implementation of Zero configuration networking (Zeroconf), a group of technologies that includes service discovery, address assignment, and hostname resolution. Bonjour locates devices such as printers, other computers, and the services that those devices offer on a local network using multicast Domain Name System (mDNS) service records.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X - Turn off sleep from the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_off_sleep_from_the_command_line.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_Turn_off_sleep_from_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet turns off Sleep on an OS X machine, either iMac or Macbook. Normally when a Mac is not used it goes in sleep mode, this turns that off.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OS X: Turn firewall on or off from the command line</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_-_Turn_firewall_on_or_off_from_the_command_line.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS_X_-_Turn_firewall_on_or_off_from_the_command_line.html</guid>
                <description>This command lets you turn the build in OS X firewall on and off, on both for specific services or essential services. It works with OS X 10.5, 10.6, 10.7 and 10.8.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Join Mac OS X to an Active Directory / OpenDLAP directory from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet joins an Mac OS X computer to a Windows Active Directory or OpenLDAP Directory domain from the Command Line or via Apple Remote Desktop.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>HP ILO - Quickly gather ILO version and firmware information via CURL</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/HP-ILO-Quickly-gather-firmware-and-version-information-with-CUR.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/HP-ILO-Quickly-gather-firmware-and-version-information-with-CUR.html</guid>
                <description>Have a lot of HP servers with ILO cards, and want to gather information from them quicly? By default you can get some information in XML format, for ILO, ILO2, ILO3 and ILO4, with curl.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NGINX: Hide / Block .git and .svn folders</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Block_access_to_.git_or_.svn_project_folders.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Block_access_to_.git_or_.svn_project_folders.html</guid>
                <description>This little nginx config snippets helps you prohibit access to .git or .svn folders in nginx</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NGINX: Catch all error codes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Catch_all_error_codes.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/NGINX_Catch_all_error_codes.html</guid>
                <description>This little nginx config snippet shows you how to catch all error codes and show a single unified error page.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Systemd rosetta / cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</guid>
                <description>A reference for systemd, for sysadmins who love plain old init.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL Generate CSR non-interactive</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_generate_CSR_non-interactive.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_generate_CSR_non-interactive.html</guid>
                <description>This is a short command to generate a CSR (certificate signing request) with openssl without being prompted for the values which go in the certificate's Subject field.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL match certificate and private key</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_match_certificate_with_private_key.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_match_certificate_with_private_key.html</guid>
                <description>This check lets you know if a certificate matches a private key. Today I had to set up something but I kept getting ssl errors. Turns out, the certificate did not match the private key, because the private key file was damaged. This is how I found out.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Fix MySQL plugin on Ubuntu 12.04 and Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Debian 6 and Ubuntu 12.04 the Munin MySQL plugin does not work by default because of a missing package. Here is a little trick on fixing it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Set up the NGINX status plugin on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This post will show you how to set up the Munin plugin to monitor NGINX (nginx_request and nginx_status) and graph it. You need to change some URLs in the config because by default this is wrong.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exploring /proc/ - tips and tricks for the procfs</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Procfs_tips_and_tricks.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Procfs_tips_and_tricks.html</guid>
                <description>This article has a lot of nice tips and trics on using the procfs linux virtual file system.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Fix CentOS IPTables rule saving (iptables: Saving firewall rules to /etc/sysconfig/iptables: /etc/init.d/iptables: line 274: restorecon: command not found)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_Save_iptables_restorecon_error.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/CentOS_Save_iptables_restorecon_error.html</guid>
                <description>On a default CentOS installation, when trying to execute the iptables save command you can get an error like iptables: Saving firewall rules to /etc/sysconfig/iptables: /etc/init.d/iptables: line 274: restorecon: command not found. Read this article to find out how to fix it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenSSL one liner to get expiry date from SSL Certificate of any website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Get_Certificate_Expiry_Date_and_Other_Info.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenSSL_Get_Certificate_Expiry_Date_and_Other_Info.html</guid>
                <description>This little openssl one liner gets the expiry date from a website's ssl certificate.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set OS X hostname from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Change-Hostname.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Change-Hostname.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet helps you change the hostname of a computer running OS X. OS X defines the hostname/computer name in three places and you need to change all of them.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Correctly grep and display the uptime, load average and amount of users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_uptime_load_and_users_with_grep_sed_and_awk.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Postfix snippets - not finished</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Set_up_an_IMAPS_and_SMTPS_mail_server_with_Postfix_and_Dovecot.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Set_up_an_IMAPS_and_SMTPS_mail_server_with_Postfix_and_Dovecot.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash - do something in every subdirectory</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash_-_Do_something_in_every_subdirectory_of_a_folder.html</guid>
                <description>Snippet which has a copy paste bash for loop to do something in a directory.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Some Bash and Arch Tweaks </title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Arch-bash-pacman-bashrc-tips.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash script for massive rename to numbers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Bash-massive-rename-to-numbers.html</guid>
                <description>Older snippet which was used for dynamic wallpaper switching.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Javascript tricks</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Javascript-tricks.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Javascript-tricks.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Convert FLV's to MP3</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Convert-all-flv-files-in-a-folder-to-mp3.html</guid>
                <description>Bash snippet to convert all .flv files to .mp3.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bash ja/nee keuze</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Ja-Nee-keuze-toevoegen-in-een-bash-script.html</guid>
                <description>Dutch snippet on adding a yes/no choice in a bash script</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Imagemagick thumbnailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Imagemagick-thumbnailer.html</guid>
                <description>Create some nice thumbnails with Imagemagick</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Vim Cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Vim_Cheatsheet.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Vim_Cheatsheet.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    