<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag ssh on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/ssh.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag ssh on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/ssh.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Get all SSH public keys from gitlab</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_SSH_public_keys_from_gitlab.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Get_all_SSH_public_keys_from_gitlab.html</guid>
                <description>This small snippet gets all the SSH keys from a gitlab instance. You need to be an administrator, then you can query all keys at once using the API. On the web frontend you can only see the keys per user, not all at once in an overview.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>nginx 1.15.2, ssl_preread_protocol, multiplex HTTPS and SSH on the same port</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/nginx_1.15.2_ssl_preread_protocol_multiplex_https_and_ssh_on_the_same_port.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/nginx_1.15.2_ssl_preread_protocol_multiplex_https_and_ssh_on_the_same_port.html</guid>
                <description>The NGINX blog recently had a nice article on a new feature of NGINX 1.15.2, $ssl_preread_protocol. This allows you to multiplex HTTPS and other SSL protocols on the same port, or as their blog states, 'to distinguish between SSL/TLS and other protocols when forwarding traffic using a TCP (stream) proxy'. This can be used to run SSH and HTTPS on the same port (or any other SSL protocol next to HTTPS). By running SSH and HTTPS on the same port, one can circumvent certain firewall restrictions. If the session looks like HTTPS, nginx will handle it, if it looks like something else, it will forward it to the configured other program. I used to use SSHL to get this functionality, but now it's built into the nginx webserver. This small guide will cover the installation of the latest version of nginx on Ubuntu (16.04) and configuring this multiplex feature.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Where is dropbearconvert on Ubuntu?</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Where_is_dropbearconvert_on_ubuntu.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Where_is_dropbearconvert_on_ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>Dropbear is a lightweight SSH server and client implementation, often used on embedded systems and routers. If you use the dropbear SSH client (dbclient) and want to use a private key, it needs to be in the dropbear format and cannot have a passphrase. Dropbear provides a conversion utility to convert openssh style keys to dropbear style keys, dropbearconvert, but on Ubuntu it's not in your $PATH. This means you have to provide the full path to execute it, which is cumbersome. There is a bug in Ubuntu that has been reported in 2012, but in Ubuntu 18.04 (2019) it's still not fixed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Disable motd news or (parts of) the dynamic motd on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Disable_dynamic_motd_and_motd_news_spam_on_Ubuntu_18.04.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Disable_dynamic_motd_and_motd_news_spam_on_Ubuntu_18.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Ubuntu 18.04 and up, when you login via SSH you are greeted with some news via motd (message of the day) that includes advertisements and messages from Canonical (via motd.ubuntu.com). This small guide shows you how to disable news, (parts of) the dynamic motd or just revert back to a plain old /etc/motd file.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSH on Windows Server 2019 (including how to sudo)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH_on_Windows_Server_2019.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH_on_Windows_Server_2019.html</guid>
                <description>On hackernews I saw a Microsoft blog post stating that Windows Server 2019 now includes OpenSSH. In this post I'll try out both the client and server on a Windows 2019 server, including how to login as a Active Directory Domain user and how to generate and place and SSH keypair. The bonus this time is how to elevate permissions via SSH on Windows, sudo but way more complicated. This guide is also applicable on Windows 10, build 1809 and up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Linux on Microsoft Azure? Disable this built-in root-access backdoor (wa-linux-agent)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_on_Microsoft_Azure_Disable_this_built_in_root_access_backdoor.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_on_Microsoft_Azure_Disable_this_built_in_root_access_backdoor.html</guid>
                <description>Are you running Linux on Microsoft Azure? Then by default anyone with access to your Azure portal can run commands as root in your VM, reset SSH keys, user passwords and SSH configuration. This article explains what the backdoor (wa-linux-agent) is, what it is meant to do, how it can be disabled and removed and what the implications are. OpenStack/QEMU also have an agent/backdoor which is covered in this article as well.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>That time when one of my HP-UX servers lost half of it's RAM (and how to connect to an HP iLO 2 with modern OpenSSH (7.6+))</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/That_time_one_of_my_HP-UX_machines_lost_half_its_ram_openssh_7.3_ilo_2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/That_time_one_of_my_HP-UX_machines_lost_half_its_ram_openssh_7.3_ilo_2.html</guid>
                <description>One of my favorite sayings is: 'Hardware is stupid, move everything to the cloud!'. The cloud is just someone elses computer, but at least I'm not responsible for the hardware anymore, since hardware breaks. When a VM breaks, because you use configuration management and version control, just roll out a new one. We all know that's not true, but still, the thought of it is nice. Last week one of the HP-UX machines had a failing disk and this week it's back with a whole new issue. After it was rebooted (due to issues with the services running on it), the Event Monitoring Service (EMS) sent an email regarding RAM issues and after manual checking it seems the machine lost half of it's RAM. It should have 16 GB and now it only has 8 GB. You might imagine my suprise. This post goes into my troubleshooting, since I was not able to go to the machine, shut it down and check if the RAM was still there. I'll cover the use of cstm (Support Tool Manager), how to connect to the HP iLO (out of band access) with modern OpenSSH (7.2) and the steps I took to gather information on what might have happened. </description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenStack nova get-password, set-password and post encrypted password to metadata service</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenStack_nova_get_-_password_set_-_password_and_post_encrypted_password_to_metadata_service.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenStack_nova_get_-_password_set_-_password_and_post_encrypted_password_to_metadata_service.html</guid>
                <description>When you create images for an OpenStack Cloud you want to use 'cloud' features. Fancy term for automatic resizing of your instance disk, adding an SSH key, (re)setting passwords and executing scripts on first boot to configure your instance further. OpenStack provides the metadata service for instances, which supplies information for the instance, like its public IP, SSH public key that was provided and vendor or user provided data like scripts or information. The OpenStack metadata service allows an instance to post data to an endpoint wich can be retreived with the 'nova get-password' command. It is meant to be an encrypted password (with the public SSH key) but it can be any plain text as well and it doesn't have to be the root password. In this guide I'll go over the scripts I use inside linux images to post a password to the metadata service and the 'nova' commands such as 'set-password' and 'get-password'. That includes decrypting a password with an SSH key that is password-protected (Horizon and nova don't support that) and the 'nova set-password' command, which sets the root password inside an instance when it has the 'qemu-guest-agent' installed and running.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nitrokey Start: Getting started guide (gnuk openpgp token)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_Start_Getting_started_guide.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_Start_Getting_started_guide.html</guid>
                <description>The Nitrokey Start is an OpenPGP USB token. It supports three 2048 bit GPG keys and is based on gnuk. Gnuk is an implementation of USB cryptographic token for GPG. Cryptographic token is a store of private keys and it computes cryptographic functions on the device. The main difference with other GPG cards like the Nitrokey Pro or the OpenPGP card is that this device does not use a smartcard. Whereas the other devices are basically USB smartcard readers, the Nitrokey Start has everything in it's firmware. This article is a getting started guide where I talk about the initial setup of the device, setting up a user PIN, an admin PIN and a reset code, generating the key and subkeys on the device, or loading external keys into the device and usage examples with GPG, OpenSSH and Thunderbird.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - pre-backup all container dump script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</guid>
                <description>This simple script creates a vzdump of all the OpenVZ containers on a machine. It can be used before an actual backup, in my case the actual backup excludes the container path /var/lib/vz/private. This because a dump is easier to backup because it has much less files in it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Shared Git repository over ssh for multiple users</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Shared_Git_repository_via_ssh_for_multiple_users.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to set up a shared git repo with multiple accounts over ssh. Only ssh, not gitolite or any other software. This is usefull if you have a small team of people that don't often need access to the repo and don't want something like github or bitbucket. With this you can use existing infrastructure.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clear Uncluttered SSH client config with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>Openssh allows you to configure parameters like username, port, proxycommand, key and more in the ~/.ssh/config file. If you have many servers this file can become cluttered and maintaining it can become a not so nice task. This simple guide shows you how you can use a conf.d directory with seperate smaller files which gets converted to the big config file by Ansible</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - Container to Template</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to convert an OpenVZ (Proxmox) container to a template. You can then use this template on any other OpenVZ (or proxmox) host. This can be used either to migrate containers or to create a kind of master image to deploy new hosts from.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Proxmox VE - One Public IP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to set up Proxmox with only one public IP. We will configure an extra interface bridge and make sure VM traffic is NATed. I have a few dedicated servers, some run Proxmox. Most of them however have only a few IP's. Therefore the VM's in proxmox cannot all have a public IP. For most of them that is not a problem. If needed I run a proxy or set up iptables to forward ports to the VM's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up your own truly secure, encrypted and shared file synchronization, aka Dropbox clone</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Set_up_your_own_truly_secure_encrypted_shared_storage_aka_Dropbox_clone.html</guid>
                <description>This article describes my truly secure, encrypted file synchronization service. It used EncFS and dvcs-autosync which lets me share only the encrypted data and mount that locally to get the plaintext. It works on OS X, Linux and ARM linux. This article has setup instructions for all those platforms.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Basic website and database backups with Duplicity</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Website-and-database-backup-with-Duplicity.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will help you backup your website and database with Duplicity. You can safely backup your MySQL, MongoDB, website and other data to an off-site location.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Restrict SSH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Restrict_SSH.html</guid>
                <description>restrict_ssh.sh is a bash script which restricts ssh for a user to a set of commands via .ssh/authorized_keys, and log it verbosely.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Limit access to openssh features with the Match option</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Limit_access_to_openssh_features_with_the_Match_keyword.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Limit_access_to_openssh_features_with_the_Match_keyword.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Persistent reverse (NAT bypassing) SSH tunnel access with autossh</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Autossh_persistent_tunnels.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Autossh_persistent_tunnels.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ProxBash - a bash script to manage Proxmox VE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</guid>
                <description>ProxMox VE is a very nice piece of software to setup a VM host very fast, which also is easy manageable via a webinterface. It supports both OpenVZ and KVM. I use it to manage a few VM's to test stuff on and it works really great. However, I'm a command line lover, and I thought it would be nice to be able to 'Manage' Proxmox VE from a bash shell. And I've written a script to do just that. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSHdialog</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/SSHDialog.html</guid>
                <description>SSHdialog - Small command line SSH helper</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    