<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag ssl-labs on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/ssl-labs.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag ssl-labs on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/ssl-labs.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Stong SSL Security on lighttpd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_lighttpd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_lighttpd.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up strong SSL security on the lighttpd webserver. We do this by updating OpenSSL to the latest version to mitigate attacks like Heartbleed, disabling SSL Compression and EXPORT ciphers to mitigate attacks like FREAK, CRIME and LogJAM, disabling SSLv3 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will set up a strong ciphersuite that enables Forward Secrecy when possible. We also enable HSTS and HPKP. This way we have a strong and future proof ssl configuration and we get an A+ on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Strong SSL Security on Apache2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_Apache2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_Apache2.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up strong SSL security on the Apache2 webserver. We do this by updating OpenSSL to the latest version to mitigate attacks like Heartbleed, disabling SSL Compression and EXPORT ciphers to mitigate attacks like FREAK, CRIME and LogJAM, disabling SSLv3 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will set up a strong ciphersuite that enables Forward Secrecy when possible. We also enable HSTS and HPKP. This way we have a strong and future proof ssl configuration and we get an A+ on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Strong SSL Security on nginx</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_nginx.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Strong_SSL_Security_On_nginx.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up strong SSL security on the nginx webserver. We do this by updating OpenSSL to the latest version to mitigate attacks like Heartbleed, disabling SSL Compression and EXPORT ciphers to mitigate attacks like FREAK, CRIME and LogJAM, disabling SSLv3 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will set up a strong ciphersuite that enables Forward Secrecy when possible. We also enable HSTS and HPKP. This way we have a strong and future proof ssl configuration and we get an A+ on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OCSP Stapling on Apache</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_Apache2.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_Apache2.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up OCSP stapling on Apache. OCSP stapling is an enhancement to the standard OCSP protocol that delivers OCSP responses from the server with the certificate, eliminating the need for relying parties (web users) to check OCSP responses with the issuing CA. This has the effect of reducing bandwidth, improving perceived site performance, and increasing security for everyone involved in establishing the secure session.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OCSP Stapling on nginx</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_nginx.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OCSP_Stapling_on_nginx.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up OCSP stapling on nginx. OCSP stapling is an enhancement to the standard OCSP protocol that delivers OCSP responses from the server with the certificate, eliminating the need for relying parties (web users) to check OCSP responses with the issuing CA. This has the effect of reducing bandwidth, improving perceived site performance, and increasing security for everyone involved in establishing the secure session.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Stong SSL Security on Lighttpd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Lighttpd_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Lighttpd_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up strong SSL security on the lighttpd webserver. We do this by disabling SSL Compression to mitigate the CRIME attack, disable SSLv3 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will set up a strong ciphersuite that enables Forward Secrecy when possible. This way we have a strong and future proof ssl configuration and we get an A on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Pass the SSL Labs Test on NGINX (Mitigate the CRIME and BEAST attack, Disable SSLv2 and Enable Perfect Forward Secrecy).</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_NGINX_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_NGINX_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to get an A on the SSL Labs test using the NGINX webserver. We do this by disabling CBC based ciphers to mitigate the BEAST attack, disabling SSL Compression to mitigate the CRIME attack, disable SSLv2 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will enable Perfect Forward Secrecy when possible. This way we have a future proof ssl configuration and we get an A on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Pass the SSL Labs Test on Apache2 (Mitigate the CRIME and BEAST attack, Disable SSLv2 and Enable Perfect Forward Secrecy).</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Apache2_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Pass_the_SSL_Labs_Test_on_Apache2_(Mitigate_the_CRIME_and_BEAST_attack_-_Disable_SSLv2_-_Enable_PFS).html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to get an A on the SSL Labs test using the Apache2 webserver. We do this by disabling CBC based ciphers to mitigate the BEAST attack, disabling SSL Compression to mitigate the CRIME attack, disable SSLv2 and below because of vulnerabilities in the protocol and we will enable Perfect Forward Secrecy when possible. This way we have a future proof ssl configuration and we get an A on the Qually Labs SSL Test.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    