<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag strongswan on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/strongswan.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag strongswan on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/strongswan.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Ubuntu 16.04 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_16.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_16.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server on Ubuntu 16.04 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC protocol stack because of vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 52, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_52_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_52_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 52, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Ubuntu 15.10 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.10.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.10.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server on Ubuntu 15.04 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC protocol stack because of vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Ubuntu 15.04 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server on Ubuntu 15.04 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC protocol stack because of vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Centos 7 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_CentOS_7.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_CentOS_7.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server with CentOS 7 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSECP protocol stack because of recent vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Keepalived notify script, execute action on failover</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived_notify_script_execute_action_on_failover.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Keepalived_notify_script_execute_action_on_failover.html</guid>
                <description>Keepalived supports running scripts on VRRP state change. This can come in handy when you need to execute an action when a failover occurs. In my case, I have a VPN running on a Virtual IP and want to make sure the VPN only runs on the node with the Virtual IP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    