<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag subfolder on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/subfolder.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag subfolder on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/subfolder.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>nginx 1.15.2, ssl_preread_protocol, multiplex HTTPS and SSH on the same port</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/nginx_1.15.2_ssl_preread_protocol_multiplex_https_and_ssh_on_the_same_port.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/nginx_1.15.2_ssl_preread_protocol_multiplex_https_and_ssh_on_the_same_port.html</guid>
                <description>The NGINX blog recently had a nice article on a new feature of NGINX 1.15.2, $ssl_preread_protocol. This allows you to multiplex HTTPS and other SSL protocols on the same port, or as their blog states, 'to distinguish between SSL/TLS and other protocols when forwarding traffic using a TCP (stream) proxy'. This can be used to run SSH and HTTPS on the same port (or any other SSL protocol next to HTTPS). By running SSH and HTTPS on the same port, one can circumvent certain firewall restrictions. If the session looks like HTTPS, nginx will handle it, if it looks like something else, it will forward it to the configured other program. I used to use SSHL to get this functionality, but now it's built into the nginx webserver. This small guide will cover the installation of the latest version of nginx on Ubuntu (16.04) and configuring this multiplex feature.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>NGINX: Proxy folders to different root</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NGINX_proxy_folder_to_different_root.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NGINX_proxy_folder_to_different_root.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to have NGINX use different folders as different upstream proxy's, without the proxy also having the folder. For example, if you proxy www.example.com/wiki to server wiki.example.com, by default it will go to wiki.example.com/wiki. This tutorial has a rewrite rule to fix that.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    