<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag systemd on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/systemd.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag systemd on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/systemd.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>systemd: Don't fear change</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/systemd_dont_fear_change.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/systemd_dont_fear_change.html</guid>
                <description>This article talks about systemd in Red Hat Enterprise Linux / CentOS 7. It gives some usage examples and talks about the differences between systemd, upstart and sysvinit.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Arch Linux on a Raspberry Pi with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_a_Raspberry_Pi_with_Arch_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_on_a_Raspberry_Pi_with_Arch_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Arch Linux on a Raspberry Pi using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Transmission Web on a Raspberry Pi with Arch Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Transmission-Raspberry-Pi-Arch-Linux.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's was running a test setup of the Citadel groupware service. The test was sucessfull, so I set up a real world setup. The Raspberry Pi would serve another purpose, namely, a Linux Torrent seedbox. As in, to seed Linux torrents from linuxtracker.org. I choose Transmission for this, because it is simple, fast and stable. Transmission has a good webinterface, plus it allows access from remote clients with the transmission-remote gui packages. This article shows you how to set it up on a Raspberry Pi running Arch Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>rc.local support on Arch Linux with systemd</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/rc.local_support_on_Arch_Linux_and_systemd.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/rc.local_support_on_Arch_Linux_and_systemd.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple tutorial on how to get /etc/rc.local support back in Arch Linux or any distro with systemd. Arch Linux uses systemd. Therefore, init functions like rc.local are not supported anymore. This systemd service allows you to have support for `/etc/rc.local`.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Systemd rosetta / cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</guid>
                <description>A reference for systemd, for sysadmins who love plain old init.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    