<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag tetris on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/tetris.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag tetris on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/tetris.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Compiling TETRIS from 1992 on OpenVMS x86 in 2024!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Tetris_from_1992_on_OpenVMS_x86_in_2024.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Tetris_from_1992_on_OpenVMS_x86_in_2024.html</guid>
                <description>Since [DECWindows / CDE](/s/blog/OpenVMS_x86_E9.2-3_fixes_CDE_and_adds_Guest_Console.html) now works on OpenVMS x86 (from 9.2-3 onwards) there is much fun stuff to do. Back in 2021 I wrote an article on the [CDE desktop on Alpha / AXPbox](/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html) and also an article on how to run [CDE on modern linux, since it's still developed](/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html#toc_6). Both articles included a game, **GENERIC-TETRIS** from 1992, [written by Qiang Alex Zhao](https://web.archive.org/web/20240815073318/https://sites.cc.gatech.edu/gvu/people/qiang.a.zhao/Games.html).
After getting the (remote) desktop working I wanted to compile and run Tetris to continue this lineage, from VAX, to Alpha, to Linux/CDE, to x86 VMS. I haven't got an Itanium to run it on, but if anyone has one left willing to send this way, feel free to contact me. This article includes the precompiled tetris binary for OpenVMS x86 and instructions to compile the source. The code required some minor modifications which I'll also cover, but that's not surprising for code that hasn't changed much since 1992 to be compiled in 2024. This article also shows you how to install curl on OpenVMS.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 14:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 14:33:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>The Common Desktop Environment (CDE) is still developed and modern in 2021</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html</guid>
                <description>While playing around with the GUI on OpenVMS I was looking for CDE documentation and I found out CDE is still being developed and can be installed on modern linux. This quick post shows you how to install CDE on Debian 10 and includes a bit on compiling GENERIC TETRIS, the same program I installed on OpenVMS. Really cool to compile and run a game from 1992 on a retro/modern desktop environment.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS CDE Desktop Remote X session GUI (on AXPbox)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html</guid>
                <description>Last year November, I posted on a new OpenVMS related project, AXPbox, the open source Alpha emulator, a fork of es40 by Tom&amp;aacute;&amp;scaron; Glozar. Last week I put together the first official release of AXPbox, one of the changes being in the network code, making it more stable, thus being able to run a remote X session. Meaning, you can run the CDE desktop and enjoy everything the OpenVMS GUI has to offer. This article shows you how to run the CDE GUI in a remote X session, including switching between the old Motif look and the new DECWindows and how to run Tetris.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    