<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag tty on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/tty.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag tty on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/tty.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Get serial port data on the web with live updating</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Get_serial_port_data_on_the_web_with_live_updating.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Get_serial_port_data_on_the_web_with_live_updating.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I was asked to build a test setup to measure the accuracy of a few loadcells (weight sensors) in a frame. Someone other than me would execute the test and required access to the measured data, preferably live and without needing knowledge of ssh or linux. The weight sensors can be read with an openscale board from sparkfun via a serial connection which the board emulates over USB (via an FTDI chip), via that same serial connection you can also calibrate them or change settings like amount of decimals. As a quick solution I created a webpage that uses a small amount of javascript to live update the readings from the board. screen is used to capture the output of the serial connection to a file which the webpage displays and updates. In this article I'll talk about how I put various bits of software together to get the output of the serial connection onto a nice webpage with live updating.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Run software on the tty1 console instead of getty login on Ubuntu 14.04 and 16.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Run_software_on_tty1_console_instead_of_login_getty.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Run_software_on_tty1_console_instead_of_login_getty.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I wanted to change the default login prompt on the tty1 console on an OpenStack instance to automatically run htop. Instead of logging in via the console, I wanted it to start up htop right away and nothing else. Ubuntu 14.04 uses init and Ubuntu 16.04 uses systemd. Both ways are shown in this tutorial.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    