<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag types on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/types.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag types on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/types.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>and &amp; or are valid in C++ (alternative tokens)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/and_or_are_valid_Cpp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/and_or_are_valid_Cpp.html</guid>
                <description>A post on lobste.rs on the C feature trigraphs triggered me to write this piece on the C++ feature, alternative tokens. I've recently suprised a co- worker by using an if statement with 'or' instead of '||', which works fine, but he never saw it before. It's in C++ since C++ 11, but MSVC requires a specific compiler flag ('/Za') or the 'iso646.h' header. This post has a few samples on the usage inclusing other alternative tokens like bitor, xor and or_eq.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Cooking with C++ templates and stronger types</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Cooking_with_Cpp_templates_and_stronger_types.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Cooking_with_Cpp_templates_and_stronger_types.html</guid>
                <description>To gain a better understanding of C++ templates I'm playing around with them. Most of the online guides stop at the example of a simple template to, for example, get the max of two inputs, or cover just a bit more (like how to overload operators for your specific template classes to make &lt;&lt; and + / - work). Combining templates with a stronger type to pass stuff around led me to a test kitchen. As in, some code with ingredients, amounts and an oven. One small thing kept it from working, after some feedback it turned out I was passing the wrong parameters to the template. Afterwards the error also made sense. This post covers both my learning and a small piece on stronger types.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    