<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag ubuntu on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/ubuntu.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag ubuntu on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/ubuntu.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>MySQL restore after a crash and disk issues</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/MySQL_restore_after_a_crash_and_disk_issues.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to restore a MySQL server. The hardware had issues with the storage and required some FSCK's, disk replacements and a lot of RAID and LVM love to get working again. Which was the easy part. MySQL was a bit harder to fix. This post describes the proces I used to get MySQL working again with a recent backup. In this case it was a replicated setup so the client had no actual downtime. </description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Firefox History stats with Bash</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Firefox_History_Stats_with_Bash.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small script to gather some statistics from your Firefox history. First we use sqlite3 to parse the Firefox history database and get the last three months, then we remove all the IP addresses and port numbers and finally we sort and count it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Ubuntu 16.04 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_16.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_16.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server on Ubuntu 16.04 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC protocol stack because of vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nagios 4 + Nagiosgraph (latest) installation on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_Core_4_Installation_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Nagios_Core_4_Installation_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the latest Nagios Core (4.2.1) on Ubuntu 12.04 and 14.04. Nagios is an open source computer system monitoring, network monitoring and infrastructure monitoring software application. Nagios offers monitoring and alerting services for servers, switches, applications, and services. It alerts the users when things go wrong and alerts them a second time when the problem has been resolved. The version in the Ubuntu 12.04 repositories is quite old, it is still the in the 3 branch. This guide helps to fix that by using the latest Nagios version. We also install Nagiosgraph, a plugin for Nagios which gives you graps of the metrics.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Migrating personal webapps and services</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Migrating_personal_services_and_webapps.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I've migrated some of my personal servers and services to new machines and newer operating system versions. I prefer to migrate instead of upgrading the OS for a number of reasons. I'll also talk about the migration process and some stuff to remember when migrating web applications and services.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 02, 2016</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_02_2016.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 02 of 2016, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Deborphan cleanup until no more orphaned packages left</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Deborphan_cleanup_until_no_more_orphaned_packages_left.html</guid>
                <description>Deborphan removes packages it thinks your system doesn't need anymore. It is a great tool for package cleanup and maintenance. Sometimes, after cleaning up the packages, it will find new packages that are orphaned (because you just cleaned up). This is a small script that cleans up with deborphan until there is nothing more to cleanup.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Microsoft Office 2013 and 2010 on Linux</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Office_2013_and_2010_on_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Office_2013_and_2010_on_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to run Microsoft Office 2013 and 2010 on Linux using CrossOver. It guides you through the installation and gives a review on what parts of the Office suite work with Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recursively find all [installed] package dependencies</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Recursively_find_all_installed_package_dependencies.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Recursively_find_all_installed_package_dependencies.html</guid>
                <description>This small script shows you all packages [installed] that are a dependency from a package, and the dependencies of those packages. I installed the build-essential package, but apt-get remove-ing that package doens't remove the development tools. So I was wondering what packages were installed, including those dependencies, to remove the ones I didn't want. This small script shows you all packages that are dependencies of a package, and repeats that for those packages.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Ubuntu 15.10 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.10.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.10.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server on Ubuntu 15.04 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC protocol stack because of vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC VPN on Ubuntu 15.04 with StrongSwan</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_vpn_with_Ubuntu_15.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC VPN server on Ubuntu 15.04 using StrongSwan as the IPsec server and for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC protocol stack because of vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all recent operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Recap of week 51, 2015</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Recap_of_week_51_2015.html</guid>
                <description>Recap of week 51, covering open source and sysadmin related news, articles, guides, talks, discussions and fun stuff.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install Ubuntu Linux on the LG Chromebase</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/LG_Chromebase_Linux.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/LG_Chromebase_Linux.html</guid>
                <description>I recently acquired the LG Chromebase 22CV241-W. It is an All in One type machine with Chrome OS. The hardware, excluding the screen and lack of battery, is largely the same as the Acer C720. Of course I removed Chrome OS and installed a real Linux on it, of which you'll find instructions below. In my case it is Ubuntu Mate. Arch Linux also works fine, but this was for someone else, so a more beginner friendly distro seemed to be a better choise. This article will cover the removal of Chrome OS and the installation of Ubuntu Mate on the LG Chromebase.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Find all services using libssl to restart after an OpenSSL update</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Find_all_services_using_libssl_to_restart_after_an_OpenSSL_update.html</guid>
                <description>When you update OpenSSL, the software that currently has the ssl libraries loaded in memory do not automatically load the updated libraries. A full system reboot resolves that problem, but sometimes that is not possible. This command shows you all the software that has loaded the libraries, allowing you to restart only those services. If you don't restart or reload after an update, the software might still be vulnerable to issues that the update fixed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing Virtual Machines with virt-install, plus copy pastable distro install one-liners</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</guid>
                <description>virt-install is a command line tool for creating new KVM , Xen or Linux container guests using the libvirt hypervisor management library. It allows you to create a VM and start an installation from the command line. This article has a few copy pastable getting started examples for different distro's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Clear Uncluttered SSH client config with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Clear_Uncluttered_SSH_client_config_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>Openssh allows you to configure parameters like username, port, proxycommand, key and more in the ~/.ssh/config file. If you have many servers this file can become cluttered and maintaining it can become a not so nice task. This simple guide shows you how you can use a conf.d directory with seperate smaller files which gets converted to the big config file by Ansible</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 12.04 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 14.04 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_14.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_14.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Ubuntu 14.04 using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step. We choose the IPSEC/L2TP protocol stack because of recent vulnerabilities found in pptpd VPNs and because it is supported on all major operating systems by default. More than ever, your freedom and privacy when online is under threat. Governments and ISPs want to control what you can and can't see while keeping a record of everything you do, and even the shady-looking guy lurking around your coffee shop or the airport gate can grab your bank details easier than you may think. A self hosted VPN lets you surf the web the way it was intended: anonymously and without oversight.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 13.10 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.10.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.10.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Ubuntu 13.10 using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 12.10 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.10.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_12.10.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPSEC L2TP VPN on Ubuntu 13.04 with OpenSwan, xl2tpd and ppp</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/IPSEC_L2TP_vpn_with_Ubuntu_13.04.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on setting up an IPSEC/L2TP vpn server with Ubuntu 13.04 using Openswan as the IPsec server, xl2tpd as the l2tp provider and ppp or local users / PAM for authentication. It has a detailed explanation with every step.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Check and Fix SSL servers for SSLv3 connections or the Poodle CVE-2014-3566 bug</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Check_servers_for_the_Poodle_bug.html</guid>
                <description>The POODLE CVE-2014-3566 bug is a new bug discovered by Google in the SSLv3 protocol. The fix is easy, disable support for SSLv3. See https://cipherli.st for a good list of SSL ciphers. You can use this check from the shell to check your servers. This command can easily be automated with other shell scripts. It also allows you to check your services without exposing them to an external checking website.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Configserver Firewall and Security (CSF and LFD)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Configserver_Firewall_and_Security_CSF_LFD.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Configserver_Firewall_and_Security_CSF_LFD.html</guid>
                <description>his page covers my notes about csf and lfd. csf is an easy SPI iptables firewall suite. lfd is the login failure daemon, which scans log files for failed authentication and blocks the IP's doing that. This page covers installation, populair command line options and popular config file options.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Patch Shellshock)with Ansible</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Patch_CVE-2014-6271_Shellshock_with_Ansible.html</guid>
                <description>This is a simple ansible playbook to patch Debian, CentOS, Ubuntu and derivatives for the Shellshock vulnerability (CVE-2014-6271).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Statically (cross) compiled vim for x86, x86-64 and mipsel</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html</guid>
                <description>Sometimes I need to manage a few systems with either low resources or a very restricted set of packages. On those systems no compilers or development libraries are available, however it is allowed to bring binaries.A few of those systems are 32 bit x68 systems, some are MIPS systems, even worse. They serve a secure purpose, I cannot go in to much detail about them, except for they require a high level of security, they process certificates. I really like vim as my editor, the only editor available by default on those systems is ed. I have an ed cheatsheet for this purpose. The solution for this problem is to create a statically (cross) compiled version of vim. This article shows you how to create a statically compiled vim that runs everywhere.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Building HA Clusters with Ansible and Openstack</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Building_HA_Clusters_With_Ansible_and_Openstack.html</guid>
                <description>This is an extensive guide on building high available clusters with Ansible and Openstack. We'll build a Highly available cluster consisting out of two load balancers, two database servers and two application servers running a simple wordpress site. This is all done with Ansible, the cluster nodes are all on Openstack. Ansible is a super awesome orchestration tool and Openstack is a big buzzword filled software suite for datacenter virtualization.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Horizon installation with SSL on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Set-Up-Horizon-Dashboard-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the Openstack Horizon (icehouse) dashboard on Ubuntu 12.04 or 14.04, including SSL setup. It features nice screenshots and even an Ansible playbook to automate it all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Openstack Swift Objectstore Access via FTP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Openstack-Swift-Objectstore-FTP-Access.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on accessing the Openstack Swift Object Storage system using an FTP client. Openstack Swift has a beautiful API which you can program to. However, sometimes it is handy to quickly be able to access your Swift/Objectstore data without programming around it. We will use ftp-cloudfs to do this. There is also Softlayers swftp, but that does not support Keystone Authentication (2.0). ftp-cloudfs does support this. The OS X Cyberduck FTP client also has Openstack Swift support, however that is a native implementation, not using FTP. With ftp-cloudfs we can use any ftp client, from Filezilla to midnight commander.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Encrypted Duplicity Backups to Openstack Swift Objectstore</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Encrypted_Duplicity_Backups_to_Openstack_Swift_Objectstore.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on backing up your data to an Openstack Swift (Objectstore) instance using Duplicity. It provides encrypted backups using gpg so that you can safely use any public cloud storage to store them. This tutorial is for Ubuntu and CentOS and includes initial setup plus a script to automate it all. We will be using the Dutch provider CloudVPS, which is a non american company, so your data is more safe than it is with a provider that is vulnerable to the patriot act. Although your data is already encrypted with GPG, you can never be to sure. CloudVPS provides 10GB free ObjectStore, if you have VPS with them, the data is stored on at least 3 machines in 3 locations and they have a boatload of certifications.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>IPv6 at Home</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/IPv6_at_Home.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/IPv6_at_Home.html</guid>
                <description>One of my Raspberry Pi's was running a test setup of the Citadel groupware service. The test was sucessfull, so I set up a real world setup. The Raspberry Pi would serve another purpose, namely, a Linux Torrent seedbox. As in, to seed Linux torrents from linuxtracker.org. I choose Transmission for this, because it is simple, fast and stable. Transmission has a good webinterface, plus it allows access from remote clients with the transmission-remote gui packages. This article shows you how to set it up on a Raspberry Pi running Arch Linux.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Linux software raid, rebuilding broken raid 1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Linux_software_raid_rebuilding_broken_raid_1.html</guid>
                <description>Last week Nagios alerted me about a broken disk in one of my clients testing servers. There is a best effort SLA on the thing, and there were spare drives of the same type and size in the datacenter. Lucky me. This particular data center is on biking distance, so I enjoyed a sunny ride there. Simply put, I needed to replace the disk and rebuild the raid 1 array. This server is a simple Ubuntu 12.04 LTS server with two disks running in raid 1, no spare. Client has a tight budget, and with a best effort SLA not in production, fine with me. Consultant tip, make sure you have those things signed. </description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>KVM add disk image or swap image to virtual machine with virsh</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_add_disk_image_or_swap_image_to_virtual_machine_with_virsh.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_add_disk_image_or_swap_image_to_virtual_machine_with_virsh.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to create and add a disk image to a KVM vm using virsh. This is useful when you for example want to expand the disk space of your virtual machine when it is using LVM, or if you want to add a swap disk to a virtual machine.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>KVM convert qcow2 disk images to raw disk images for performance</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_convert_qcow2_disk_images_to_raw_disk_images_for_performance.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_convert_qcow2_disk_images_to_raw_disk_images_for_performance.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to convert KVM qcow2 disk images to raw disk images. The qcow2 disk format has some decent features like encryption, compression and copy to write support. However, the compression and the copy processes make it quite a bit slower than raw disk images. Sometimes you want to convert the disk images so that the VM will perform better. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>KVM host with bonding and VLAN tagged Virtual Machines setup on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_with_bonding_and_VLAN_tagging_setup_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_with_bonding_and_VLAN_tagging_setup_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to setup Ubuntu 12.04 as a KVM host with multiple virtual machines. The kvm host will have VM's in multiple VLAN's and will handle the VLAN tagging over a bonded interface. It also covers creation of an example virtual machine with the ubuntu vmbuilder tool and shows you how to add a serial console to an ubuntu 12.04 virtual machine for troubleshooting.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Bonding NIC Teaming on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NIC_Bonding_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/NIC_Bonding_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to setup NIC bonding / NIC teaming on Ubuntu 12.04. Bonding, also called port trunking or link aggregation means combining several network interfaces (NICs) to a single link, providing either high-availability, load-balancing, maximum throughput, or a combination of these.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Back Up Thunderbird Message Filters</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Thunderbird_Back_Up_Mail__Message_Filters.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Thunderbird_Back_Up_Mail__Message_Filters.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to backup and restore the message filters in Thunderbird on multiple platforms.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ntop-ng 1.1 installation on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ntop-ng-installation-on-Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ntop-ng-installation-on-Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This is a guide on installing the latest ntop-ng (1.1) on Ubuntu 12.04. ntopng is the next generation version of the original ntop, a network traffic probe that shows the network usage, similar to what the popular top Unix command does. ntop is based on libpcap and it has been written in a portable way in order to virtually run on every Unix platform, MacOSX and on Win32 as well. ntopng users can use a a web browser to navigate through ntop (that acts as a web server) traffic information and get a dump of the network status. In the latter case, ntop can be seen as a simple RMON-like agent with an embedded web interface. This tutorial will walk you through the compilation and installation of ntopng from source.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused Ubuntu kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_Ubuntu_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This one liner will help you remove unused Ubuntu kernels. Ubuntu does not remove kernels when they install a new one, however the default /boot partition is relatively small, about 100MB. So after 10 kernels, you can get No Space Left On Device errors with apt-get upgrading. Then you can eitehr remove them manually, or use this one liner to automatically remove them all.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install the latest ZNC from source on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_the_Lastest_ZNC_from_Source_in_Ubuntu.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Install_the_Lastest_ZNC_from_Source_in_Ubuntu.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install the latest (1.0) version of ZNC (an advanced IRC bouncer) on Ubuntu from source. Why from source? The package in the repositories is quite old and missing features like multiple IRC networks. It also includes an upstart script, and an example config for ZNC. ZNC is an advanced IRC bouncer that is left connected so an IRC client can disconnect/reconnect without losing the chat session.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My Todo.txt Workflow, including Unison, Todour and Android</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/My_Todo.txt_Workflow.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/My_Todo.txt_Workflow.html</guid>
                <description>Todo.txt is a way to manage your tasks/todo items in a plaintext format. It has a few simple rules, there are a lot of applications to work with it, but in its core it is a plaintext file, so a text editor is sufficient to use it. Recently I started using todo.txt, including syncing on all my devices via my own servers. This article shows you my workflow, and how to set up a similar environment, including ssh, unison, todour for OS X, DayTasks for Ubuntu and Simpletasks Cloudless for Android.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Samba Shares with Active Directory Login on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SAMBA_Share_with_Active_Directory_Login_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SAMBA_Share_with_Active_Directory_Login_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a SAMBA server which authenticates all users to an Active Directory, including group based permissions. It uses Samba, Winbind, Kerberos and nsswitch. This allows you to have a Linux machine serving files via SMB, where your authentication and autorization for the files and folders is done via Active Directory.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Screenfetch installation tutorial</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Screenfetch_installation_tutorial.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to install screenfetch, a bash information tool. It displays handy system information at login, including distro name, kernel, uptime, cpu, ram and nice distro-based artwork. The tutorial includes support for bash and zsh, for every supported linux OS (ubuntu, centos, arch, redhat, solusOS, linux mint and more.)</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Systemd rosetta / cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Systemd_Rosetta_Reference.html</guid>
                <description>A reference for systemd, for sysadmins who love plain old init.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Fix MySQL plugin on Ubuntu 12.04 and Debian 6</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-Fix-MySQL-Plugin-on-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>On Debian 6 and Ubuntu 12.04 the Munin MySQL plugin does not work by default because of a missing package. Here is a little trick on fixing it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin - Set up the NGINX status plugin on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Munin-NGINX-Status-Plugin-Ubuntu-12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This little tutorial will show you how to set up the Munin plugin to monitor NGINX (nginx_request and nginx_status) and graph it. You need to change some URLs in the config because by default this is wrong.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Munin optimization guide for Debian (rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice and nice)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Munin_optimalization_on_Debian.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to help you tune the performance of Munin using rrdcached, tmpfs, ionice, nice and a few other tricks.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ClamAV installation and daily scan + report on Ubuntu</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ClamAV.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/ClamAV.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ubuntu/Debian update mailer</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Ubuntu_update_mailer.html</guid>
                <description>This is a bash script for Ubuntu and Debian, to be run by cron on a set interval. It checks if there are apt-updates, and if so, mails an overview of the packages which can be updated, whith their local version, the version available and an URL to the Ubuntu package site where you can see the changelog. I wrote this as an addition for my Nagios monitoring, that only shows how many updates there are, this is a lot more verbose. It also runs on Debian since 1 Nov 2012. Only the links don't work then, because the packages are different.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Set up a local Ubuntu (apt) repository with apt-mirror</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_local_Ubuntu_debian_apt_mirror.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Set_up_a_local_Ubuntu_debian_apt_mirror.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to setup your own debian/ubuntu package repository with apt-mirror.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Stopping fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication error and other errors in fail2ban on ubuntu 9.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Stopping-fail2ban.server-ERROR-Unexpected-communication-error-and-other-errors-in-fail2ban-on-ubuntu-9.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how to stop fail2ban.server : ERROR Unexpected communication errors on Ubuntu 9.04.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Debian packages clean up commands</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Debian-apt-get-dpkg-packages-cleanup-commands.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Debian-apt-get-dpkg-packages-cleanup-commands.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    