<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag usb on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/usb.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag usb on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/usb.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Get webcam resolution and info on Ubuntu and fix HD</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Get_webcam_resolution_and_info_on_Ubuntu_and_fix_HD.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Get_webcam_resolution_and_info_on_Ubuntu_and_fix_HD.html</guid>
                <description>With all the video calling nowdays due to working from home I decided to get a webcam. Since I mostly work at a workstation, I have no microphone or camera built in. A friend gave me a spare webcam, a generic non-brand. It says 'HD Camera' on the box, but by default it records in 640x480. Using a few tools on Ubuntu you can figure out what resolutions are supported for your device. It turned out to be Cheese, the webcam capture program I used, not supporting the 'mjpeg' format, just the 'yuyv' RAW format. Using another webcam program named Webcamoid solved it, that program was able to use mjpeg.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Introducing the Yubikey Nano XL Rugged edition</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Introducing_the_Yubikey_Nano_XL_Rugged_Edition.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Introducing_the_Yubikey_Nano_XL_Rugged_Edition.html</guid>
                <description>Last month my Yubikey broke. I had a second one as a backup so there were no problems for me. This second yubikey is a Nano model, that means it is about 1 cm by 1 cm, the normal yubikey is 2 cm by 5. It fits inside the USB port and is meant to be inserted in the computer all the time. Extracting it from the port is hard as well, since it is so small. I use my yubikey on different machines and don't like the idea of it being in a computer when I'm not there, so I wanted to fix this. I did not fix it by buying a regular sized yubikey, but I found a clever workaround, which I name the Yubikey nano XL Rugged. You'll understand when you see the pictures.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Create a VMWare ESXi 5  5.1 5.5 USB install disk</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare-ESXi-5-USB-installer.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare-ESXi-5-USB-installer.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial will show you how you can convert a VMWare ESXi 5, 5.1 and 5.5 iso image to a USB install disk. You will learn how to create a USB drive from which you can install VMWare ESXi 5.1. This also works for the special HP version of ESXi with all the drivers.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    