<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag vim on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/vim.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag vim on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/vim.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Bare Metal Vi, boot into Vi without an OS!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Bare_Metal_Boot_to_Vi.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Bare_Metal_Boot_to_Vi.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to run Vi without an operating system, bare metal. This is a follow up on my article from 2014 where I made a custom linux distro that would [Boot to Vim, VIM as PID 1](https://raymii.org/s/blog/Vim_as_PID_1_Boot_to_Vim.html). This time we go further, we boot into Vi without an operating system. This is made possible by Cosmopolitan, a libc that outputs a POSIX-approved polyglot format that runs natively on Linux + Mac + Windows + FreeBSD + OpenBSD + NetBSD + BIOS with the best possible performance and the tiniest footprint imaginable.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Boot to Vim, Vim as Pid 1</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Vim_as_PID_1_Boot_to_Vim.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Vim_as_PID_1_Boot_to_Vim.html</guid>
                <description>This is a response on a great article from Pascal Bourguignon, namely how to run Emacs as PID 1. As we all know, nobody uses emacs. No, all joking aside, I found it to be a good article and wanted to see how I could do that with Vim. Not in User Mode Linux, but by creating an actual ISO. Boot to Vim, as you might want to call it. This is actually fairly simple. Compile vim statically, set it as init= at boot and you're done. We are going to use small 9MB distro named Tiny Core, Core edition and customize that to boot right into our static build of Vim.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Statically (cross) compiled vim for x86, x86-64 and mipsel</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Statically_cross_compiled_vim_for_x86_x86-64_and_mips.html</guid>
                <description>Sometimes I need to manage a few systems with either low resources or a very restricted set of packages. On those systems no compilers or development libraries are available, however it is allowed to bring binaries.A few of those systems are 32 bit x68 systems, some are MIPS systems, even worse. They serve a secure purpose, I cannot go in to much detail about them, except for they require a high level of security, they process certificates. I really like vim as my editor, the only editor available by default on those systems is ed. I have an ed cheatsheet for this purpose. The solution for this problem is to create a statically (cross) compiled version of vim. This article shows you how to create a statically compiled vim that runs everywhere.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>FreeBSD Ports: remove config options</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_Ports_remove_config_options.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/FreeBSD_Ports_remove_config_options.html</guid>
                <description>Today I wanted to upgrade a few packages on one of my FreeBSD servers. The vim port kept complaining: You must select one and only one option from the UI single. Read on to find out how I fixed this error.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Vim Cheatsheet</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Vim_Cheatsheet.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Vim_Cheatsheet.html</guid>
                <description>Not available.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    