<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag virtualization on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/virtualization.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag virtualization on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/virtualization.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - pre-backup all container dump script</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/OpenVZ_Proxmox_-_pre-backup_all_container_dump_script.html</guid>
                <description>This simple script creates a vzdump of all the OpenVZ containers on a machine. It can be used before an actual backup, in my case the actual backup excludes the container path /var/lib/vz/private. This because a dump is easier to backup because it has much less files in it.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ/Proxmox - Container to Template</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/OpenVZ_Proxmox_Container_to_Template.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to convert an OpenVZ (Proxmox) container to a template. You can then use this template on any other OpenVZ (or proxmox) host. This can be used either to migrate containers or to create a kind of master image to deploy new hosts from.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Proxmox VE - One Public IP</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Proxmox_VE_One_Public_IP.html</guid>
                <description>This guide will show you how to set up Proxmox with only one public IP. We will configure an extra interface bridge and make sure VM traffic is NATed. I have a few dedicated servers, some run Proxmox. Most of them however have only a few IP's. Therefore the VM's in proxmox cannot all have a public IP. For most of them that is not a problem. If needed I run a proxy or set up iptables to forward ports to the VM's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>KVM add disk image or swap image to virtual machine with virsh</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_add_disk_image_or_swap_image_to_virtual_machine_with_virsh.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_add_disk_image_or_swap_image_to_virtual_machine_with_virsh.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to create and add a disk image to a KVM vm using virsh. This is useful when you for example want to expand the disk space of your virtual machine when it is using LVM, or if you want to add a swap disk to a virtual machine.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>KVM convert qcow2 disk images to raw disk images for performance</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_convert_qcow2_disk_images_to_raw_disk_images_for_performance.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_convert_qcow2_disk_images_to_raw_disk_images_for_performance.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to convert KVM qcow2 disk images to raw disk images. The qcow2 disk format has some decent features like encryption, compression and copy to write support. However, the compression and the copy processes make it quite a bit slower than raw disk images. Sometimes you want to convert the disk images so that the VM will perform better. </description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>KVM host with bonding and VLAN tagged Virtual Machines setup on Ubuntu 12.04</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_with_bonding_and_VLAN_tagging_setup_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/KVM_with_bonding_and_VLAN_tagging_setup_on_Ubuntu_12.04.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to setup Ubuntu 12.04 as a KVM host with multiple virtual machines. The kvm host will have VM's in multiple VLAN's and will handle the VLAN tagging over a bonded interface. It also covers creation of an example virtual machine with the ubuntu vmbuilder tool and shows you how to add a serial console to an ubuntu 12.04 virtual machine for troubleshooting.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Install extra software in the VMWare vCenter Appliance (VCSA)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare_vCenter_Appliance_Install_Extra_Software.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/VMWare_vCenter_Appliance_Install_Extra_Software.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to install extra software in the VMWare vCenter appliance (VCSA). VMWare provides a vCenter appliance, which is a SUSE Linux Enterprise Server appliance with the VMWare vCenter server software installed. Because this is SUSE, we can add repositories and install software from there. By default it comes without repositories enabled. I needed to do this because I want to use NRPE on the vCenter appliance.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVZ dnsmasq set capabilities failed fix</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OpenVZ_dnsmasq_set_capabilities_failed_fix.html</guid>
                <description>When running dnsmasq under OpenVZ I sometimes get an error when restarting: set capabilities failed. This is because dnsmasq starts as root, then does privileged stuff and then drops to the configured run user. In OpenVZ these permissions are not passed to the VPS, sadly. These three commands fix the problem.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ProxBash - a bash script to manage Proxmox VE</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ProxBash.html</guid>
                <description>ProxMox VE is a very nice piece of software to setup a VM host very fast, which also is easy manageable via a webinterface. It supports both OpenVZ and KVM. I use it to manage a few VM's to test stuff on and it works really great. However, I'm a command line lover, and I thought it would be nice to be able to 'Manage' Proxmox VE from a bash shell. And I've written a script to do just that. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    