<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag virtualbox on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/virtualbox.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag virtualbox on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/virtualbox.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>After 47 years, OpenVMS gets a package manager (VSP)!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/After_47_years_OpenVMS_gets_a_package_manager_VSP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/After_47_years_OpenVMS_gets_a_package_manager_VSP.html</guid>
                <description>As of the 18th of February, OpenVMS, known for its stability and high-availability, 47 years old and ported to 4 different CPU architecture, has a package manager!
This article shows you how to use the package manager and talks about a few of its quirks. It's an early beta version, and you do notice that when using it.
A small list of things I noticed, coming from a Linux (apt/yum/dnf) background:
There seems to be no automatic dependency resolution and the dependencies it does list are incomplete. No update management yet, no removal of packages and no support for your own package repository, only the VSI official one. Service startup or login script changes are not done automatically. Packages with multiple installer files fail and require manual intervention.
It does correctly identify the architectures, has search support and makes it way easier to install software.
The time saved by downloading, manually copying and starting installation is huge, so even this early beta is a very welcome addition to OpenVMS.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:33:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Compiling TETRIS from 1992 on OpenVMS x86 in 2024!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Tetris_from_1992_on_OpenVMS_x86_in_2024.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Tetris_from_1992_on_OpenVMS_x86_in_2024.html</guid>
                <description>Since [DECWindows / CDE](/s/blog/OpenVMS_x86_E9.2-3_fixes_CDE_and_adds_Guest_Console.html) now works on OpenVMS x86 (from 9.2-3 onwards) there is much fun stuff to do. Back in 2021 I wrote an article on the [CDE desktop on Alpha / AXPbox](/s/blog/OpenVMS_CDE_Desktop_remote_x_axpbox.html) and also an article on how to run [CDE on modern linux, since it's still developed](/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html#toc_6). Both articles included a game, **GENERIC-TETRIS** from 1992, [written by Qiang Alex Zhao](https://web.archive.org/web/20240815073318/https://sites.cc.gatech.edu/gvu/people/qiang.a.zhao/Games.html).
After getting the (remote) desktop working I wanted to compile and run Tetris to continue this lineage, from VAX, to Alpha, to Linux/CDE, to x86 VMS. I haven't got an Itanium to run it on, but if anyone has one left willing to send this way, feel free to contact me. This article includes the precompiled tetris binary for OpenVMS x86 and instructions to compile the source. The code required some minor modifications which I'll also cover, but that's not surprising for code that hasn't changed much since 1992 to be compiled in 2024. This article also shows you how to install curl on OpenVMS.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 14:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 14:33:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS x86 E9.2-3 fixes CDE (DECWindows) and adds a Guest Console (no serial port required anymore)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_x86_E9.2-3_fixes_CDE_and_adds_Guest_Console.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_x86_E9.2-3_fixes_CDE_and_adds_Guest_Console.html</guid>
                <description>I'm a big fan of OpenVMS. You can [read all my OpenVMS articles here](/s/tags/openvms.html). Since the [licensing changes](https://web.archive.org/web/20240814192656/https://vmssoftware.com/about/news/2024-03-25-community-license-update/) to the Hobbyist Program, I applied and was included in to the Ambassador Program. A new update of the X86 field test is released and this includes to major changes for hobbyists. One is a new feature, the Guest Console, which makes installing easier by no longer requiring a serial port and fiddling with Putty or your telnet client and the second is a fix to the C/C++ compiler which, (probably by accident), fixes CDE and DECWindows. The [Common Desktop Environment (CDE)](/s/blog/The_Common_Desktop_Environment_CDE_is_still_developed_in_2021.html) is still under development and can be installed on Linux quite easily. This post shows the two new features, the Guest Console and CDE working.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 23:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 23:58:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Spinrite 6.0 on UEFI and an NVMe SSD drive</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Spinrite_6.0_on_UEFI_and_NVMe_ssd_drives.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Spinrite_6.0_on_UEFI_and_NVMe_ssd_drives.html</guid>
                <description>Spinrite is a hard drive recovery and maintenance utility written by Steve Gibson from GRC. It is marketed on the Security Now TWiT podcast which I often listen to. I have bought a copy of it and sometimes use it on solid state disks or SD cards. Spinrite 6.0 is written is assembly language and runs on top of MS-DOS or FreeDOS, using the BIOS. UEFI is not supported and neither are NVMe drives. This post will show you how to run Spinrite 6.0 on such a system anyway, using a modern linux live USB drive that can boot on UEFI only system and VirtualBox, exposing the NVMe disk as a SATA drive.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 21:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    