<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag vt220 on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/vt220.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag vt220 on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/vt220.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Split keyboards, a five year review including the ErgoDox EZ, Matias Ergo Pro and Kinesis Freestyle 2</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Split_keyboards_a_five_year_review_including_the_ErgoDox_EZ_Matias_Ergo_Pro_and_Kinesis_Freestyle_2.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Split_keyboards_a_five_year_review_including_the_ErgoDox_EZ_Matias_Ergo_Pro_and_Kinesis_Freestyle_2.html</guid>
                <description>A split keyboard is weird at first, but once you get used to it, you will never want anything else. The keyboard is made up from two halves allowing your arms and wrists to be in a natural (neutral, straight) position, instead of having an angle/twist in your wrist. I've been using split keyboards for about five years now. Over those years I've tried several different models from different manufacturers. In this article I'll talk about the three split keyboards I've used intensively and two I have only seen or tried shortly. We'll start with my current and favorite split keyboard, the ErgoDox EZ. The other two I've used are the Matias Ergo Pro and the Kinesis Freestyle 2. I discuss the UHK and Microsoft Natural Ergonomic Keyboard 4000 briefly.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Running WPS-8 (Word Processing System) on the DEC(mate) PDP-8i and SIMH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_WPS-8_(Word_Processing_System)_on_the_DEC(mate)_PDP-8i_and_SIMH.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_WPS-8_(Word_Processing_System)_on_the_DEC(mate)_PDP-8i_and_SIMH.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers running WPS-8 on a modern day emulator. WPS-8 is a word processor by DEC for the PDP-8. The PDP-8 was a very populair 12-bit minicomputer from 1965. WPS-8 was released around 1970, it came bundled with DEC's VT78 terminal. This terminal bundle was also known as the DECmate. This article covers the setup of the emulator, simh with the correct disk images and terminal settings. It covers basic usage and the features of WPS-8 and it has a section on key remapping. The early keyboards used with WPS-8 have small but incompatible differences with recent keyboards, but nothing that xterm remapping can't fix. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    