<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag w3c on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/w3c.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag w3c on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/w3c.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates, raymii.org now also available on Gopher</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_raymii.org_now_on_gopher.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_updates_raymii.org_now_on_gopher.html</guid>
                <description>I've made some new improvements to this website, you can now view raymii.org on Gopher! Building on the last site improvement, every article being available as plain text, it was easy to generate a gophermap file and bind it all together with pygopherd.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Site updates for accessibility, text only pages and skip to main content</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_Improvements_for_accessibility.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Site_Improvements_for_accessibility.html</guid>
                <description>I've made some new improvements to this website. Raymii.org is generated using my self-written static site generator named ingsoc, the new features are focussed on accessibility. If you are using a screen reader or command-line browser this will benefit you. Or if you like to archive stuff offline. The two main improvements are a text-only version of every content page (article/tutorial etc) and a 'Skip to main content' link.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Local W3C HTML5 Validator Server</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Local_W3C_HTML5_Validator_Server.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Local_W3C_HTML5_Validator_Server.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a local instance of the w3c html validator, including HTML5 validation support via a local instance of the Validator.nu HTML5 validator. The online w3 validator has strict limits and will ban you for some time if you validate to often. So if you for example have a local unit test to check a website you will get banned a lot. Which is understandable of course, it is a free service. They provide all source code plus it is in the debian repositories, it is dead simple to set up one yourself.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    