<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag windows-server on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/windows-server.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag windows-server on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/windows-server.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>SSH on Windows Server 2019 (including how to sudo)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH_on_Windows_Server_2019.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH_on_Windows_Server_2019.html</guid>
                <description>On hackernews I saw a Microsoft blog post stating that Windows Server 2019 now includes OpenSSH. In this post I'll try out both the client and server on a Windows 2019 server, including how to login as a Active Directory Domain user and how to generate and place and SSH keypair. The bonus this time is how to elevate permissions via SSH on Windows, sudo but way more complicated. This guide is also applicable on Windows 10, build 1809 and up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Active Directory and Exchange Command Line Powershell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Active_Directory_Exchange_Powershell_Snippets.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Active_Directory_Exchange_Powershell_Snippets.html</guid>
                <description>This is a collection of Powershell snippets to install Active Directory, create a new Active Directory Domain, join an existing Active Directory domain and to install Microsoft Exchange 2013. The snippets were tested on Windows Server 2012 R2.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Microsoft Exchange / Active Directory Powershell script to notify users of expiring Passwords</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Microsoft_Exchange_Powershell_Script_User_Password_Expiry.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Microsoft_Exchange_Powershell_Script_User_Password_Expiry.html</guid>
                <description>This is a small PowerShell script which emails your users that their password is going to expire in X days. This is needed when you have an Active Directory and Exchange Environment, but your users do not log in to a Windows machine bound to the Active Directory, but for example a Mac OS X or Linux machine with Full Disk Encryption enabled. Then they are not notified that their password is about to expire. This script can run as a scheduled task and scan and email your users that their password is about to expire.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ejabberd Active Directory LDAP Login</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_Active_Directory_LDAP_Login.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ejabberd_Active_Directory_LDAP_Login.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up ejabberd to authenticate to an Active Directory LDAP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Gitlab Active Directory LDAP Authentication</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Gitlab_and_Active_Directory_LDAP_Authentication.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Gitlab_and_Active_Directory_LDAP_Authentication.html</guid>
                <description>Gitlab is a self hosted git based source control application similar to Github, written in Ruby on Rails. It is used by many organisations and is a wonderfull piece of software. It supports LDAP Authentication (via the OmniAuth Gem), but it is tricky to set up with Active Directory and Windows Server 2003/2008/2012. This tutorials shows you how to set up Gitlab to authenticate against Active Directory LDAP.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    