<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag windows on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/windows.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag windows on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/windows.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing Virtual Machines with virt-install, plus copy pastable distro install one-liners</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</guid>
                <description>virt-install is a command line tool for creating new KVM , Xen or Linux container guests using the libvirt hypervisor management library. It allows you to create a VM and start an installation from the command line. This article has a few copy pastable getting started examples for different distro's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Back Up Thunderbird Message Filters</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Thunderbird_Back_Up_Mail__Message_Filters.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Thunderbird_Back_Up_Mail__Message_Filters.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to backup and restore the message filters in Thunderbird on multiple platforms.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2007 and 2010 Autodiscovery DNS SRV record for BIND</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</guid>
                <description>This is a BIND configuration example to set up Exchange Autodiscovery. Autodiscovery is the ability for Outlook to automatically configure itself to an Exchange 2007/2010 server. The main benefit is for remote users to use Outlook on the Internet as if it was connected on the LAN, this is called Outlook Anywhere or Outlook RPC over HTTP. This is very easily accomplished by having a specific DNS record available for the domain. However, the only examples Microsoft gives you are for their own software. This is the BIND version of the record.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Join Mac OS X to an Active Directory / OpenDLAP directory from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet joins an Mac OS X computer to a Windows Active Directory or OpenLDAP Directory domain from the Command Line or via Apple Remote Desktop.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2010 - OWA - Lock user after x amount of failed logins</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to set up automatic user lockout in Exchange 2010 - Outlook Web Acces (OWA). When a user does 5 wrong login attempts, he/she is locked out from the webinterface. After for example 5 minutes he or she is unlocked again automatically. This helps you mitigate brute force attacks, since an attacker can only try 1 password/minute, but the user will not be blocked for to long. Exchange 2010 has some special register settings to make IIS stop caching, otherwise it would not work. As a bonus you get an LDAP saved search query to view locked out users</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    