<?xml version="1.0" ?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag yubikey on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/yubikey.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag yubikey on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/yubikey.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Three new NitroKeys! Nitrokey Pro 2, Storage 2 and a FIDO-U2F Nitrokey</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Three_New_Nitrokeys_Pro_2_Storage_2_and_Fido_u2f.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Three_New_Nitrokeys_Pro_2_Storage_2_and_Fido_u2f.html</guid>
                <description>Last week I received several newsletters from Nitrokey. As you might know, I'm a fan of their (mostly open source) hardware security devices. Their newsletters introduced two new keys, the Nitrokey Pro 2 and the Nitrokey FIDO-U2F key. On their website I also saw the Nitrokey Storage Pro 2. This article is a summary of the newsletters and goes over the new features in the new hardware. It boils down to a new OpenPGP smartcard version (3.3, it was 2.1) in the Nitrokey Pro 2 and Storage 2. The FIDO-U2F device is an entirely new Nitrokey (with a button).</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Introducing the Yubikey Nano XL Rugged edition</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Introducing_the_Yubikey_Nano_XL_Rugged_Edition.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Introducing_the_Yubikey_Nano_XL_Rugged_Edition.html</guid>
                <description>Last month my Yubikey broke. I had a second one as a backup so there were no problems for me. This second yubikey is a Nano model, that means it is about 1 cm by 1 cm, the normal yubikey is 2 cm by 5. It fits inside the USB port and is meant to be inserted in the computer all the time. Extracting it from the port is hard as well, since it is so small. I use my yubikey on different machines and don't like the idea of it being in a computer when I'm not there, so I wanted to fix this. I did not fix it by buying a regular sized yubikey, but I found a clever workaround, which I name the Yubikey nano XL Rugged. You'll understand when you see the pictures.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>My Yubikey broke, but I had a backup. So should you with your 2FA</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_Yubikey_Broke_-_Important_tip_for_two_factor_BACKUP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/My_Yubikey_Broke_-_Important_tip_for_two_factor_BACKUP.html</guid>
                <description>Today my trusty old first generation Yubikey didn't light up when I plugged it in. No problem for me, I had a backup key. But most people don't, so here's an important tip when you use two factor authentication like a Yubikey, Nitrokey or Google Authenticator (HOTP). TL;DR: Have a second hardware token stored away safely and backup your QR codes (print/screenshot) somewhere secure. Swap the hardware tokens often to make sure they both work with all services. Just as with regular data, make backups and test restores.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    