<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag yum on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/yum.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag yum on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/yum.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>After 47 years, OpenVMS gets a package manager (VSP)!</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/After_47_years_OpenVMS_gets_a_package_manager_VSP.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/After_47_years_OpenVMS_gets_a_package_manager_VSP.html</guid>
                <description>As of the 18th of February, OpenVMS, known for its stability and high-availability, 47 years old and ported to 4 different CPU architecture, has a package manager!
This article shows you how to use the package manager and talks about a few of its quirks. It's an early beta version, and you do notice that when using it.
A small list of things I noticed, coming from a Linux (apt/yum/dnf) background:
There seems to be no automatic dependency resolution and the dependencies it does list are incomplete. No update management yet and no support for your own package repository, only the VSI official one. Service startup or login script changes are not done automatically. Packages with multiple installer files fail and require manual intervention.
It does correctly identify the architectures, has search support and makes it way easier to install software.
The time saved by downloading, manually copying and starting installation is huge, so even this early beta is a very welcome addition to OpenVMS.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:33:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do action if on specific distribution (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS or RHEL) or distribution version (ubuntu precise, ubuntu trusty)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only_if_on_specific_distribution_or_distribution_version.html</guid>
                <description>This ansible playbook example helps you execute actions only if you are on a certain distribution. You might have a mixed environment with CentOS and Debian, when using ansible to execute actions on different servers you don't need to run yum on debian, or apt on CentOS. Some package names are different and such, so this helps you with a when statement to select a specific distribution. As a bonus, you also get a when for specific distribution versions, like Ubuntu precise (12.04 LTS) or Ubuntu trusty (14.04 LTS).</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Only do something if another action changed</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Only-do-something-if-another-action-changed.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how execute actions only if another action has changed. For example, a playbook which downloads a remote key for package signing but only executes the apt-add command if the key has changed. Or a playbook which clones a git repository and only restarts a service if the git repository has changed.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Remove unused CentOS/Red Hat kernels</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/Remove_Old_CentOS_RHEL_Kernels.html</guid>
                <description>This small article will show you how to remove unused kernels in Red Hat or CentOS. This is sometimes necessary because the /boot partition can fill up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible - Sudo sometimes</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_-_Better_sudo_control.html</guid>
                <description>This Ansible tutorial shows you how run some actions via sudo and some not. It also shows you how to run an entire role via sudo or not.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Packages</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/Software_packages.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/Software_packages.html</guid>
                <description>Some software I encounter does not have a debian .deb package available. Via the ./configure, make, sudo checkinstall I compile them into a package and put it up here for download.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    