<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag haproxy on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/haproxy.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag haproxy on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/haproxy.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>OpenVMS 9.2 for x86, Installing HAProxy and troubleshooting UNIX file paths</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Installing_HAProxy.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Installing_HAProxy.html</guid>
                <description>This article shows you how to install HAProxy on OpenVMS 9.2 for x86. I've often used HAProxy in my career as a sysadmin and find it a very useful tool. HAProxy is an open source, fast, reliable load balancer for TCP and HTTP-based applications. This guide assumes you've set up your OpenVMS system via [my guide](https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started.html) and the [second part](https://raymii.org/s/blog/OpenVMS_9.2_for_x86_Getting_Started_part_2.html) of my guide, that will give you a fully licensed OpenVMS installation with networking and SSH access. Since I've used HAProxy so very often to set up high-available clusters and load balancers, I was surprised but happy to see it ported to OpenVMS. This guide shows the setup but also a few OpenVMS specific quirks, like file paths and troubleshooting error messages / logs.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 22:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: restrict specific URLs to specific IP addresses</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_restrict_specific_urls_to_specific_ip_addresses.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_restrict_specific_urls_to_specific_ip_addresses.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to use haproxy to restrict certain URLs to certain IP addresses. For example, to make sure your admin interface can only be accessed from your company IP address. It also includes an example to prompt for a password if the visitor is from a different network.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Ansible: access group vars for groups the current host is not a member of</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_access_other_groups_group_vars.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Ansible_access_other_groups_group_vars.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to access group variables for a group the current host is not a member of. In Ansible you can access other host variables using `hostvars['hostname']` but not group variables. The way described here is workable, but do I consider it a dirty hack. So why did I need this? I have a setup where ssl is offloaded by haproxy servers, but the virtual hosts and ssl configuration are defined in Apache servers. The loadbalancers and appservers are two different hostgroups, the ssl settings are in the appserver group_vars, which the hosts in the loadbalancer group need to access. The best way to do this is change the haproxy playbooks and configuration and define the certificates there, but in this specific case that wasn't a workable solution. Editing two yaml files (one for the appservers and one for the loadbalancers) was not an option in this situation.</description> 
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Nitrokey HSM/SmartCard-HSM and Raspberry Pi web cluster</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_HSM_web_cluster.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Nitrokey_HSM_web_cluster.html</guid>
                <description>This article sets up a Nitrokey HSM/SmartCard-HSM web cluster and has a lot of benchmarks. This specific HSM is not a fast HSM since it's very inexpensive and targeted at secure key storage, not performance. But, what if you do want more performance? Then you scale horizontally, just add some more HSM's and a loadbalancer in front. The cluster consists of Raspberry Pi's and Nitrokey HSM's and SmartCard-HSM's, softwarewise we use Apache, `mod_nss` and haproxy. We benchmark a small HTML file and a Wordpress site, with a regular 4096 bit RSA certificate without using the HSM's, a regular 2048 bit RSA certificate without using the HSM's, a 2048 bit RSA certificate in the HSM, a 1024 bit RSA certificate in the HSM and an EC prime256v1 key in the HSM. We do these benchmarks with the `OpenSC` module and with the `sc-hsm-embedded` module to see if that makes any difference.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: intercept all cookies and set secure attribute</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_intercept_all_cookies_and_set_secure_attribute.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_intercept_all_cookies_and_set_secure_attribute.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to use haproxy to set the secure attribute on cookies. You might have a backend application which is not able to set the secure attribute on cookies or for which haproxy does the ssl offloading. This simple frontend rspirep sets the secure attribute for all cookies.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: client side ssl certificates</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_client_side_ssl_certificates.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/haproxy_client_side_ssl_certificates.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to configure haproxy and client side ssl certificates. It features a few comprehensive examples.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: set specific ssl ciphers</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_set_specific_ssl_ciphers.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_set_specific_ssl_ciphers.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to set specific ciphers for haproxy when using an ssl frontend.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: add strict transport security or any other http header</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_add_strict_transport_security_or_any_other_http_header.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_add_strict_transport_security_or_any_other_http_header.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to add a header to a haproxy response, for example, the HSTS header (http strict transport security).</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: ssl backends</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_ssl_backends.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_ssl_backends.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to configure an ssl backend on haproxy 1.5 or higher.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>haproxy: redirect to ssl or other website</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_redirect_to_ssl_or_any_other_website.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/haproxy_redirect_to_ssl_or_any_other_website.html</guid>
                <description>This snippet shows you how to use haproxy to redirect http traffic to https or any other website</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    