<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag windows on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/windows.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag windows on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/windows.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Using IceWM and a Raspberry Pi as my main PC, sharing my theme, config and some tips and tricks.</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_IceWM_and_sharing_my_config_and_tips_tricks.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Using_IceWM_and_sharing_my_config_and_tips_tricks.html</guid>
                <description>KDE is my desktop environment of choice. KDE5 is rock-solid, configurable in any way possible and works great. It treats you like a responsible adult instead of a child like GNOME does these days, and after XFCE switched to GTK3, the RAM usage is on-par, more often than not a bare KDE install (Debian or Arch) uses around 300MB ram. This is with Baloo (search indexer) and Akonadi (PIM database backend) disabled. Great default behaviour, low resource usage and enourmous configurability, so why is this post then titled 'IceWM'? At home I'm using a small ARM device (Raspberry Pi 4 with an SSD) as my main computer, and there resources are limited. KDE runs fine, but you notice that it is a bit slower than on my work computer. IceWM on the other hand, uses less than 30 MB of RAM and even less CPU. The program that gives you a desktop background, icewmbg, uses double the RAM of IceWM itself! IceWM, next to Awesome, is one of my favorite window managers, very configurable and provides all I need. This PC doesn't have multiple screens, which would be a bit more of a hassle than with KDE. After switching, the machine feels a lot faster. It's the small details in which I notice it, like text input, a few seconds of lag here and there. This post shows my IceWM config including some options explained, my IceWM theme and a few tips and tricks to configure the rest of the desktop.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Execute a command and get both output and exit status in C++ (Windows &amp; Linux)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Execute_a_command_and_get_both_output_and_exit_code.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Execute_a_command_and_get_both_output_and_exit_code.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to parse some command line output inside a C++ program. Executing a command and getting just the exit status is easy using `std::system`, but  also getting output is a bit harder and OS specific. By using `popen`, a POSIX `C` function we can get both the exit status as well as the output of a given command. On Windows I'm using `_popen`, so the code should be cross platform, except for the exit status on Windows is alway 0, that concept does not exist there. This article starts off with a stack overflow example to  get just the output of a command and builds on that to a safer version (null-byte handling) that returns both the exit status as well as the command output. It also involves a lot of detail on `fread` vs `fgets` and how to handle binary data.</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Windows 10 updates with PowerShell</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Windows_10_Updates_with_PowerShell_PSWindowsUpdpate.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/blog/Windows_10_Updates_with_PowerShell_PSWindowsUpdpate.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had issues updating one of my machines that runs Windows 10. Turns out the firewall was to restrictive. However, the information provided by the update dialog was just, 'Oh, updating failed, maybe try again'. Nothing useful, so I tried to figure out if it's possible to use Powershell for updating. Since Windows 10 build 1709 Microsoft provides a built in module, but that is not that user friendly. In this article I'll talk about using PSWindowsUpdate and the built in Microsoft WindowsUpdateProvider to update a Windows 10 machine via the commandline</description> 
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>ScreensaverStopper, stop activating the screensaver by sending F24 often</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/software/ScreenSaverStopper.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/software/ScreenSaverStopper.html</guid>
                <description>ScreensaverStopper sends the F24 keystroke every 40 seconds. This way, Windows should not activate the screensaver. Useful if you do not have rights to disable the screensaver, but can run executables. Wwritten in C++, compiled with GCC 8.1 via MinGW/cMake. Filesize is around 14 KB, memory usage after a day of running around 600KB. License is GNU GPLv3.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>std::string to lowercase or uppercase in C++</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/std_string_to_lowercase_or_uppercase_in_cpp.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/std_string_to_lowercase_or_uppercase_in_cpp.html</guid>
                <description>I'm using codewars to practice my development skills. Today I learned a method to transform a std::string's casing, either to uppercase or lowercase. Researching it further, I also found out how to do unicode strings with boost. This article also includes a mini howto on installing Boost on Windows 10 via mingw for use with CLion.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>SSH on Windows Server 2019 (including how to sudo)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH_on_Windows_Server_2019.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/SSH_on_Windows_Server_2019.html</guid>
                <description>On hackernews I saw a Microsoft blog post stating that Windows Server 2019 now includes OpenSSH. In this post I'll try out both the client and server on a Windows 2019 server, including how to login as a Active Directory Domain user and how to generate and place and SSH keypair. The bonus this time is how to elevate permissions via SSH on Windows, sudo but way more complicated. This guide is also applicable on Windows 10, build 1809 and up.</description> 
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Use Ubuntu behind a Microsoft ForeFront TMG proxy with cntlm</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Use_Ubuntu_behind_a_Microsoft_ForeFront_TMG_proxy_with_cntlm.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Use_Ubuntu_behind_a_Microsoft_ForeFront_TMG_proxy_with_cntlm.html</guid>
                <description>Recently I had to deploy a few machines in a network where outgoing network access was forced through a Microsoft Forefront TMG proxy. For all the Windows clients this went automatically due to domain policies, for Linux this has to be set up manually. Defining the proxy in /etc/environment was not enough since NTML authentication is required, which is not supported by default. I found cntlm, a piece of software which acts as a local proxy, translating all requests to authenticated NTLM requests to your upstream proxy. This guide covers the (offline) installation, setup, getting the correct password hash and system-wide configuration. It should work on a desktop as well, but I did not test that.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Windows 7 installer on a KVM Linux VPS (Windows on Digital Ocean)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Windows_7_Installer_on_KVM_Linux_VPS_Digital_Ocean.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Windows_7_Installer_on_KVM_Linux_VPS_Digital_Ocean.html</guid>
                <description>For fun I wanted to install Windows 7 on a KVM Linux VPS (on [Digital Ocean) but it should work for any KVM or XEN-HVM VPS with console access). I was experimenting with Grub2 and ISO booting, since grub2 can natively boot a linux ISO. For Windows this is not possible, the installer needs to be extracted on a FAT32 partition from which you boot. On a normal system I would repartition the disk using a live CD, but on a VPS where an ISO cannot be booted this is troublesome. If I could boot from an ISO I would use that to install Windows, but where's the fun in that? I had to figure out how to shrink an EXT4 filesystem from a running Ubuntu VPS, which is possible, however very risky, with pivot_root. Next the partiton table can be converted to MBR, the partition can be resized, a FAT32 partiton and filesystem can be created, the Windows Installer files copied onto that, some Grub config and a reboot later, you're in the Windows 7 Installer.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Installing Virtual Machines with virt-install, plus copy pastable distro install one-liners</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/virt-install_introduction_and_copy_paste_distro_install_commands.html</guid>
                <description>virt-install is a command line tool for creating new KVM , Xen or Linux container guests using the libvirt hypervisor management library. It allows you to create a VM and start an installation from the command line. This article has a few copy pastable getting started examples for different distro's.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Back Up Thunderbird Message Filters</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Thunderbird_Back_Up_Mail__Message_Filters.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Thunderbird_Back_Up_Mail__Message_Filters.html</guid>
                <description>This tutorial shows you how to backup and restore the message filters in Thunderbird on multiple platforms.</description> 
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2007 and 2010 Autodiscovery DNS SRV record for BIND</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2007_2010_Autodiscovery_DNS_SRV_record_for_BIND.html</guid>
                <description>This is a BIND configuration example to set up Exchange Autodiscovery. Autodiscovery is the ability for Outlook to automatically configure itself to an Exchange 2007/2010 server. The main benefit is for remote users to use Outlook on the Internet as if it was connected on the LAN, this is called Outlook Anywhere or Outlook RPC over HTTP. This is very easily accomplished by having a specific DNS record available for the domain. However, the only examples Microsoft gives you are for their own software. This is the BIND version of the record.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Join Mac OS X to an Active Directory / OpenDLAP directory from the commandline</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/snippets/OS-X-Add-or_Remove_Mac_to_Active_Directory_or_OpenLDAP_Domain.html</guid>
                <description>This little snippet joins an Mac OS X computer to a Windows Active Directory or OpenLDAP Directory domain from the Command Line or via Apple Remote Desktop.</description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Exchange 2010 - OWA - Lock user after x amount of failed logins</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Exchange_2010_OWA_lock_users_after_x_amount_of_failed_logins.html</guid>
                <description>This is a tutorial to set up automatic user lockout in Exchange 2010 - Outlook Web Acces (OWA). When a user does 5 wrong login attempts, he/she is locked out from the webinterface. After for example 5 minutes he or she is unlocked again automatically. This helps you mitigate brute force attacks, since an attacker can only try 1 password/minute, but the user will not be blocked for to long. Exchange 2010 has some special register settings to make IIS stop caching, otherwise it would not work. As a bonus you get an LDAP saved search query to view locked out users</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    