<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
    <?xml-stylesheet href="/s/inc/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
    <rss version="2.0"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title>RSS feed for tag wps-8 on Raymii.org</title> 
            <link>https://raymii.org/s/tags/wps-8.xml</link> 
            <description>RSS feed for tag wps-8 on Raymii.org</description>
            <atom:link href="https://raymii.org/s/tags/wps-8.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
            <item>
                <title>Create a PDP-8 OS8 RK05 system disk from RX01 floppies with SIMH (and get text files in and out of the PDP-8)</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Creating_an_OS8_RK05_system_disk_from_RX01_floppies_for_the_PDP-8_with_SIMH.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Creating_an_OS8_RK05_system_disk_from_RX01_floppies_for_the_PDP-8_with_SIMH.html</guid>
                <description>This guide shows you how to build an RK05 bootable system disk with OS/8 on it for the PDP-8, in the SIMH emulator. We will use two RX01 floppies as the build source, copy over all the files and set up the LPT printer and the PTR/PIP paper tape punch/readers. As an added bonus the article also shows you how to get text files in and out of the PDP-8 sytem using the printer and papertape reader / puncher.</description> 
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
            <item>
                <title>Running WPS-8 (Word Processing System) on the DEC(mate) PDP-8i and SIMH</title> 
                <link>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_WPS-8_(Word_Processing_System)_on_the_DEC(mate)_PDP-8i_and_SIMH.html?utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=raymii&amp;utm_campaign=tagrss</link> 
                <guid>https://raymii.org/s/articles/Running_WPS-8_(Word_Processing_System)_on_the_DEC(mate)_PDP-8i_and_SIMH.html</guid>
                <description>This article covers running WPS-8 on a modern day emulator. WPS-8 is a word processor by DEC for the PDP-8. The PDP-8 was a very populair 12-bit minicomputer from 1965. WPS-8 was released around 1970, it came bundled with DEC's VT78 terminal. This terminal bundle was also known as the DECmate. This article covers the setup of the emulator, simh with the correct disk images and terminal settings. It covers basic usage and the features of WPS-8 and it has a section on key remapping. The early keyboards used with WPS-8 have small but incompatible differences with recent keyboards, but nothing that xterm remapping can't fix. </description> 
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
            </item>
    
        </channel>
    </rss>
    
    